真實故事改編
When you love someone you've gotta trust them.
當你愛一個人 你必須相信他
There's no other way.
別無它法
You've got to give them the key to everything that's yours.
你得將掌管生命中一切的那把鑰匙給他
Otherwise what's the point?
要不然有什麼意義?
And for a while I believed that's the kind of love I had.
一直以來 我深信我擁有的是這樣的愛
片名: 賭城風雲
Before I ever ran a casino or got blown up...
在我開賭場及被炸之前...
Ace Rothstein was a hell of a handicapper.
艾斯·羅斯坦 可是最屌的賽馬預測者
I can tell you that.
我告訴你
I was so good that whenever I bet I'd change the odds...
我旺到每次只要我下注 全國的賭盤賠率...
for every bookmaker in the country.
都會隨著改變
I'm serious I had it down so cold...
不蓋你 我對賽馬的研究精湛到...
that I was given paradise on Earth.
讓我晉陞人間天堂
I was given one of the biggest casinos in Las Vegas to run the Tangiers...
我被升為拉斯維加斯最大賭場之一《坦吉樂》的管理人...
by the only kind of guys that can actually get you that kind of money.
唯有聘請我的那幫人才能如此大手筆
$62,700,000.
六千兩百七十萬美元
I don't know all the details.
我不知道細節
In fact nobody knew all the details...
老實說 沒人知道細節...
but it should've been perfect.
原本應該很完美的
He had me Nicky Santoro his best friend watching his ass...
他有我這好友尼奇·山多羅挺他...
and he had Ginger the woman he loved on his arm.
他手中也攬著他愛的女人 金吉兒
But in the end we fucked it all up.
到頭來 我們全搞砸了
It should've been so sweet too.
原本應多完美
It turned out to be the last time that street guys like us...
結果 我們這樣的小混混...
were ever given anything that fucking valuable again.
在這次之後就再也無緣搞油水這麼豐富的大生意了
Vegas was a place where suckers...
那時的賭城 是蠢蛋們...
flew in every year on their own nickel...
一毛一毛存足了錢飛來...
and left behind about a billion dollars.
直到輸光了家當才走人的地方
But at night you couldn't see the desert that surrounds Las Vegas.
在夜晚 你看不到包圍拉斯維加斯的沙漠
But it's in the desert where lots of the town's problems are solved.
但城裏許多的問題卻都是在沙漠裏解決的
Got a lot of holes in the desert...
沙漠裏的坑洞可多著呢
and a lot of problems are buried in those holes.
裏面埋藏了很多問題
Except you gotta do it right.
只是程式要對
You gotta have the hole already dug...
你得先把洞挖好...
before you show up with a package in the trunk.
再將貨從汽車後車箱載來
Otherwise you're talking about 30 or 45 minutes of digging.
要不然你就得在沙漠挖上個30到45分鐘
Who knows who's gonna be coming along in that time?
誰又知道期間會有什麼人出現?
Before you know it you gotta dig a few more holes.
不知不覺中 你又得多挖好幾個洞
You could be there all fucking night.
搞不好一整晚都得耗在那兒
精華地段  拉斯維加斯  十年前
Who could resist?
誰抗拒的了?
Anywhere else I was a bookie a gambler...
在別處 我只是個登記賽馬的一個賭徒...
always looking over my shoulder hassled by cops day and night.
老是得小心翼翼 成天被條子們騷擾
But here I'm Mr. Rothstein.
但在這兒 我可是羅斯坦先生
I'm not only legitimate but running a casino.
不但不偷雞摸狗 還管間賭場
And that's like selling people dreams for cash.
那就像是將夢想換為現金
I hired an old casino pal Billy Sherbert as my manager and went to work.
我聘任了賭場的一個老朋友 比利·雪伯當經理 然後開始工作
And this is Ronnie who takes care of the card room.
這是負責牌室的羅尼
For guys like me Las Vegas washes away your sins.
像我們這種人 拉斯維加斯洗去了我們的罪孽
It's like a morality car wash.
像是道德洗車場一樣
It does for us what Lourdes does for humpbacks and cripples.
它對我們的效用就像法國露德 對駝背和殘障的人一樣
And along with making us legit...
不但讓我們重見天日...
comes cash tons of it.
還帶來了現金 數不盡的錢
What do you think we're doing here in the middle of the desert?
不然你以為我們沒事 跑到這沙漠中央幹嘛?
It's all this money.
就是為了這些錢
This is the end result of all the bright lights...
這是所有炫目的燈光...
and the comped trips of all the champagne...
所有的招待 香檳 免費住宿...
and free hotel suites and all the broads and all the booze.
女人與喝不完的酒 最終所造成的結果
It's all been arranged just for us to get your money.
全都是為了 讓我們弄走你的錢
That's the truth about Las Vegas.
這就是賭城的真面目
We're the only winners.
我們是唯一的贏家
The players don't stand a chance.
賭徒們一點機會都沒有
And their cash flows from the tables...
而他們的錢從賭桌上...
to our boxes through the cage...
流入我們的收銀櫃再進入保險籠...
and into the most sacred room in the casino.
最後流入全賭場最神聖的房間
The place where they add up all the money...
他們計算錢的地方...
the Holy of holies the count room.
萬物之首 計算室
注意 請勿進入
Now this place was off-limits.
這兒可不是閒雜人等可進出的
Even I couldn't get inside.
連我都進不去
But it was my job to keep it filled with cash. That's for sure.
當然 但我的工作是讓它保持 滿滿的狀態
They had so much money in there...
裏頭的錢多到...
you could build a house out of stacks of $100 bills.
可讓你用百元大鈔砌棟房子
And the best part was that upstairs...
最棒的是...
the Board of Directors didn't know what the fuck was going on.
上頭董事會什麼屁都不知道
To them everything looked on the up-and-up.
在他們看來一切都乾淨俐落 沒人動手腳
Right? Wrong.
不是嗎? 當然不
Verify $5000.
確認五千元
The guys in the counting room...
在計算室的那些人...
were all slipped in there to skim the joint dry.
都是被派進去將裏頭吸乾的
They'd do short counts they'd lose fill slips.
他們會少算錢 將計單弄掉
They'd even take cash right out of the drop-boxes.
甚至直接從箱裏拿走現款
And it was up to this guy right here...
全是靠這傢夥...
standing in front of $2 million...
站在兩百萬元前的這位...
to skim the cash off the top without anybody getting wise...
在被國稅局或任何人發現前...
the IRS or anybody.
把錢摸走
Notice how in the count room nobody ever seems to see anything.
在計算室裏 好像都沒人在看
Somehow somebody's always looking the other way.
不知怎的 大家都視若無睹
Look at these guys. They look busy right?
看看這些傢夥 他們看來真忙 不是嗎?
They're counting money. Who wants to bother them?
他們在算錢 誰會吵他們呢?
I mean God forbid they should make a mistake and forget to steal.
我的意思是 天曉得他們會不會犯了錯而忘記偷錢
Meanwhile you're in and you're out.
這期間 你可來去自如
Past the jag-off guard who gets an extra $100 a week...
走過那些鳥事不幹的警衛 每禮拜還多拿一百元...
just to watch the door.
只為了看門
It's routine. Business as usual...
一如往常一樣規律...
In, out, hello, goodbye.
走進 走出 你好 再見
That's all there is to it.
就這麼簡單
Just another fat fuck walking out of a casino with a suitcase.
就只是個拎著皮箱 走出賭場的肥豬
Now that suitcase was going straight to one place:
但那口箱子 會直接送往一個地方
right to Kansas City which was as close...
堪薩斯市 那裏是...
to Las Vegas as the Midwest bosses could go...
中部的老大能離拉斯維加斯 最近的地方...
without getting themselves arrested.
而不用怕被逮捕
That suitcase was all the bosses ever wanted.
老大們要的只是那口箱子
堪薩斯市
And they wanted it every month.
每個月都要
聖馬利諾義大利超市
Now this old Mormon fuck here...
這個摩門教的混蛋...
he had to fly in with suitcases once a month nice and easy.
他每個月都得拿著箱子飛來
- Something smells good.  - They made us something to eat.
- 什麼東西這麼香?  - 他們做了好料的
The bosses would come from all over:
老大們會從各地飛來...
Detroit, Cleveland, Milwaukee,
底特律 克裏夫蘭 密爾瓦基...
all over the Midwest...
整個中西部...
and they would meet in this produce market in Kansas City.
他們都會在這個位於 堪薩斯市的市場碰面
Nobody even knew it.
根本沒人會知道
One of the guys made his mother do the cooking.
有一個讓他媽做菜
Do you ever see that guy Jerry Steriano?
你有看到傑瑞·史塔瑞歐嗎?
These old greaseballs might not look it...
這些老頭們看來可能不怎麼樣
but believe me...
但相信我...
these are the guys who secretly controlled Las Vegas.
他們才是賭城的秘密操縱者
Mama that man's here again.
媽媽 那男人又來了
Because they controlled the Teamsters Union.
因為他們控制著 全美卡車司機工會
And that's where you had to go to borrow money to buy a casino.
而要開賭場非得到那兒去借錢
- Would you put in shrimp?  - I would.
- 你要放蝦嗎?  - 我會的
Nobody got a Teamsters' loan unless the guys in this room...
要是這些傢夥們每月拿不到這隻小箱子...
knew they were gonna get their little suitcases.
那誰就都別想貸到款
Guys like this antique over here out of Detroit.
像這從底特律來的老傢夥
Or especially guys like Remo Gaggi the outfit's top boss.
或尤其是像利蒙·蓋吉 這群人的首腦
You got a round figure on it?
有大概數字嗎?
Definitely the most important guy in this room.
絕對是這房裏最重要的人物
- About 20 pounds. Around $700,000.  - Good.
- 十公斤 那就差不多七十萬了  - 很好
It's a little early for Las Vegas...
雖說對拉斯維加斯還有點早...
but I want to welcome the ladies and gentlemen of the gaming industry....
但我想邀請賭博遊樂業界的先生與小姐們...
As far as the world was concerned...
就以世界所知...
Andy Stone head of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
安迪·史東卡車司機工會 退休基金會的負責人...
was a legitimate guy.
是個清白的人物
A powerful man.
有權力的人
He played golf with the President.
他與總統一同打高爾夫
On behalf of the Teamsters' Pension Fund...
代表卡車司機工會退休基金會...
- I'm glad to present...  - But he also took orders.
- 我很高興將這...  - 但安迪也聽命於人
When he was told to give a pension-fund loan to Philip Green...
當他被指示將基金貸款 貸給菲立浦·葛林...
this check for $62,700,000
六千兩百七十萬的支票...
for the new Tangiers.
給全新的坦吉樂
he did what he was told.
他就會乖乖聽話
Here was the perfect front man.
他可是最完美的傀儡
What the fuck else could he be? He didn't know too much.
他還能幹嘛呢? 他什麼都不知道
He didn't want to know too much...
也什麼都不想知道...
especially that the bosses made the Teamsters lend him money.
尤其是老大們讓工會借錢給他
He wanted to believe they gave him the money because he was smart.
他想相信他們是因為 他的才智貸款給他
I say that knowing just how much competition we have in this city.
我瞭解這城市的競爭性有多大 才會說出此話
And where they got Green from?
他們從哪兒找來葛林的?
Who the fuck knows?
誰知道啊?
All I know is that he was an Arizona real-estate hustler...
我只知道他在亞利桑那州 是個房地產經紀...
who barely had enough gas money to come and pick up his fucking check.
卻連開來拿支票的油錢 都差點付不出來
And it was the bosses' man...
是由老大的人...
美國中部 卡車司機工會退休基金
Andy Stone who gave all the orders.
安迪·史東下所有的命令
Not the Chairman of the Board Philip Green.
並不是由董事會主席 菲立浦·葛林
I understand.
我瞭解
Now all they needed was...
現在只缺...
someone they could trust to run the casino.
一個可信任的人來管理賭場
And who better than Ace? He was already in Vegas a couple years...
有誰比艾斯更適合? 他已經在賭城混了幾年...
and he had the fucking place clocked.
他對這兒瞭若指掌
But typical Ace, give him a shot at running a casino
艾斯的一貫作風 你給他個管理賭場的機會...
and he tries to talk you out of it.
他還推三阻四
I don't know if I could do this.
我不知道自己行不行
The Gaming Commission would never give me a license.
賭博遊樂委員會絕不會發執照給我的
I have at least 24 gambling and bookmaking pinches on me.
我最起碼有兩打以上 賭博與賽馬被逮的前科
You don't have to have a license to work in a casino.
在賭場工作不需要執照
All you gotta do is apply for one.
你只需要去申請
The State law says that you can work in a casino...
州法律允許你在申請期間...
while they process your application.
在賭場做事
They got a 10-year backlog.
他們文件進度現在落後十年
What happens when they do find out?
若他們發現了怎麼辦?
Why would they want to find out?
他們為什麼會想發現?
We're putting $100 million here. Why would they lock us out?
我們在這兒投資了一億 他們何必趕我們走?
They'll never find out. All you gotta do is keep changing your job title.
他們不會發現的 你只需要一直改變職位頭銜
Like from Casino Executive to Food and Beverage Chairman.
像從賭場執行長改到 餐飲主席
Then they put your application at the bottom of the pile.
然後他們又會將你的申請表 擺到最下麵去
I know guys who've worked there for 30 years don't have a license.
我有大把的員工已經工作三十年了還沒執照
It's a tough proposition Andy.
這不是容易的決定 安迪
If I did it I'd have to run it my way.
若我去做 得讓我用我的方式
You got it.
沒問題
I'm serious. No interference.
我說真的 不能有干涉
Nobody's gonna interfere with your running the casino.
沒有人會干涉你管理賭場
I guarantee it.
我保證
And that's how they got Ace to take over.
艾斯就是這樣接手的
They wanted him because Ace ate slept and breathed gambling.
要艾斯是因為 他不管是吃喝拉撒睡時都在賭
They worked out a real cute job title too...
他們還給了他個很可愛的頭銜...
Tangiers Public Relations Director.
坦吉樂公關理事
But the only thing he ever directed was the casino.
但他只管賭場
He made his first bet when he was 15 and he always made money.
他從十五歲時第一次下注就沒輸過
He didn't bet like you or me.
他不像你我那樣賭
Having some fun with it shit like that.
就為了他媽的好玩
Where did you learn how to deal?
你在哪兒學當莊家的?
He bet like a fucking brain surgeon.
他下注時就像是腦部外科醫生一樣
Place the checks properly.
籌碼得擺對
- That's the way you do it.  - Yes sir.
- 像這樣  - 是的
He had to know everything.
他得洞悉一切
He'd find out the inside stuff nobody else knew...
他知道沒人曉得的內幕...
and that's what he'd put his money on.
他會根據此下注
Even back home years ago...
就連在老家時
在老家時
when we first hung out he'd know if the quarterback was on coke...
當我們剛認識的時候... 他都知道四分衛有沒有吸可卡因
I'll take Columbia for $20,000.
我賭哥倫比亞兩萬
if his girlfriend was knocked up.
或他的女友是否懷孕
He'd get the wind velocity so he could judge the field goals.
他會去測風速 只為了預測射門得分
He even figured out the bounce you got off different kinds of wood...
他算出了籃球場上...
on college basketball courts.
不同木材質地板的彈性
He'd be working on this day and night.
他從早到晚都在做這些
He knew everything about a game he would bet on.
他對他要下注的賭局 瞭若指掌
Ace got down at $6,000. Get me down at $6,000.
艾斯下了六千 我也跟下六千
Season after season...
一季又一季...
the prick was the only guaranteed winner I ever knew.
那小子是我唯一認識的絕對贏家
But he was so serious about it all...
但他那麼認真下注...
that I don't think he ever enjoyed himself.
在我看來他從不放輕鬆享受享受
But that's just the way he was.
但那就是他
Back then the bosses didn't give a fuck whether he enjoyed himself or not.
當時 老大們也不會在乎他享不享受
To them he was a cash register.
對他們而言 他像是棵搖錢樹
All they had to do was ring the bell and take money.
他們只要搖一搖就可拿錢
Especially Remo...
尤其利蒙...
who was a fucking degenerate gambler who always lost.
他是個逢賭必輸的衰客
All those fucking sweeps.
靠 這麼多滿貫
- Unless Ace made his bets.  - Enough now!
- 除非艾斯下注  - 真是夠了
Ace made more money for them on a weekend...
艾斯一個週末為他們賺的錢...
than I could do heisting joints for a month.
比我搶劫一個月的還多
Whatever Ace picked up on the street he told Remo.
艾斯將他聽到的小道消息都告訴了利蒙
Fixed fights, doped horses,
內定的拳賽 下了藥的馬...
crooked fucking zebras, locked-in point spreads.
買通的裁判 預定的分數
He told fucking Remo everything.
他什麼屁都告訴了利蒙
And to tell you the truth I don't blame him.
說真的 我也不能怪他
Keeping Remo happy with money...
用錢財讓利蒙快樂...
was the greatest insurance policy in the world.
是世上最好的保險
Son of a bitch!
王八蛋
How did you get Oklahoma-Michigan?
你怎麼知道是 奧克拉荷馬或密西根
Nobody ever had Oklahoma.... How'd you do it?
根本沒人猜到奧克拉荷馬 你是怎麼辦到的?
That's why they paid so well.
所以他們才賠得高啊
You see? Never tells me nothing.
你看吧? 什麼都不跟我說
What do we got on for next week?
下禮拜的怎麼樣?
It's a little too early. I'll know by Thursday. Is that all right?
現在還太早了 我得要星期四才知道 可以嗎?
- You'll come by the house?  - I'll come by.
- 你會來家裏嗎?  - 我會繞過來的
At 7:00.
七點
Good job my boy. Keep it up.
做得好 小子 繼續啊
Hey Nick.
嘿 尼克
I'll be right out.
我馬上去
See that guy? Keep a good eye on him.
看到那傢夥了嗎? 好好看著他
He's making a lot of money for us.
他為我們賺了很多錢
And he'll continue making money for us so keep a good eye on him.
他會繼續為我們賺錢 所以你得好好看著他
Not like the fucking Feds out there without brains.
不像你外面那群沒腦的政府關員
- Okay?  - All right.
- 好嗎?  - 沒問題
Want me to take this?
要我帶走嗎?
Now on top of everything else...
所以這麼多事之外...
I gotta make sure nobody fucks with the Golden Jew.
我還得擔保 沒人會動我們的大紅人
Couple of shooters for the ladies.
幫小姐們倒幾杯酒
Yeah we made a great pair.
我們真是好搭擋
I made book and Nicky made sure we always collected.
我下注而尼奇負責收錢
The old men loved us and why not?
老頭子們愛死我們了
They all made money with us.
他們全靠我們賺錢
How did Nicky collect?
尼奇怎麼收錢?
Don't ask.
別問
Then where the fuck is the money? I don't see it.
錢他媽的在哪兒? 我沒見到
- Hi, Melissa, Heidi.  - Hi, Sam.
- 你們好 瑪莉莎 海蒂  - 你好 山姆
Who's this guy?
那是誰?
- Get the fuck out. I laid nine.  - It was eight.
- 去你的 我下九  - 是八
Ace tell him the line on the Bears game.
艾斯告訴他芝加哥小熊隊的注
- Eight.  - If he don't know nobody knows.
- 八  - 他要不知道 就沒人知道了
- It was eight.  - How come I laid nine?
- 是八  - 那我怎麼算成九?
'Cause you're a jag-off.
因為你是個蠢才
- Excuse me.  - What?
- 對不起?  - 什麼?
- Is this yours?  - Yeah, that's my pen. Why?
- 這是你的筆嗎?  - 是我的 怎樣?
It's nice. I didn't know whose it was.
很好看 我不知道是誰的
I didn't want it to get lost.
我不想它弄丟
Thank you. Why don't you take that fucking pen...
謝謝 你為什麼不拿那只筆...
and shove it up your ass, you fucking jag-off?
捅到你屁眼裏去 你這蠢才
- Well I was just offering  - Asshole.
- 我只是...  - 王八蛋
Look out Joe.
小心 喬
What's that? You hear a little girl?
那是什麼? 你有沒有聽到女孩哭?
Is that a little fucking girl?
是個小女孩嗎?
What happened to the tough guy...
剛叫我朋友捅什麼的...
who told my friend to stick it up his fucking ass?
那個硬漢呢?
Nicky, take it easy. Nicky.
尼奇 夠了
While I tried to figure out why the guy said what he said...
我還在想那人 為什麼這麼說時...
Nicky just hit him.
尼奇就動手了
No matter how big a guy might be Nicky would take him on.
不管一個人多大個子 尼奇都會跟他拚命
You beat Nicky with fists, he comes back with a bat.
你拿拳頭打他 他就會拿球棒回你
You beat him with a knife, he comes back with a gun.
你拿刀捅他 他就會用槍射你
And if you beat him with a gun, you better kill him,
你若拿槍射他 那你最好是殺了他...
because he'll keep coming back and back...
因為他會一直不停的回來...
until one of you is dead.
直到你掛了為止
With me protecting Ace...
由我保護艾斯...
he made a fortune for the bosses.
他為老大們狠狠賺了一票
That's what got him to Vegas.
這就是他來賭城的原因
He was a money machine.
他根本就是印鈔機
A tremendous earner for these guys.
為這些傢夥賺大錢
As soon as he took over he doubled the fucking drop.
他一來就把供金增加了一倍
With Ace the casino never saw so much money.
艾斯來後 賭場從就沒見過那麼多的錢
And the bosses they couldn't be happier.
老大們當然是笑不攏嘴
In Vegas, I had to keep a few juiced-in local cowboys working.
在賭城 我還得跟附近有關係的一些牛仔找事做
They were close to the good old boys.
他們與老傢夥們很熟
Without us these guys would still be shoveling mule shit.
要不是我們 那些傢夥現在都還在鏟驢糞
You've got to keep a cleaner station.
場子得保持乾淨
If you need Mr. Clean page him.
需要清潔工就呼叫他
Won't happen again Sam.
下次不會了 山姆
- Mr. Rothstein.  - It won't happen again Mr. Rothstein.
- 羅斯坦先生  - 下次不會了 羅斯坦先生
Is this guy just another dumb fucking white man or what?
這傢夥又是一個蠢白人嗎?
- You need this guy.  - Can't get rid of him?
- 你需要他  - 弄不走是嗎?
He's juiced in. He's the County Commissioner's cousin.
他有關係的 他是縣輔導的表兄弟
I wouldn't give the bum a mop job.
我連清潔工都不會給他做
I had no choice. I had to take care of them.
別無選擇 我必須照顧他們
These yokels ran the state.
這些鄉巴佬當權
Thanks, Senator.
多謝 議員
- They passed the laws, they owned the courts.  - I need a room.
- 他們立法 又掌管法院  - 我要開房間
I had dozens of politicians and officials in that place every week.
我每週都有十多個政客來訪
- Get him what he wants.  - Certainly.
- 他要什麼都給他  - 當然
Why not make them happy?
何不讓他們快樂?
For politicians like our State Senator up there...
對於政客 例如我們這位州議員...
everything was on the house.
一切都是免費的
These guys won their comped life when they got elected.
他們的招待生涯 在當選時就贏得了
Why not take advantage of it?
何不加以利用?
Still the politicians came cheap. We could handle them.
政客還是小事 我們解決的了
It's a whale like K.K. Ichikawa...
是像市川那種...
who plays $30,000 a hand in baccarat.
百家樂一把下三萬的豪賭客
That's the one you really gotta watch.
這種才該看緊
He plays fast and big. He has the cash and the credit...
他下注動作快 玩得大 他的資金雄厚...
to turn out your lights.
足可把你玩垮
A year ago he cleaned out a couple of casinos in the Cayman Islands.
一年前他讓開曼群島上 好幾家賭場洗底
Downstairs he takes us for $2 million...
他從賭場贏了我們兩百萬...
and upstairs he takes free soap shampoo and towels.
又從酒店套房拿了免費的肥皂 洗髮精與毛巾
Another billionaire cheapskate who loved his free rooms...
又是一個喜愛免費套房...
free private jets and $2 million of our money.
免費私人飛機又賺得我們兩百萬的億萬富翁小氣鬼
But we got him back.
我們也不好惹
I had our pilot tell him the plane was on the fritz.
我讓機師告訴他飛機故障
- What went wrong?  - I'm awfully sorry.
- 發生什麼事?  - 非常抱歉
These mechanical things happen.
是機械故障
Better here than up there.
在這兒總比在上面好
Then he missed the flights connecting with Japan.
然後他趕不上回日本的飛機
I can't believe there's no room.
竟然沒有空房
We got him back with a whole floor of rooms to himself.
我們給了他一整樓的房間
- Sorry you missed your plane.  - You'd like some of my money back.
- 真抱歉讓你趕不上飛機  - 你想要贏回我的錢啊
Oh no. No gambling.
不 不賭了
And once he was back he played small.
他回來後開始下小注
He bet $1,000 a hand instead of his usual $30,000 a hand.
一把只賭一千 而不是平常的三萬一把
But I knew the trick with whales like Ichikawa...
但我知道這些豪賭客的習性...
was that they can't bet small for long.
他們不可能一直下小注的
He didn't think of it as winning $10,000...
他不覺得是贏一萬...
he thought of it as losing $90,000.
他會想成是輸九萬...
So he upped his bets.
所以他開始加碼
Until he dropped his winnings back and gave up $1 million of his own cash.
直到他將贏得的輸光 再加上自己一百萬的現金
In a casino, the cardinal rule is to keep them playing...
在賭場裏 第一原則就是 讓他們一直賭...
and keep them coming back.
也讓他們一直回來
The longer they play the more they lose.
賭得越多就輸得越多
In the end we get it all.
最終錢就都是我們的
In Vegas everybody's gotta watch everybody else.
在賭城 每個人都得注意著別人
Since the players are looking to beat the casino...
玩家是來贏賭場錢的...
the dealers are watching the players...
莊家得看好玩家...
the boxmen are watching the dealers...
收付賭注得看好莊家...
the floormen are watching the boxmen...
管場的注意著收付賭注的人...
the pit bosses are watching the floormen...
賭區經理看著管場的...
the shift bosses are watching the pit bosses...
值班經理看著賭區經理...
the casino manager is watching the shift bosses...
賭場經理看著值班經理...
I'm watching the casino manager...
我則看著賭場經理...
and the eye in the sky is watching us all.
而監視照相機看著我們大家
Plus we had a dozen guys...
另外 還有十多個傢夥...
most of them ex-cheats who knew every trick in the house.
大多以前都是老千 他們知道所有的騙術
Yes!
好啊
- Very nice.  - I told you I was hot tonight.
- 非常好  - 我就跟你說我今天很旺
Looking good.
好樣的
Let's go. This is for Ginger.
來吧 為了金吉兒 快
Let me have $100 on your hard 10.
一百賭你沒老A
Thank you.
謝謝
Here we go now.
來吧
- Oh I'm sorry.  - The dice.
- 對不起  - 骰子
Thank you very much.
多謝
I appreciate that.
多謝你
Take care, Steve. Take chances, drive fast.
保重 史蒂夫 要冒險啊 開快車
This $100 is for you love. Thanks for your time.
這一百給你 甜心 多謝你賞光
- Come on.  - What's the matter?
- 快點  - 怎麼了?
I made a lot of money for you, I want my cut.
我幫你賺了不少 我要我的份
What money? I've seen you stealing.
什麼錢? 我看到你偷錢
"What money? " Look at the stack of chips.
"什麼錢?" 你看看這堆籌碼
- I want my half.  - I've watched you.
- 我要我的一半  - 我觀察你一夜了
- I want my money.  - Your bag is full of chips.
- 我要我的錢  - 你皮包裏全是熟籌碼
- I didn't steal anything from you.  - Get lost!
- 我才沒偷你的東西  - 滾吧
- Get lost?  - Yes!
- 滾吧?  - 沒錯
- Well how about that?  - Come on!
- 這怎麼樣呢?  - 別這樣
What a move. I fell in love right there.
真酷 讓我一見鍾情
But in Vegas, for a girl like Ginger, love costs money.
但在賭城 像金吉兒這樣的女孩 得花上大錢
I'm gonna go powder my nose.
我去補個妝
- Ginger's mission in life was money.  - I'll be right back.
- 金吉兒的人生目標是錢  - 馬上回來
- See you.  - Thanks for asking.
- 待會見  - 多謝你
She was a queen around the casino.
她在賭場可是皇后
She brought in high rollers and helped them spend a lot of money.
她召來大賭客 並也幫他們花大錢
- Hello.  - Hey Ginger. How you doing?
- 你好  - 嘿 金吉兒 你好嗎?
Great. You might have something for me. Got me covered?
好得很 一點小意思 你幫我搞定了嗎?
- Thank you.  - Take care of yourself.
- 非常感謝  - 自己保重喔
I got some lucky pills for you, Andy.
我有些幸運丸給你 安迪
Who didn't want her? She was one of the best known...
誰不想要金吉兒? 她是城裏名聲最響亮...
best liked and most respected hustlers in town.
也是道上最受歡迎的江湖人物
Smart hustlers like her could keep a guy awake...
像她這麼聰明的玩家 可以讓男人...
for two or three days before sending him home broke...
兩三天不睡 然後再讓他一文不名的...
to the little woman and his bank examiners.
回到老婆與銀行審查主任身邊
Any change?
有找錢嗎?
Oh I hit a few games on the way back.
我回來時小賭了幾把
But that was all bullshit. She just pocketed the cash.
那根本是胡扯 她把錢收起來了
- How you doing tonight?  - Good.
- 你今天好嗎?  - 不錯啊
- How are you?  - Beat.
- 你呢?  - 衰死了
- Ginger had the hustlers' code.  - Take one for you.
- 金吉兒洞悉玩家們的習性  - 給你一百
- Thank you.  - She knew how to take care of people.
- 多謝  - 她懂得如何買通他人
That's what Vegas is all about.
這就是賭城的座右銘
- $6,800.  - Thanks.
- 六千八百元  - 謝啦
- It's kickback city.  - Have a good night.
- 這裏是講究回扣的城市  - 晚安
She took care of the dealers...
她罩莊家...
pit bosses floor managers...
賭區經理 管場經理...
but mostly the valet parkers...
但尤其關照停車小弟...
the guys who could get you anything and take care of anything.
他們能幫你找到任何東西 也能幫你解決任何事
Ginger took care of the parkers...
金吉兒搞定了停車的...
who took care of the security guards who took care of the cops...
他們搞定警衛 而警衛會擺平員警...
- who let her operate.  - I need that stuff tonight.
- 讓她可繼續開工  - 我今晚需要那東西
- No problem.  - You are a doll.
- 沒問題  - 你真好
The valet parking job was such a money-maker...
停車賺的錢多到...
they had to pay off the hotel manager just to get the concession.
得買通酒店經理才能排上空缺
But one thing I didn't understand...
不過有一點我不懂...
was that she had everything under control...
她將一切都控制的好好的...
except for her old pimp boyfriend Lester Diamond.
卻被她那拉皮條的男友 萊絲特·戴蒙德吃得死死的
I got other people in this. I got partners.
我得顧到其他人 我的搭擋們
I'm looking out for you in this thing okay?
在這事上有我罩你 知道嗎?
You'll get yours back and you'll get it back first. Okay?
你將獲你應得的 而且第一個拿到 好嗎?
- All right.  - Where you going?
- 好的  - 你去哪兒了?
Where are you? You're in that place.
你在哪兒? 你又飄走了
- I'm here.  - No you're not.
- 我在這兒  - 不 你不在
Where are you?
你在哪?
I'm always here for you.
我永遠在你身邊
- You are.  - I am.
- 真的  - 是啊
The Ginger I knew wouldn't even look at this creep.
我所認識的金吉兒 根本不會多看這怪胎一眼
- Good luck.  - Yeah.
- 祝你好運  - 是啊
He was a moocher a card cheat...
他是個老千 專作假牌...
a country club golf hustler, a scumbag,..
老在高爾夫俱樂部招搖撞騙 一個癟三...
- chasing dentists for a few bucks.  - Careful.
- 為了幾塊錢追著牙醫屁股跑  - 小心點
He was always broke. He always had a story.
他永遠都沒錢 永遠都有藉口
Somehow she could never turn him down.
不知為何 她卻拒絕不了他
The way Ginger saw it was that he was just an unlucky guy.
在金吉兒眼裏 他只是運氣不好
Somebody had to take care of him.
總得有人照顧他
在老家
But nobody had to take care of Nicky.
但尼奇可不需要人照顧
You find any cash in there we'll whack it up with you.
你找到現金的話 我們就跟你平分
He took care of himself only too well.
他把自己照顧得太好了
That's why every badge back home wanted to nail him.
這也是為什麼老家的條子 都想抓他到案
I folded these things beautifully. I would appreciate a little respect.
我將這些都折得好好的 能不能放尊重點
Don't look at me, pal, I gotta live with her.
別看我 兄弟 我還得跟她同床共枕
Even after a vacation, they hassled him at the airport.
就連去渡個假 他們在機場時都不放過他
Frank Marino was there to meet him. So were the cops.
法蘭克·瑪雷諾在那兒等他 條子們也在
They wanted to pinch him...
他們想逮他...
- for a diamond burglary in Antwerp.  - Help me fold these.
- 因為一宗在安特衛普的鑽石竊案  - 幫忙折吧
They were ready to blame him for anything no matter where.
他們隨時願意嫁禍於他 不管是在哪兒發生什麼事
They were usually right.
他們通常是對的
Because Nicky enjoyed being a gangster.
因為尼奇很喜歡混幫派
And he didn't give a damn who knew it.
他也不在乎有誰知道
There we go. Look at that. Beautiful!
看看 美極了
I mean that's what worried me...
讓我擔心的是...
'cause it turns out Nicky was about to be sent to Vegas.
尼奇似乎要被派來拉斯維加斯
- All right we're clear.  - There's more.
- 好了 就這樣  - 還有
There's a couple stuck in there.
一定還有些卡在裏面
- I'm telling you they're out!  - Come on.
- 我告訴你都拿出來了  - 快
Don't get so defensive it could be stuck in your hair.
別急於辯護 可能還有些卡在你頭髮裡
What's that?
那是什麼?
There's no more. Thanks.
沒有了 謝謝
I couldn't wait to get my hands on Vegas.
我迫不及待想去拉斯維加斯
But the bosses didn't send me out to have a good time.
但老大可不是送我去玩的
They sent me out to make sure that nobody fucked with Ace.
他們要我去確保 沒人找艾斯的麻煩
And nobody interfered with the fucking skim.
也確保沒人幹擾每月的抽頭
- Hey.  - Hey how you doing?
- 嘿  - 你好嗎?
Hey Sammy.
嘿 山姆
- Boy look at this place.  - Incredible.
- 天呀 瞧瞧這地方  - 不可思議
Welcome to Vegas.
歡迎來賭城
- Okay Sammy.  - Something huh?
- 好樣的 山姆  - 不錯吧
Ginger.
金吉兒
Holy shit. What've you been doing out here?
靠 你都在這兒幹嘛?
Honey come here.
甜心 過來
This is Jennifer and Nick. They're dear friends of mine.
這是珍妮佛與尼克 我的好朋友們
- Hi Jennifer.  - A pleasure.
- 你好 珍妮佛  - 幸會
Okay Sammy.
好樣的 山姆
After, we ate we left Jennifer and Ginger...
晚餐後 我們讓珍妮佛與金吉兒一塊兒...
and we took a ride to talk.
我們倆則出去談話
And then he hit me with it.
然後他對我丟了顆炸彈
What do you think about me moving out here?
你覺得我也搬來如何?
You got a problem with that?
有問題嗎?
No of course not.
當然沒有
You mean I have your permission?
你是說你允許囉?
Sure you do. But I just gotta tell you...
當然囉 但我得告訴你...
it's no joke out here.
在這兒可不能開玩笑
You gotta keep a low profile.
你得保持低調
It's not like back home. They don't like guys like us.
不像是在老家 這兒他們不喜歡我們
This sheriff's a real cowboy.
警長是個不折不扣的牛仔
Even coppers aren't afraid to bury people in the desert.
連巡警都不怕在沙漠裏埋人
I don't care. I want to get away from back home for a while.
我不在乎 我只想離開老家一陣子
I'm tired of that shit back there.
我厭倦了那裏
Look at this place. It's made of money.
看看這地方 簡直是錢砌的
You know what the best part is?
知道最屌的是什麼?
Nobody's gonna know what we're doing.
沒人知道我們在幹嘛
There's nobody here to see us. Everybody's back home.
沒人看著我們 大家都在老家
I got pinched twice for no reason.
我無緣故被逮了兩次
I really gotta be careful.
我真得小心了
I'm running a licensed place. Everything's legit.
我管理的地方是有執照的 全是合法的
Don't worry about it. I'm not gonna do anything.
別擔心 我什麼都不會做的
I'm especially not gonna involve you in anything.
我尤其不會拖你下水
Ace saw Vegas one way...
艾斯看賭城的觀點...
- Call and tell him I'm coming?  - Of course.
- 你跟他說過我要來嗎?  - 當然
but I saw it another.
我的看法不同
I saw it as untouched.
我視它為未開發的
They had bookies pimps and drug dealers I could shake down.
多的是可勒索的賭馬組頭 皮條客與毒販...
Who the fuck were they gonna run to?
他們能找誰靠?
So I started getting everybody in line.
我開始一個一個下手
Best of all for the first time in my life...
最屌的是 我這輩子第一次...
I figured out a way not to lose.
發覺了穩贏的方法
He had a foolproof scheme.
他是有個穩贏之計
It wasn't very scientific but it worked.
雖然不高明 但起碼行得通
When he won he collected.
他贏時就收錢
When he lost he told the bookies to fuck off.
輸時就叫賭馬組頭去死
What were they gonna do? Muscle Nicky? Nicky was the muscle.
他們能怎樣? 逼迫尼奇? 尼奇就是逼迫者
- Hey how you doing?  - How you doing?
- 你好嗎?  - 你好嗎?
- You got that thing for me?  - What thing?
- 你有東西給我嗎?  - 什麼東西?
Nicky I thought you was laying.
尼奇 我以為你是來下注的
I was laying? No I'm taking it.
下注? 不 我來收錢
- You sure?  - I'm positive.
- 你確定?  - 非常
- I'm a little confused.  - You're a little confused?
- 我搞混了  - 你搞混了?
Maybe if I stick your fucking face through this window...
或許在我把你的臉砸過這窗戶後...
you'll get unconfused.
你就會清楚點
- Give me the fucking money.  - I'm sorry.
- 把錢他媽的給我  - 對不起
I didn't mean anything by it.
我不是故意的
That's why you had it ready. You thought I was laying it.
所以你連錢都準備好了 你他媽的以為我要下注
- My fucking head.  - Smarten up.
- 我的頭  - 放聰明點
And now Nicholas Santoro will come up and tell us about our first President.
而現在尼可拉斯·山多羅要來跟我們說第一總統的故事了
George Washington was born
喬治·華盛頓出生在...
But still it was nice and quiet for a while.
但最起碼還風平浪靜了一陣子
We presented Nicky and Jennifer all over town...
我們帶著尼奇與珍妮佛滿街亮相...
like regular Ozzie and Harriets.
像是明星似的
You got a beautiful swing.
你棒揮得很好
Ace got Little Nicky involved with Little League. It was great.
艾斯讓我兒子 小尼奇 參加市區青少棒 真的很好
Turned out that one of the other coaches was a metro intelligence cop.
結果其中的一位教練 是市立警察局情報單位的
But it didn't matter. It was all about the kids.
不過無所謂 這純粹是孩子的事
He's gotta realize everything can't be a home run.
他得明白不是每棒都能揮出全壘打
That's exactly what I tell him but that's the kind of kid he is.
我也是這樣告訴他 不過那小子就是這樣
And Nicky being Nicky he made his presence known.
尼奇就是尼奇 他總是引人注目
Especially at the casino where he definitely did not work...
尤其是在他不工作的賭場
people got the message.
大家都明白
Me that's why the bosses sent me out here.
就是我 這也是老大為何派我來
I was to make sure no other crews robbed the joint.
我是來確定 沒有其他人在拿這兒的錢
Like these two fucking balloon heads over here.
像在那邊的那兩個蠢才
They were gonna try to bang us out of $200,000.
想從我們這兒騙走二十萬
Yeah right I'm sure.
走著瞧
How are you? What are you doing here?
你好嗎? 你怎麼會在這兒?
I'm over here now.
我到這兒來了
- You're over here?  - Yeah I'm over here with them.
- 到這兒來?  - 是啊 跟他們一起
We're waiting on Carmine.
我們在等卡爾曼
Yeah we're looking for Carmine.
是啊 在等卡爾曼
He was here before. He had a suitcase and then he left.
他本來在這兒 拿了口箱子後來就走了
Carmine left?
卡爾曼走了?
He's gone?
他走了嗎?
He's not here?
他不在這兒?
Carmine's out?
他出去了?
I think he went across the street or somewhere else or something.
他好像過了馬路還是什麼的
Well listen good luck with the joint.
是喔 聽著 祝你在這兒好運
- Thanks Eddy.  - Lots of luck.
- 謝啦 艾迪  - 非常好運
Good luck to you too.
也祝你好運
They forgot to sign their papers.
他們忘了簽名
They don't need those anymore.
他們不需要這個了
Out of respect guys from other crews got away with a warning.
因為基本尊重 我只給別幫傢夥一點警告
Everybody else watch out.
其他的人可得小心了
Like these yokels here...
像這群鄉巴佬...
who never heard of Nicky or the bosses back home.
從沒聽過尼奇或他老家的老大們
They're the morons who give you the most trouble.
這種王八蛋最麻煩了
We'd catch them and they'd try to sneak back...
被我們抓到後又會溜回來...
with beards and wigs and fake noses.
戴著假鬍子 假髮 假鼻子
You can spot these assholes by watching the way they bet.
只要看這些王八蛋下注的方式 你就可辨認他們
Like this guy. He's betting lavender chips...
像這傢夥 以紫籌碼下注...
at $500 each with only one little problem.
每次下五百 不過只有個小問題
He's always guessed right.
他每次都猜對
If he wasn't so fucking greedy he'd have been tougher to spot.
要不是他這麼貪心 可能還不會這麼明顯
But in the end they're all greedy.
不過到頭來 他們每個都貪
I saw that the dealer was weak but he wasn't in on it.
我看到莊家很弱 但他們並不是一夥的
He just wasn't protecting his hand.
他只是沒保護好自己的牌
He was lifting his hole card way too high.
他把底牌掀得太高了
Here's this guy reading the dealer's hole card...
有個傢夥在看莊家的底牌...
and signaling his buddy at this table.
再對他坐在桌上的兄弟打手勢
And that's just what these hustlers look for.
這些在外混的就是這樣
They cruise from casino to casino looking for weak dealers...
他們從一家賭場到另一家 找尋著弱莊家...
the way lions look for weak antelope.
像是獅子們找著弱小的羚羊
Operator this is Mr. R.
接線生 這是羅先生
Get me Armstrong and Friday over to Pit 2 right away.
立刻叫阿姆斯壯 與佛萊迪來二號賭台區
BJ 19 second base the beard.
二十一點第十九桌 第二個位子的那個大鬍子
Operator I need Mr. Happy. Loud.
接線生 來段生日快樂曲 要大聲點
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday dear Jeff
親愛的傑夫 祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂
Man down!
有人倒下
Go get medical. We got a cardiac arrest here.
叫救護車 有人心臟病發
He's fine folks. Just give us some room please.
他沒事了 大家 麻煩給我們一點空間
They never know what hit them.
他們根本搞不清狀況
If and when they do find out they got zapped by a cattle prod...
若他們真的發現是被電擊棒電到...
they wish they really did have a heart attack.
他們會希望自己其實是心臟病發
Turns out this guy and his fucking pals were knocking this place dead for years.
結果發現這兩個傢夥已在這兒 招搖撞騙好多年了
- He's wired.  - What are you doing?
- 他身上有竊聽器  - 你在幹嘛?
There it is. That's it.
在那兒 就是它了
- Cheater's justice.  - Oh God!
- 老千的正法  - 我的天
No!
不
I wanted everybody to know that things were changed around here.
我要所有人知道這兒跟以往不同了
We had to make an example of these pricks that the party was over.
我們得用這些傢夥來讓大家知道 他們的好日子不長了
I'm just curious.
我很好奇
I saw you shuffling your checks with your right hand.
我看到你用右手玩籌碼
- Can you do that with both hands?  - No.
- 你兩隻手都可以這樣嗎?  - 不
- You can't do it with both hands?  - No sir.
- 不能用兩隻手嗎?  - 不能
- Can you do it with your left hand?  - I never tried.
- 左手可以嗎?  - 我從沒試過
- So you're a righty.  - Yeah.
- 所以你是右撇子  - 是
Now you're gonna have to learn with your left hand.
那你現在得學習用左手咯
- It's $100,000 $110,000 I think.  - Yes it is.
- 十萬 不 十一萬吧  - 是啊
Okay.
好的
Hi.
嗨
That's a lot of money to be counting out in public.
在大庭廣眾數這麼多錢
Why don't I take him over to the office and verify it?
為何不讓我拿到辦公室確認?
A little privacy.
多一點隱私
By the way send over a nice bottle of champagne on ice.
順便叫一瓶好香檳來
- Sure will.  - Real special.
- 沒問題  - 要很特別的
By the way I'm Billy Sherbert casino manager.
對了 我是賭場經理 比利·雪伯堤
- Having a good time?  - Yes.
- 還玩得愉快嗎?  - 是的
You want to count the money in privacy.
你在較有隱私的地方算比較好
I have a plane to catch. Can I get my winnings?
我得趕飛機去克裏夫蘭 我可以領取我贏得的錢嗎?
Look what they did to my hand man.
看他們對我的手做了什麼
I'm gonna give you a choice:
我給你一個選擇
You can have the money and the hammer or you can walk out of here.
你可以拿錢然後被錘頭砸 或者是從這兒走出去
- What do you want?  - I wanna get out of here.
- 你要哪個?  - 我要走
Tell your friends what happens if they fuck around here.
告訴你那群朋友 他們若來亂搞 會發生什麼事
- I'm sorry I made a bad mistake.  - You're fucking right.
- 對不起 我犯了大錯  - 你真他媽的說對了
If you come back either one of you we'll break your fucking heads.
你們要是再敢回來 我會敲爛你們的頭
You see that fucking saw? We're gonna use it. We don't fuck around here.
你看到那鋸子沒? 不是放著好看的 我們不是在開玩笑
- Got it?  - Yes.
- 懂嗎?  - 是
- Get out of here.  - Thank you.
- 給我滾  - 謝謝你
Throw him out in the alley. Tell the cops he got hit by a car.
把他丟到後街去 跟條子說他被車撞到了
Within no time everything was set in place.
不到一會兒 一切就都搞定了
We got rid of the freelance scamsters the pro was way up...
我們弄走了那些老千 盈利上揚好多...
the gods were happy or as happy as the gods can ever be.
上頭老大高興極了
And I decided to complicate my life.
然後我決定將生活複雜化
For a guy who likes sure things...
對不愛冒險的我來說...
I was about to bet the rest of my life on a real long shot.
我用我的下半輩子 下了筆勝算不大的賭注
We're not getting any younger.
我們也不年輕了
Don't you think it's time?
你不覺得是時候了?
Aren't you getting tired of all this shit? Banging around hustling around?
你對這些不厭煩嗎? 這邊睡 那邊混?
- Are you trying to handicap me?  - I'm gonna do you one better.
- 你想要妨礙我嗎?  - 我想給你更好的
I'm trying to marry you.
我想娶你進門
You wanna marry me?
你想嫁我嗎?
I'm serious.
我說真的
I wanna settle down. I want a family.
我想定下來 想有個家
You got the wrong girl Sam.
你找錯人了 山姆
I'd be a good father you'd be a good mother.
我會是個好爸爸 你也將是個好媽媽
You don't know me.
你不知道我
You've known me two three months. What do you know?
你才認識我兩三個月 你瞭解什麼?
I'm 43 years old. I don't want to wait.
我已經43歲了 我不想再等了
I know you well enough to know that I really love you very much.
我對你的瞭解深到 令我自己知道我非常愛你
I can't think of anybody better to be with.
你是我心目中最理想的人
I don't feel like waiting anymore.
我不想再等了
You know a lot of happily married people? 'Cause I don't.
你見過很多婚姻美滿的人嗎? 我可沒見過
I know all that.
這我都懂
I care about you.
我在乎你
But I just don't have those kind of feelings for you.
但我對你沒有那種感覺
I'm sorry. I'm not in love with you.
對不起 我並不愛你
- All right.  - Understand?
- 好的  - 懂嗎?
I'm sorry.
對不起
No....
不...
That can grow.
那可以培養
As long as there's a mutual respect that kind of thing can grow.
只要互相尊重 感情是可以培養的
I'm realistic. I can accept that.
我很現實 我可以接受
What is love anyway?
愛到底是什麼?
It's a mutual respect. It's a devotion.
不就是互相尊重 不就是一心一意
It's a caring from one person to another.
是一個人在乎另一個人
And if we could set up some kind of foundation...
若我們可以設立一個基礎...
based on that mutual respect...
以相互尊重為底...
I feel that eventually you would care enough about me...
我覺得遲早你會對我有情...
that I could live with that.
這樣我能接受
If it doesn't work out...
若行不通的話...
if it doesn't play out then what happens to me?
若行不通的話 那我怎麼辦?
I'm doing well now. I'm gonna do even better.
我現在做得不錯 往後會越來越好
So whatever happens...
不論如何...
if it doesn't work out between us...
就算我們倆行不通...
I'll make sure you're okay for the rest of your life.
我都會確保你下半輩子的生活
If there are kids especially...
尤其如果有了孩子...
I'll take care of you better than you'd imagine.
我會給你今生最好的照料
- What are you pitching me?  - Just what I said.
- 你葫蘆到底賣什麼藥?  - 我都明講了
You'll be set up for the rest of your life.
你下半輩子都不用愁
That I can promise you.
這我可保證
Want to take a chance?
要不要試試?
When I married Ginger I knew all the stories...
我娶金吉兒時就聽過她的一切往事...
but I didn't give a fuck. I'm Sam Rothstein I said.
但我不在乎 我是山姆·羅斯坦
I can change her.
我能改變她
It was typical Ace.
這是典型的艾斯
He invited the biggest people in town. He knew they'd show.
他請了城裏所有的大人物 他知道他們都會出席
He knew they all wanted something from him.
他知道他們都有求於他
With Ace nobody ever got a free ride. Even Ginger.
艾斯絕對不可能不求回報 連金吉兒也不例外
With her he still covered his bets.
一切還是依他行事
They had to have the baby first before they could get married.
他們在結婚前得先有孩子
He even made us watch Amy for a few days...
他甚至還托我們幫忙看艾美幾天...
when they went on their honeymoon.
好讓他們去渡蜜月
I didn't mind we loved the kid.
無所謂啊 我們愛死那孩子
Can you feel my eyes on you?
你感到我的眼神?
Can you feel me look into your heart?
你感到我看透你的心嗎?
Can you feel me in the pit of your stomach?
你能感到我躺在你肚皮上嗎?
Can you feel me in you?
你能在體內感受我?
In your heart?
在心裏?
Don't make me come there.
別等我過去
Answer me.
回答我
I love you.
我愛你
Baby do you know that I love you too?
寶貝 你知道我也愛你嗎?
- No Lester.  - Do you know that?
- 不 萊斯特  - 你知道嗎?
Yes.
知道
This is the best thing I can do for my life right now.
這是我目前能為自己做的 最好的事
That's right.
沒錯
So it's going to be okay.
所以會沒事的
Promise?
你發誓?
I wish you all the luck in the world.
我希望你幸福
- You do?  - Yeah I do.
- 真的?  - 是 我真的這麼想
It's the best thing you can do right now.
這是你目前能做的最好的事
I mean this.
我說真的
You have real security.
你生活會很安穩
Sweetheart you're gonna be situated just right in Vegas.
甜心 你將坐在賭城最有利的位子
Come on. This is great for us.
這對我們來說再好不過了
I'm always gonna be here for you. I ain't going no place.
我會一直都在你身邊的 我哪兒都不會去
I'm looking at you right now.
我現在就在看著你
I'm seeing you for the very first time right this minute.
彷彿生平第一次見到你似的
I'm saying I can feel my heart click.
我可聽到我的心悸動
I see you 14 years old.
我看到你十四歲時
I see you the first second I ever saw you.
我在見你的第一秒就看到你了
I see you long-legged little colt...
我看到你 像匹長腿的小馬兒...
stupid braces on your teeth.
還戴著蠢蠢的牙套
- Okay then.  - Every time I see you that's what I see.
- 好吧  - 我每次見你時都看到這些
Talk to you later. Bye.
再聊吧 再見
- You all right?  - Yeah.
- 你還好嗎?  - 嗯
Why are you crying?
為什麼哭?
I'm not crying.
我沒有哭
- Maybe you shouldn't drink so much.  - I'm okay.
- 別喝這麼多了吧  - 我沒事
You just have to understand.
希望你能理解
I've been with Lester since I was a kid.
我自小就跟萊斯特在一起
I just wanted to say goodbye.
我只是想道別
I just....
我只是...
I think I have a right to do that.
我想我有權這樣做
Okay?
好嗎?
It's all right.
沒關係
That part of your life is over with.
你那段人生已經完結了
- Right?  - Yeah.
- 不是嗎?  - 是的
You're with me now.
你現在跟我
- Yeah.  - Right?
- 是的  - 不是嗎?
- You're sure?  - Yeah.
- 你確定嗎?  - 是的
- Want to go? Let's go back in.  - Okay.
- 要走了嗎? 我們回去吧  - 好的
It's great.
很好
It's all my stuff. Oh my God.
都是我的東西 天呀
You brought all my stuff!
你把我的東西都帶來了
I can't....
我不能...
Try it on. It's yours.
試試看 這是你的
You're kidding.
別開玩笑了
My God.
我的天
- What is it?  - It's chinchilla.
- 是什麼毛?  - 是龍貓
It's so soft.
好軟喔
Nice isn't it?
很好喔?
No one's ever been so nice to me.
從沒有人對我這麼好
Oh my God!
我的老天
Do you think it's too much if I wear these all on the same day?
我要是在同一天將它們全都戴上 會不會太過火啊?
You can do whatever you want.
你想怎樣就怎樣
Do I keep my promises or do I keep my promises?
我有沒有實現我的諾言啊?
You're so wonderful. The jewelry's not so bad either.
你太好了 這些珠寶也不錯
We shouldn't keep this in the house. We gotta put it in the bank.
我們不應該把這些放在家裏 應該擺到銀行去
Come on. Can I keep this one in the house?
我不能留一副在家嗎?
Pay attention to me.
仔細聽好
What I'm gonna tell you is very important.
我要告訴你一件重要的事
All this stuff doesn't mean anything.
這全部都不算什麼
Money this doesn't mean anything without trust.
錢財珠寶 如果沒有信任就毫無意義
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
我得要信任你到可將生命交給你
洛杉磯
With over $1 million in cash and jewels tucked in a bank in Vegas...
總價值超過一百萬的現金與珠寶 鎖在賭城的銀行裏...
only for Ginger she was secure and happy.
全歸她所有 金吉兒非常有安全感
She loved that shit.
她最愛那些
But a guy in my line of work has to have a lot of payoff cash around.
但在我這行裏 手上得有許多流動的現金
Crooked cops and kidnappers they don't take checks.
貪汙的條子與綁匪 他們都不收支票
Need any help with that Mr. Collins?
考林先生 需要幫忙嗎?
So I put $2 million cash in a Los Angeles bank...
所以我在洛杉磯的銀行裏 也擺了兩百萬...
under the name of Mr. and Mrs. Tom Collins.
用考林先生與夫人的名義
This was strictly my shakedown and kidnapping money.
這純粹是我個人的贖金與保金
Since I'd be in jail or locked in a closet when I needed the money most...
因為在我最需要這筆錢時 我不是蹲在牢裏就是被關在衣櫃...
I gave Ginger the only key to the cash that could get me back alive.
所以我將這筆錢唯一的鑰匙 給了金吉兒好讓我能保命
This is just a signature card.
這是簽名卡
Once she signs she'll be the only person...
她簽了之後就會是世上...
to have total access to the box no one else including myself?
唯一可以開保險箱的人 連我都開啟不了?
That's right. That's the way you wanted it.
是的 這是你的要求
Sam let me ask you a question.
山姆 我問你個問題
You must really trust your wife.
你一定很信任你老婆
Sure I do. Why?
是啊 怎麼啦?
It's good. It's just unusual.
很好啊 只是很少見
To tell you the truth so many of my clients don't.
實不相瞞 我有很多客戶都不信任
With Ginger and the money in place I felt covered.
將金吉兒還有錢的事解決後 我安心多了
To play it safe I switched job titles again...
為了安全起見 我又將頭銜...
and made myself Food and Beverage Director.
換成餐飲董事
This way nobody would bother me about a license.
這樣一來就沒人可以 為執照的事找我麻煩
Vegas was like a dream for me.
賭城對我來說像是個夢
Trouble was Nicky was dreaming of his own kind of Vegas.
問題是尼奇也夢想著 他自己的賭城
I put money out on the street charging three points a week.
我將錢放出 每天三分利
Juice to the dealers.
莊家高利貸
- Don't make us look for you.  - You won't have to look for me.
- 別逼我們找上門  - 你不會需要這樣的
I appreciate it. Thanks Nicky.
多謝了 尼奇
They were degenerate gamblers coke freaks.
他們不是爛賭鬼就是爛毒鬼
In no time I had half the dealers in the Tangiers in my pocket.
沒多久 坦吉樂一半的莊家 都在我手掌心裏
Then the next thing I did I started busting out high-stakes poker players.
下一步 我開始出千騙大賭客的錢
It was so obvious.
好明顯
All of Nicky's half-assed mechanics they were signal-happy.
尼奇所有的小把戲 全都是靠手勢
I'm gonna open for $500.
我下五百
Signaling back and forth.
互相打手勢
Nicky thought nobody was watching him. But he was wrong.
尼奇以為沒人注意到他 但是他錯了
I didn't want any of those agents near my place.
我不想要那些探員在我的地盤
- Four aces.  - I can't believe this.
- 四條A  - 我不相信
If I didn't have bad luck I wouldn't have any luck.
我唯一的運氣好像就是手氣背
I wished Nicky and his whole crew would just get lost.
我真希望尼奇與他那票人 可以馬上消失
What am I gonna do? Go back home and start a war?
但我能怎樣? 回老家去挑起場戰爭?
Nicky's a made guy and I'm not. I can't do that.
尼奇在幫裏算是有頭有臉的人物 我不能那麼做
Gaming agents are all over the place.
到處都是賭博遊樂公會的探員
I'm not allowed to get lucky in this place?
這兒不允許手氣旺的人嗎?
You've been lucky all week. They're looking to nail you.
你已經旺了一個禮拜了 他們在找機會逮你
Ace was so worried about his casino...
艾斯太在意他的賭場...
he forgot what we were doing out here in the first place.
他忘了我們當初為什麼而來
A million times I wanted to yell in his fucking ear:
最少有一百萬次 我都好想在他耳邊大喊...
"This is Las Vegas.
這兒是拉斯維加斯
"We're supposed to be out here robbing you dumb fucking hebe."
"我們本來就是來搶錢的 你這個蠢猶太人"
I don't give a shit who he's connected to.
我才不在乎他有什麼關係
Tell him to take his feet off the table.
叫他把腳從桌上拿下來
Does he think this is a goddamn sawdust joint?
他以為這兒是什麼廉價的地方?
Sir would you mind taking your feet off the table...
先生 麻煩你將腳放下...
and put your shoes on please?
並將鞋穿上 好嗎?
Yeah I would mind. I'm having a bad night.
是 是很麻煩 我今天已經夠背了
Fucking asshole won't budge.
那王八蛋動都不動
Call security.
叫警衛
How are you?
你好嗎?
Good. How are you?
好 你呢?
Do me a favor. Want to take your feet off the table and put your shoes on?
給個面子 把你的腳放下去 然後把鞋穿上好嗎?
Fuck you.
去你的
I want you to exit this guy off the premises off his feet...
我要你把這傢夥從賭場架著丟出去...
and use his head to open the fucking door.
用他的頭來開門
Sir you're gonna have to leave. You mind coming with us outside?
先生 你得離開 麻煩你跟我們出去
Bullshit. I ain't going anywhere with you.
媽的 我哪兒都不跟你去
- Bullshit. You're out of here.  - Fuck you!
- 媽的 你給我滾  - 去你的
You know who you're fucking with? Do you?
你知道你在招惹誰嗎? 你知道嗎?
You fucking faggot! Do you know who you're fucking with?
你他媽的王八蛋 你知道你招惹了誰嗎?
Leave me alone!
別碰我
- Come on!  - You gotta be kidding me!
- 喂  - 別鬧了
Sure enough an hour later I get the call.
不出所料 我一小時後就接到電話
Ace, what happened over there? Did you know that guy was with me?
艾斯 那邊怎麼了? 你知道那傢夥是跟我的嗎?
I didn't know that. You know what he did?
我不知道 你知道他做了什麼嗎?
I walked over to him politely and he tells me to fuck myself.
我很有禮貌的走過去 他卻叫我回家吃自已
- Then he called me a faggot.  - What?
- 還罵我是臭玻璃  - 什麼?
- I threw that cocksucker out.  - Come here.
- 我把那王八蛋踢出去了  - 過來
You called my friend a faggot? Told him to go fuck himself?
你罵我的朋友臭玻璃 還叫他回家吃自己?
Is that what you did? Tell him to go fuck himself?
你這樣說? 叫他回家吃自己?
You fucking hick you!
你這個死鄉巴佬
You go over there. You apologize.
你給我過去道歉
You better hope he lets you back in.
你最好求他讓你進去
If you get out of line again I'll smash your head so hard...
你要再敢沒大沒小 我會將你的頭打到...
you won't be able to get that cowboy hat on. Fucking hick.
你連那牛仔帽都戴不上 死鄉巴佬
Listen this guy obviously doesn't know who he was talking to.
聽著 這傢夥壓根就不知道自己在跟誰說話
He doesn't know that we're dear friends.
他不知道我們是好兄弟
He's already very sorry.
他非常抱歉
But if you could do me a favor and let him back in...
但如果你可買我個面子 讓他再進去...
I swear he'll never get out of line again.
我發誓他再也不會亂來
If he does it again he's out for good.
若他再敢亂來 就別想再踏進這兒
I'll never let him in the place again.
我永遠都不會再讓他進門
I'm sorry about this.
真是對不起
All right Ace? Thanks pal.
好嗎 艾斯? 謝了 兄弟
You took your boots off? You put your feet on the table?
你把鞋都脫了? 把腳放在桌上?
You shit-kicking stinky horse-manure-smelling motherfucker you!
你這全身馬糞騷的渾蛋
You fuck me up over there I'll stick you in a hole in the desert.
你要敢再去丟我的臉 我會在沙漠裏將你埋了
- Go over and apologize.  - Nicky I'm sorry.
- 快給我去道歉  - 尼奇 對不起
Ace could be a very touchy guy.
艾斯可是個很敏感的人
Especially when he got bigger in town.
尤其是當他在城裏越來越出名後
Like when he hired Jonathan and David away from the Palace...
像他將強納森與大衛 從凱撒宮挖角來時...
by building them a new stage and giving them a silver Rolls-Royce.
他為他們蓋了全新的舞臺 還給了他們一人一輛勞斯萊斯
But I tell you he knew how to bring in the crowds.
但我得說 他真的知道怎麼吸引群眾
He knew all the fucking angles.
他懂得一切門路
He brought the whole Femme Fatale show from Paris...
他將整個蛇蠍美人的秀 從巴黎搬來...
but he forgot how lazy them European dancing broads can get.
但他卻忘記那些歐洲跳舞妹有多懶
He had to weigh them once a week so they wouldn't blow up like balloons.
他還得每週為她們秤體重 她們的身材才不至於像吹氣球
You're still eight pounds over.
你還是4公斤過重
- What's the reason for this?  - Mr. Rothstein sir
- 為什麼會這樣?  - 羅斯坦您...
Never mind the "sir." Why is she eight pounds over?
別在那兒您了 她為什麼會超重4公斤?
I'm trying to use respect.
我只是尊重您
Mr. Rothstein is good enough for you.
羅斯坦先生就可以了
Well sometimes when you put that pressure point on them
嗯 有時當你給她們太多的壓力...
All you do is give me answers. Just give me the right answer.
你只需要給我答案 給我正確答案就好
I don't know why. She's frightened if she doesn't lose weight she'll get fired.
我不知道 她害怕要是不減肥 她就會被解雇
That's right she will get fired. Send her back to Paris
沒錯 她會被解雇 送她回巴黎...
- It's been our policy  - Stop everything.
- 我們一貫的做法是...  - 停
- She's an institution.  - That's the problem. She's lazy.
- 她很出名  - 這就是問題 她太懶散
I gotta give the guy credit.
我得佩服這傢夥
I mean he does the most obvious thing.
我的意思是 他做了最明顯的事
This is the only town in the country where a bookie joint is legit.
這裏是全國唯一可以合法簽注的地方
So why not take advantage right?
為什麼不加以利用呢?
So he took bookie joints off the street...
所以他把簽注從街上...
and opened them up inside the casino.
開到賭場內
Within a few years he had...
沒幾年後...
every casino on The Strip trying to copy off of him.
精華地段的每家賭場都想抄襲他
Between my innovations...
我的創意...
and Nicky's dedication to his job...
加上尼奇對工作的投入...
I soon had the best operation on The Strip.
我的賭場很快就成為 精華地段中最好的賭場
Watch yourself. There's a lot of heat on you.
小心點 你最近很引人注目
Why somebody is complaining?
怎麼 有人抱怨嗎?
I'm hearing things from security. They're all ex-cops.
我從警衛那兒聽來的 他們以前都曾是員警
The sheriff wants to put you in the Black Book.
警長已將你放入黑名單了
That Black Book is a bunch of bullshit.
那黑名單根本就是個屁
There's two names in it for the whole country...
全國只有兩個人的名字在裏面
and one of them is still Al Capone.
教父艾爾·卡邦就是其中之一
They put you in that book you're gonna be in trouble.
你上了名單麻煩就大了
You won't be able to walk into a casino.
你將進不了賭場
I'm trying to make a living that's all.
我只不過是在養家活口罷了
I'm just telling you. Don't say I didn't warn you.
我只是跟你講一聲 別說我沒警告你
Mrs. Rothstein straight ahead. Very nice. Thank you.
羅斯坦夫人 請看前面 很好 謝謝你
For his hard work and dedication...
因他的努力與認真...
and the new life blood he has instilled in Las Vegas...
與他為拉斯維加斯帶來的新生命...
Sam has established himself as an indispensable member...
山姆將自己建立為賭博遊樂業界...
of the gaming community.
不可缺乏的成員
As the head of the Tangiers Gaming Corporation...
以坦吉樂賭博遊樂集團 董事長的名義...
it's my pleasure to welcome Sam Rothstein...
我很容幸為你們介紹 山姆·羅斯坦...
to the Vegas Valley Country Club.
維加斯穀鄉村俱樂部新成員
嘉許狀
Back home they'd put me in jail for what I'm doing.
要是在老家 我所做的 早就讓我蹲牢房去了
But out here they're giving me awards.
但在這兒 他們卻頒獎給我
It is with great pleasure that I accept this certificate of appreciation...
我很榮幸能獲得...
from the Charitable Foundations of Greater Las Vegas.
拉斯維加斯慈善基金會頒發的嘉許獎狀
Congratulations sweetheart.
恭喜你 甜心
Sam raised more than we've ever raised before.
山姆募得了有史來最多的捐款
But my greatest pleasure was watching my wife work the room.
但我最愛的還是看著我老婆 金吉兒周旋全場
They all loved her. How could you not love her?
他們愛死她了 但你又怎能不愛她?
She could be the most charming woman you ever saw.
她是世上最有魅力的女人
People loved to be around her.
人們都喜歡在她身邊
You've got to bring Amy to Sasha's birthday party.
你一定得帶艾美來參加莎夏的生日派對
We'd love to have her there. 3:00 Saturday.
星期六下午三點 我們很希望她能來
- Yes okay.  - Great.
- 好的  - 太好了
She made everybody feel good.
她讓大家都開心
- Congratulations Sam.  - Thanks.
- 恭喜你 山姆  - 謝謝
Hello Mrs. Rothstein. How are you?
嗨 羅斯坦夫人 你好嗎?
You're one of the most gorgeous women I've seen. You're a lucky man Mr. Rothstein.
你是我見過最美麗的女人 羅斯坦先生 你真是個幸運的男人
Thanks for that compliment.
多謝誇獎
He was a young kid from the casino. Nice kid. Bright boy.
他是賭場裏的小夥子 挺好又聰明的小子
What balls on this fucking kid. The next day I fired him.
這小子真他媽的帶種 我第二天就炒了他
Ginger had that effect on people. I think she even encouraged them.
金吉兒對人就是有這種魅力 她甚至鼓勵他們這樣
Do you wanna see this one?
你想看看這件嗎?
Daddy gave me all this jewelry because he loves me so much.
爸爸幫我買了這麼多珠寶 因為他好愛我
But as much as they loved her...
但不管他們多愛她...
Fabulous.
真美麗
they didn't know what really moved her.
他們都不知道什麼讓她感動
Look at this.
看看這個
Daddy gave me....
爸爸給我的...
With Ginger happy I was able to concentrate on what I knew best.
金吉兒快快樂樂的 我才能專心去做我所專長的...
Loose machines are right back over there.
較松的機器都在後面
What are they doing back there? You can't even see them.
它們在那兒幹嘛? 看都看不到
Okay.
好吧
What about the progressives with the high jackpots?
那最大累積獎金的那些呢?
These are our best machines. They bring all the action.
這些是我們最好的機子 都是靠它們
No wonder the drop is off. The action is in the front.
難怪盈收變少了 重頭戲都在前面
- Bring them up front.  - All right I will.
- 擺到前面去  - 好的 我會
Listen carefully. There are three ways of doing things here.
聽好了 在這有三種做事方法
The right way the wrong way and the way that I do it.
正確的 不正確的 和我的方法
- Understand?  - I do understand. I'll get right on it.
- 懂了沒?  - 我懂了 馬上去辦
- Thank you.  - Don't thank me. Just do it.
- 謝謝  - 別謝我 去做就是了
You're the slots manager. I shouldn't have to tell you this.
你是吃角子老虎機的經理 我不應該還需要告訴你這些
Dang you are right. I'm so sorry.
唉 你說得真對 真是抱歉
So I ended up working 18-hour days.
我一天得工作18個小時
Ginger was the one who wound up enjoying the best of Vegas.
金吉兒反倒是成為真正享受賭城的人
Come with me please. I have a better table for you.
請跟我來 我帶您去更好的桌
What did you say to that fucking jerk anyway?
你到底跟那王八蛋說了些什麼?
I told him that I was Mrs. Sam Rothstein.
我跟她說我是羅斯坦夫人
You might as well get something out of it.
當然得加以利用咯
It wasn't long before what I was afraid was gonna happen happened.
不久後我所擔心的事就發生了
Nicky managed to get himself banned from every casino in Vegas.
尼奇把自己搞到成為 全賭城的拒絕往來戶
From then on I couldn't be seen talking to him
從那時起 我在賭城完全不能
anywhere in or near Vegas.
被人看見與他交談
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
這他媽的是什麼意思?
"...detrimental to gaming and...
因對業者有害...
"he will be ejected from any casino in Las Vegas.
"他將被禁止進入 拉斯維加斯中任何賭場"
"And the casinos can be fined as much as $100,000...
"違反此規的賭場 在他每次出現時..."
"every time he shows up."
"都將被罰款逾十萬元"
- You believe this shit?  - Yeah you got banned.
- 你相信嗎?  - 是啊 你被禁了
"Because of notorious and unsavory reputation."
"因為眾所周知的惡名昭彰"
Motherfucker.
那些渾蛋
- Is there any way around this?  - No there's no way.
- 有什麼可擺平的方法嗎?  - 不 沒辦法
Let's say for instance...
例如說...
I want to go into the restaurant which happens to be in the casino...
我去了家剛好就附設賭場的餐廳...
to get one of those sandwiches I like?
為了想吃它的三明治呢?
Forget it. You can't even set foot in the parking lot.
別想了 你連停車場都踏不進去
That's how serious it is.
就是這麼嚴重
- in other words I'm fucked?  - in so many words yes.
- 換句話說 我玩完了?  - 換幾句話都是這意思
It didn't sink into his head about the Black Book and what it meant.
他完全都沒瞭解那黑名單的意義
Not being able to go into a casino is just one thing...
不能進賭場只是其一...
but being in this book etched your name into the brains of every cop and FBI agent.
這名單會將你的名字刻在 每一個聯邦調查員的腦海裏
You're listed in there with Al Capone. But Nicky didn't care.
你與芝加哥教父是一樣的 但尼奇不在乎
I gotta do something. They ain't getting rid of me.
我得想想辦法 他們趕不走我的
They're not getting rid of me. I'm staying here. Fuck them.
他們趕不走我的 我要待在這兒 去他們的
So once they pulled that shit...
所以他們一開始這鳥規矩...
I started doing my own things in Vegas nobody had thought of doing.
我就開始做自己突發奇想的事情
To keep an eye on things I brought in my kid brother and some desperados...
為了多點眼線 我將我弟弟與些惡漢從老家帶來...
from back home and started knocking over high rollers casino bosses...
開始搶劫一些賭場豪客 賭場老大...
bookmakers anybody right here in town.
下注組頭等等 全部一網打盡
I had a good fucking crew going for me I'll tell you that.
說真的 我這隊人馬還真是不錯
I had Sal Fusco a great second-story guy.
我有沙爾·福斯寇 最擅長從二樓進屋偷東西
Jack Hardy worked for a safe company before he did a six-year bit.
傑克·哈迪在被關六年前 曾在保險箱製造公司工作
Then there was Bernie Blue. This guy could bypass any alarm for me.
還有本尼·布盧 這傢夥不論什麼警鈴都能解除
It was like old times.
就像以前一樣
I opened up my own jewelry store too. The Gold Rush.
我也開了自己的珠寶店 叫做掏金熱潮
Sometimes I used to go along on a heist just for the fun of it.
有時我會為了刺激好玩 而參與偷竊
I didn't like the people I was ripping off looking at me...
我不喜歡被我偷的人看著我...
so I turned their fucking pictures around.
所以我都將他們的照片轉過去
- What's taking so long?  - This is a motherfucker!
- 為什麼這麼久?  - 這東西真他媽的
- It's working.  - Learn to open these instead of taking them.
- 在動了  - 學會怎麼開就不用整個搬走了
These stones got a lot of niggers in them.
這些寶石的瑕疵真多
If that fucking Pepe's switching stones on us...
那該死的皮皮要是私下偷換鑽石...
he better take a fucking camel back to Nigeria.
他最好給我騎駱駝回奈及利亞
- They're in Penthouse "K."  - Check in alone?
- 他們在總統套房K  - 單獨登記嗎?
- They checked in alone.  - Are they out now?
- 是的  - 他們出去了嗎?
- Yes. Don't worry.  - All right. Thanks.
- 是 別擔心  - 好的 謝啦
He had tipsters all over town. Bellmen...
我們在整城裏都有線民 從旅館侍者...
- You got to hurry.  - Okay.
- 得快點  - 好的
- ...valet parkers...  - They're just checking in now.
- 停車小弟...  - 他們正在登記
- I'll tell him.  - ...pit bosses...
- 我會告訴他  - 賭區經理...
Room 1230 at the Scirocco.
在西洛可的1230房
- 1230. Right.  - ...secretaries.
- 1230房 收到  - 還有秘書
- Mint condition coins.  - Mint condition? All right.
- 完美狀況的硬幣  - 完美狀況嗎? 收到
They all got a piece of the score.
他們當然都有一份
Car's coming.
車來了
They were very careful.
他們都很謹慎
They always bypassed the alarms or else if not...
他們每次都先解除警鈴 要不然...
they'd drill enough holes to knock through the walls with a sledgehammer.
就在牆上打洞然後鑿牆而入
Nicky was grabbing everything he could.
尼奇能偷的都偷了
Nobody out there was expecting a guy like him.
外頭根本沒有人想到 會有像他那樣的人
For Nicky Las Vegas was the fucking Wild West.
對尼奇來說 拉斯維加斯就像是蠻荒西部
I just got a shipment of diamonds from Israel.
我才剛拿到一批從以色列來的鑽石
What the fuck did they expect from me? I had to earn didn't I?
他們他媽的想要我怎樣? 我得賺錢 不是嗎?
- This diamond has flaws in it.  - There's no flaws in it.
- 這些鑽石有瑕疵  - 沒有瑕疵
Don't tell me. I'm doing this for 25 years.
別告訴我怎麼做 我在這行已經25年了
You better clean your loupe because there's no flaws in this diamond.
你的放大鏡最好擦乾淨點 因為這批鑽石沒有瑕疵
When we got local merch...
通常要是附近來的貨...
we'd usually send it to Palm Springs or Arizona L.A.
我們都會送到棕櫚泉市 或是亞利桑那州與洛杉磯
I had a couple of sand niggers out there. You know Arabs.
我有幾個熟識的中東佬 你知道 阿拉伯人
Are you gonna have a meeting or buy some diamonds?
你們是要開會還是要買鑽石?
I know his language. I'm talking with him.
我懂他的語言 我跟他講講
$40,000 you buy the whole package.
全部四萬塊
$20,000. That's my final offer.
兩萬 不要拉倒
He suddenly talks English. Let's talk turkey. $25,000.
他突然會說英文了 別玩遊戲了 兩萬五
I actually turned my bedroom into a bank vault where I kept the choice stuff.
我將我的房間改為保險箱 保留一些我特選的好東西
I couldn't leave it at the Gold Rush in case we got raided by the cops...
因為員警可能會突然臨檢 所以不能將其留在店裏...
or if my crew got cute.
也防止我手下手癢
I had the only key. Jennifer didn't give a fuck.
我保有唯一的鑰匙 珍妮佛才不在乎
She fell asleep on the couch watching TV every night.
她每晚都在沙發上 看電影看到睡著
This stuff was all mine. I didn't send any of this back home.
這些全是我的東西 我一樣也沒送回老家
Actually I couldn't because I wasn't supposed to be doing it.
其實我也不行 因為我根本不應該做這些
The bosses were making so much money with the casinos...
老大們光是賭場就賺飽了...
that they didn't want anybody making any waves.
他們不希望有人惹是非
You've all given your crew a piece of that?
你的人馬每人都分到了嗎?
I took care of everybody.
我大家都罩好了
That's why there was no real organized street stuff in Vegas before I came.
這就是為什麼在我來之前 拉斯維加斯並沒有犯罪集團
But how much cash could I bury in my closet right?
但我家衣櫃裏又能藏多少錢呢?
You have to understand and I'm sure you do...
你必須要瞭解 而我也相信你瞭解...
that in a venture of this kind...
做這種風險大的投資...
you must be prepared to take some kind of loss.
要有可能虧損的心理準備
I put some money in legitimate deals with Charlie Clark Ace's banker.
我將一些錢交給查理·克拉克 艾斯的銀行經理 做一些正當投資
- You will try to push it through won't you?  - Yes.
- 你會盡力而為 不是嗎?  - 是的
You got to understand I'm giving you $50,000 cash.
你得瞭解我現在 給了你五萬元現金
Then I put more money in some legitimate places like my restaurant.
然後我將更多錢投入正當的投資 例如我開的餐館
- Is that the last one?  - Yeah.
- 剩這個了?  - 是
I had my kid brother Dominick run it.
我讓我小弟 多明尼可經營
Fuckers.
王八蛋
Here you go guys.
在這裏
- Thanks a lot.  - Enjoy it. Have a good time.
- 謝了  - 慢慢享用
- Choke on it motherfucker.  - Hi Dom.
- 噎死你 王八蛋  - 嗨 小多
How you doing?
你怎麼樣?
Yeah Nicky loved restaurants. He was a real restaurant buff.
是啊 尼奇很喜歡餐館 他對開餐廳也很拿手
And over the years he always made money with them.
這麼多年來 他逢開餐廳必賺
In Vegas he had the Leaning Tower. It was a very popular spot.
他在拉斯維加斯開了比薩斜塔 很受大家歡迎
He had politicians showgirls and movie stars hanging out all over.
常有政客 脫衣舞孃 還有電影明星光顧
That show at The Flamingo gets better and better.
佛羅明哥的那場秀越做越好
By the way Sammy said whenever you have a minute give him a call.
對了 山姆說 請你有空時打個電話給他
- Made you a messenger too?  - I'll do anything for a buck.
- 你也變傳話的了啊?  - 有錢我什麼都做啊
- He does it to everybody. Enjoy your dinner.  - Thanks.
- 他對每個人都這樣 好好享用晚餐  - 謝啦
I got to tell you the thing Nicky liked most was the showgirls.
尼奇最喜歡的 當然就是脫衣舞孃
To them Nicky was the movie star.
對她們來說 尼奇像是電影名星
- You walk past me?  - This is Shelly.
- 你就這樣走過?  - 這是雪麗
- Hi Shelly. How are you?  - Hi.
- 嗨 雪麗 你好嗎?  - 嗨
This is Stacy.
這是史黛希
- This is Nick. Wanna have dinner? Come on.  - All right.
- 這是尼克 想吃晚餐嗎? 一起吧  - 好啊
Let's check the kitchen first. Excuse us one second.
我帶你去廚房看看 失陪一下
Come on I'll show you. I fly stuff in fresh every day.
來吧 我帶你去 我每天都空運新鮮的東西進來
I get bread from back home. I get fish from California.
我從老家運麵包 從加州運魚
You can always tell a great kitchen like ours because of the milk-fed veal.
光從我們用奶餵食的小牛肉就看得出 我們絕對是好餐廳
That's the secret. See milk-fed veal is pure white.
這就是訣竅 奶喂小牛的肉是純白色的
Out here they got that pink veal. Slide over honey.
其他餐館都用那種粉紅色的小牛肉 過去點 甜心
Now pink veal you can pound for two days.
粉紅色的那種小牛肉 你就算是追個兩天兩夜
It'll never ever get tender. You know what I mean?
它還是不會變嫩 你懂我的意思嗎?
I left here with the money. Got muscled on the street.
我從這兒拿錢離開時 在街上被搶了
A couple guys I owe them. So I gave them the money.
是幾個我欠錢的傢夥 所以我把錢給他們了
- That's what I did.  - Yeah?
- 就是這樣  - 是嗎?
You call yourself a man?
你還敢自稱是男人嗎?
You know you're a lying lowlife motherfucking gambling degenerate prick?
你知道你是個撒謊的雜碎 他媽的爛賭的狗東西嗎?
You know that's what you are? Two small kids at home.
你知道自己是什麼東西嗎? 家裏有兩個小孩
I gave you money to pay the fucking rent...
我給你錢付房租...
and buy groceries put the heat on.
買菜 開暖氣
You know your wife called Frankie and told him the fucking heat's off?
你知道你老婆打給法蘭克 說家裏連暖氣都被停了嗎?
You didn't gamble that money? Can you tell me that?
你沒拿錢去賭嗎? 你敢這樣跟我說嗎?
- No you didn't?  - I didn't.
- 你沒有嗎?  - 沒有
Don't fuck with me Al! Don't make a fuck out of me.
別耍我 艾爾 別把我當傻子
You wanna make a fool out of me? You didn't gamble?
你當我是傻子是吧? 你沒去賭?
Tell me you gambled the money and I'll give you the money to put the heat on!
告訴我你把錢拿去賭掉了 我就給你錢回去交電費
Did you gamble?
有沒有賭?
Fucking degenerate you.
真是他媽的狗東西
Fucking kids at home.
孩子在家裏
Here. Get the fuck out of here.
拿去 給我滾
- Thanks Nick.  - Yeah thanks.
- 謝了 尼克  - 是啊 謝了
If I find out you fucked up I'll leave you where I find you.
若被我知道是你搞砸的 我會把你扔在我找到你的地方
- How many of these you gonna eat?  - Two.
- 你要吃幾個?  - 兩個
At around 6:30 a.m. when he finished his day...
但早上六點半 當他下班時...
no matter where he was or what he was doing...
不管他在那裏或是在做什麼...
he always went home to make breakfast for his son Nicky boy.
他都會回家為兒子 小尼奇做早餐
I know you like this.
我知道你喜歡
A little butter right? Not a lot. You know why right?
一點點牛油 對不對? 不要很多 你知道為什麼 對不對?
- Why?  - 'Cause it clogs up your heart.
- 為什麼?  - 因為會堵塞心臟
What a smart kid you are.
你真是聰明的孩子
Okay eat.
快吃吧
Every couple of weeks I sent Marino back to the bosses...
每隔幾個禮拜我就會派瑪雷諾去老大那兒...
with a piece of what I made. Not a big piece but what did they know?
也分他們一份 當然不是很多 但他們哪知道?
在老家
They were 1,500 miles away and I don't know anybody who can see that far.
他們在2500裡外 天高皇帝遠
Their drop was a truck stop garage...
收貨地點是個修車場...
where Remo and the guys used to hang out and count their millions.
利蒙他們以前常在那兒數錢
The cops knew but they didn't give a fuck. They worked it out.
條子們也知道 但他們不在乎 他們早協議好了
Nicky sends his warmest regards.
尼奇向你們問好
I knew how to keep the bosses happy.
我知道怎樣讓老大們服服帖帖
Whenever they gave me little jobs to do you know to send a message...
每當他們有些小事需要我做 例如傳個話之類的...
I would carry things out to a "T."
我一定做到完美
Like the time Tony Dogs who was supposed to be the new maniac tough guy in town...
就像那次東尼道格 那個聽說是城裏的新硬漢...
shot up one of Remo's bars.
在利蒙的一家酒吧亂開槍
Here's a fucking guy who kills two of Remo's guys...
這渾蛋打死了兩個利蒙的手下...
and a poor fucking waitress who was just working on her night off.
還有一個代班的倒楣女侍者
This guy's just begging to be made an example of.
這傢夥根本就等著被我們殺雞儆猴
I want the names of all the other people he had with him.
我要知道當天有誰跟他一起動手
I don't care what you have to do to them to get them. You understand?
我要你不擇手段去查 懂不懂?
I'll take care of it.
我搞定 利蒙
To be truthful with you I had to admire this fucking guy.
說真的 我還蠻佩服這渾蛋的
He was one of the toughest Irishmen I ever met.
他真是我所遇過 最硬脖子的愛爾蘭人
This son of a bitch was tough.
這傢夥真是個硬漢
For two days and two nights we beat the shit out of him.
我們痛毆了他兩天兩夜
We even stuck ice picks in his balls.
還用冰銼刺他的睪丸
He better give me a name or I'm gonna give him yours, Frank.
他最好快吐個名字出來 法蘭克 要不然我就遞你的上去
Thanks a lot.
謝謝喔
But he never talked.
但他守口如瓶
I know you would've ratted by now.
我知道你要供早就供了
In the end, I had to put his fucking head in a vise.
最後 我還得他媽的把他的頭擺在夾板裏
Can you hear me?
你聽到了沒?
Listen to me. I got your head in a vice.
聽好 你的頭在夾板裏
I'll squash your head like a grapefruit if you don't give me a name.
再不給我個名字 我就夾爆你的頭
Don't make me do this. Please come on.
別逼我這麼做 拜託你快說吧
Don't make me be a bad guy.
別逼我當壞人
Fuck you.
去你的
Motherfucker. You believe this? Two fucking days and nights.
王八蛋 你相信嗎? 他媽的兩天兩夜
Fuck me? You motherfucker!
去我的? 你這個王八蛋
Fuck my mother? Is that what you're telling me?
去我老母? 你是這意思是吧?
You motherfucker!
你這渾蛋
Oh God. Give me the fucking name!
天呀 給我一個名字
Charlie M.
查理
- Charlie M.  - Charlie M?
- 查理  - 查理?
You make me pop your eye out your head...
你逼我將你眼珠都爆出來...
to protect that piece of shit?
就為了保護這狗屁名字?
You dumb motherfucker!
王八蛋加蠢才
Kill me you fuck!
殺了我啊 渾蛋
You motherfucker!
你這王八蛋
Frankie do him a fucking favor.
法蘭克 你幫幫他吧
Word got around that finally...
鎮上流傳著...
there was a real gangster in town.
說這兒終於出了個真的幫派份子
Nicky was the new boss of Las Vegas.
尼奇成了拉斯維加斯的新老大
Four reels, sevens across. Three $15,000 jackpots.
四個輪 一排七個 三個一萬五的獎金
You have any idea what the odds are?
你知道這機率是多少嗎?
It's gotta be in the millions. Maybe more.
要好幾百萬 可能更多
Three jackpots in 20 minutes?
二十分鐘內三個大獎?
Why didn't you pull the machines? Why didn't you call me?
你為什麼沒停機? 為什麼沒通知我?
It happened quick. Three guys won. I didn't have a chance.
發生得太快 一下就三個人贏 我還沒機會
You didn't see the scam?
你沒看到出千嗎?
There's no way to determine that.
這無法確定
Yes there is. An infallible way. They won!
有 絕對有 他們贏了就是最好的證據
It's a casino. People gotta win sometimes.
這裏是賭場 總會有人贏的
You're pissing me off. You're insulting my intelligence.
你氣死我了 你在污辱我的智慧
You think I'm an idiot?
你認為我是白癡?
Somebody had to get into those machines and set the reels.
一定有人對轉輪動了手腳
The probability on one machine is a million and a half to one.
一台機的機率是一百五十萬比一
On three machines in a row it's in the billions. It can't happen.
連續三台的機率是好幾兆比一 這根本不可能
What's the matter with you?
你到底是怎麼了?
Didn't you see you were being set up on the second win?
你難道不知道你被騙了嗎?
- You didn't see that?  - I think you're overreacting.
- 你沒看到嗎?  - 我覺得你有些反應過度
Listen, you fucking yokel. I've had it with you.
聽著 智障 我受夠你了
I've been carrying your ass ever since I got here.
我從到這兒時就一直罩你
Get your things and get out of here.
把東西收收走吧
- You're firing me?  - I'm firing you.
- 你開除我?  - 我就開除你
- You might regret this.  - I'll regret it if I keep you.
- 你可能會後悔  - 留你我一定後悔
- This is not the way to treat people.  - If you didn't know about the scam...
- 不應該這樣對人  - 若你不知道有人出千...
you're too dumb to work here. If you did you were in on it.
你就蠢到不配在這兒工作 若你知道 你就是共犯
Either way you're out. Go on.
不管怎樣 你都得走
The guy is history as far as I'm concerned.
在我看來那傢夥已經被炒了
You can't fire him. His brother-in-law is County Commissioner.
你不能開除他 他的姐夫是縣輔導
Everyone out here with cowboy boots is a commissioner or related to one.
這裏每個穿馬靴的不是輔導 就是輔導的親戚
I'm sick of this.
我受夠了
This is his state. His uncle's Chief Judge.
這是他的州 他的叔叔是大法官
His brother-in-law runs the County Commission.
他的姐夫管理縣委員會
There's gotta be a way to work him back in.
一定有方法讓他回來
You're in the finances upstairs. You don't see what's going on.
你是搞帳目的 在樓上 你看不到下麵發生的事
I've got thousands of players. I got 500 dealers.
我有上千的賭客 卻只有五百個莊家
They're all looking to rob me blind 24 hours a day.
他們每天24小時都在想著怎麼將我搶空
I have to let them know I'm watching all the details all the time.
我必須要讓他們知道 我隨時都在注意每個細節
That there is not one single thing I will not catch.
我不會漏掉任何一樣事情
Look at yours. Look at that.
看你的 看
Look at this. There's nothing.
再看這個 什麼都沒有
Look how many blueberries your muffin has.
你看你的藍莓那麼多
- I have nothing.  - What are you talking about?
- 我一個都沒有  - 你在說什麼?
If you don't do it yourself it never gets done.
自己不動手做就弄不好
Where are you going?
你要去哪兒?
From now on I want you to put an equal amount of blueberries in each muffin.
從現在開始 我要你全都放同份量的藍莓
An equal amount of blueberries in each muffin.
全都放同份量的藍莓
Do you know how long that will take?
你知道那多花時間嗎?
I don't care how long it takes. Put an equal amount in each muffin.
我不管要多久 每個鬆餅的份量都要一致
Just a little. That a girl.
再吃一點 乖
- Wanna go to Mommy?  - Wanna come to Mommy?
- 你要找媽媽?  - 來媽媽這兒?
It's all right sweetheart.
好的 甜心
I need to talk to you. I need some money.
我要跟你談談 我需要點錢
- What do you need?  - Got her?
- 你要什麼?  - 抱好了嗎?
I need a lot. I need more than usual.
我需要很多 比平時要多
Why don't you take it out of your account?
為什麼不從你戶頭領呢?
I would, you know, Sam, it's just that...
我本想 只是...
I need more than that. I need $25,000.
我需要更多 我要兩萬五
$25,000?
兩萬五千元?
- For yourself?  - Yeah.
- 你自己要?  - 是啊
Why do you need that much?
你為什麼要那麼多?
What's the difference? I just need it.
有什麼差別? 我需要就是了
I gotta ask you. That's a lot of money. It's not a box of popcorn.
我一定得問啊 那很多錢耶 又不只是一盒爆米花
We don't have to turn this into a big deal.
我們不用將這變成件大事
We don't have to have a fight.
我們不用吵架
It was important to me. Forget it. Something I wanted to do.
只是對我很重要 算了 有些想做的事罷了
Who's fighting? Tell me what it's for.
誰在吵架? 告訴我錢的用處
Why can't you tell me what it's for?
為什麼不能告訴我?
Now I want you to tell me.
現在我要你告訴我
My wife comes to me and asks me for $25,000. Do you want a coat?
我老婆跑來問我要兩萬五 你想買大衣嗎?
- No.  - If you want a coat you got it.
- 不  - 如果想買大衣 就去買啊
It's not the money. It's just why do you want it?
不是錢的問題 只是 你為什麼要?
Am I not entitled to ask that?
我無權過問嗎?
I've been independent all my life. I never had to ask anybody for anything.
我一輩子都很獨立 我從不為任何事求人
Now you're making me beg you for this.
現在你要我求你是吧
- What are you talking about?  - Okay? And you're embarrassing me.
- 你在說什麼?  - 好 你還羞辱我
- Why make me feel so bad?  - You're asking me for $25,000.
- 為什麼得讓我如此難受?  - 你問我要兩萬五
I'm not out to make you feel bad. I want to just be able to trust you.
我不是要讓你難堪 我只是希望能信任你
It's about trust.
是信任問題
I have to be able to trust you with my life.
我必須要連性命都能交託於你
Do you understand?
你懂嗎?
Can I trust you?
我能信任你嗎?
Answer me. Can I trust you?
告訴我 我能嗎?
You can trust me.
你能
Good. So then you can tell me what the money is for.
好 那你就可以告訴我 錢要拿來幹嘛
She's leaving the bank now.
她現在正離開銀行
I'll follow her.
我跟著她
What is that?
那是什麼?
I know that look. What does that look mean?
我知道那神情 那表情是什麼意思?
It means I got the money.
意思是我有錢
How are you doing? It's Lester right?
你好嗎? 是萊斯特吧?
From my recollection aren't you the card shark...
我記得你不是玩牌老手...
the golf hustler the pimp from Beverly Hills?
高爾夫球騙子 比佛利山莊的皮條客嗎?
If I'm wrong correct me.
若記錯了 請糾正我
I never knew you to be a heist man.
我從不知道你也是個小偷
But if you are you know what?
不過如果是的話 這樣吧
Here take mine too.
我的也拿去吧
Take it. You already have hers.
拿吧 反正你已拿了她的
She's my wife.
她是我老婆
Look at me.
看著我
You did know that didn't you? You knew she's my wife?
你知道吧? 你知道她是我老婆吧?
- Look at me.  - I know that.
- 看著我  - 我知道
You do yeah?
知道啊?
If you ever come back again...
你下次若再想回來...
to take her money next time bring a pistol.
拿她的錢 記得帶槍
That way you got a chance.
這樣你才有機會
Be a man don't be a fucking pimp.
當個男人 別做皮條客
Now you want to do me a favor? Get out of here.
現在 賣我個面子 快滾吧
I wanna be alone with my wife. Get the fuck up and get out of here.
我想跟我老婆獨處 給我他媽的滾
Fucking piece of shit.
渾蛋狗雜種
Remember when you called him that night and said goodbye to him?
記得那晚你打電話跟他道別嗎?
He didn't say "Don't get married. I'll be right down."
他並沒說 "別結婚 我馬上來"
- He didn't say that did he?  - No he didn't.
- 他沒這樣說吧?  - 不 沒有
What did he say?
那他說了什麼?
"Fuck him. Take him for everything he's got."
"跟他睡 撈光他的錢"
Come here. I want to show you something.
過來 我給你看樣東西
Make them stop it!
叫他們停
It's not his fault! It's my fault!
不是他的錯 是我的錯
Piece of shit.
沒用的狗雜種
Do it yourself you chickenshit cocksucker!
自己來吧 你這沒膽的渾蛋
He's such a prick.
他太可惡了
He had some guy from the hotel beat him up.
他叫旅館的人揍他
He didn't want to do it himself.
他自己不想動手
He didn't want to get his own hands dirty.
他不想將手弄髒
Why did he have to do that?
他為什麼要這樣?
Tell me.
告訴我
- It wasn't a nice thing to do  - No shit.
- 那不是件好事...  - 廢話
You gotta understand it. He doesn't know if this guy is shaking you down.
你得瞭解 他並不知道這人是不是在騙你的錢
I told him all about this guy before we got married.
我在結婚前就告訴過他這個人了
- This is no fucking surprise.  - You did? I didn't know that.
- 這並不是什麼新鮮事  - 是嗎? 我並不知道
He's just a friend of mine I was trying to help. So what?
他只是我的朋友 我想要幫他 有什麼大不了?
The first time I ever saw you guys together...
我第一次看到你們倆在一起時...
I never saw him so happy.
我從未見他那麼快樂過
I know he's a crazy Jew fuck and everything...
我知道他是個猶太瘋子...
but I never seen him act like that with anybody else.
但我從未見過他跟別人一起時這樣
I think he's crazy about you. He really loves you.
他為你瘋狂 他真的很愛你
- He does.  - Come on.
- 他真的是  - 拜託
I went into this with my eyes open.
我是睜著雙眼走進這關係的
I knew the bottom could drop out any time.
我知道隨時都可能變卦
I'm a working girl. You don't think I'm gonna go into a situation like this...
我也混過 你真以為我在沒有保障的情況下...
if I don't think I'm covered on the back end?
會走這條路嗎?
Sure I can see that.
是啊 我可以瞭解
So he put aside some jewelry for me. A lot of jewelry.
他買了好多珠寶給我 好多好多
A lot of expensive jewelry? About how much?
很多貴重的珠寶? 大概值多少?
You want to steal it?
你想偷嗎?
No. I'm just curious. I was wondering...
不 只是好奇 我是在想...
how much he would put into a thing like that.
他會在那種東西裏投入多少錢
I'm told it's worth about $1 million maybe more.
他跟我說大約一百萬 可能更多
There you go. What does that tell you?
那就是咯 這說明瞭什麼?
$1 million in jewelry.
一百萬的珠寶
Does that tell you he is crazy about you?
這不說明瞭他愛你愛到瘋了嗎?
I should have never married him.
我根本就不該嫁給他的
He's a Gemini. Triple Gemini. Duality.
他是雙子座的 雙子加三級 兩面人
Gemini is the snake you know. You can't trust a snake.
雙子座就像條蛇 你不能相信蛇
I mean it.
我說真的
I know what you mean. Listen Ginger.
我懂你的意思 金吉兒 聽著
This is probably not.... I don't have the answers anyway.
這可能不是... 我也沒有答案
- This is probably not what you want to hear.  - I do.
- 這可能不是你想聽的  - 我想
You're a little upset and I understand that.
你不高興 我可以理解...
But try to make the best of it now. Go slow. See what happens.
但先撐著點吧 慢慢來 看看會發生什麼事
He could've killed him!
他差點殺了他
He didn't have to hit him. I'm not sleeping with the guy.
他用不著打他 我又沒跟他上床
He makes me sneak around to see my own friends.
他讓我得偷偷摸摸的跟我的朋友見面
What the fuck is that all about?
這算什麼呢?
I guess it's 'cause he loves you so much he's jealous and worries.
我想是因為他太愛你了吧 他吃醋又擔心
Who gives a fuck what I do?
誰會在乎我做什麼?
I'll try to find out what the hell is going on.
我會試著問問到底怎樣
- When I see him I'll talk to him.  - Okay.
- 遇到他時我會跟他談談的  - 好
- All right?  - Yeah.
- 可以嗎?  - 好
Thanks...
謝了...
for putting up with me.
忍受我嘮叨
Take it easy with this shit. This can only make matters worse.
別喝這麼兇吧 這只會讓情況更糟
You're a beautiful girl. Don't ruin that.
你是個美女 別搞砸了
I've seen a lot of girls get shot to hell from this stuff.
我看過太多漂亮女孩 因這個變醜八怪
You're so nice.
你真好
Come on now. I don't wanna see you unhappy.
好了啦 我不想見你不快樂
Thanks.
謝了
It's all right.
沒事啦
County Commissioner Pat Webb is here to see you.
縣輔導派特·委布來見你
- Give me a minute.  - Okay. Just a minute.
- 等一下  - 好的 請稍候
Mr. Webb, can I get you anything?
你需要什麼嗎?
No, thank you, little lady.
不 謝謝 小姐
Send him in and call me four minutes after.
讓他進來 然後四分鐘後打給我
Mr. Rothstein I'm Pat Webb.
羅斯坦先生 我是派特·委布
How do you do?
你好嗎?
- It is a pleasure.  - I heard a lot about you.
- 幸會  - 我常聽起你的事
Thank you sir. House is doing well.
過獎了 莊家最近還過得去
All that money is rolling in.
那麼多錢滾滾而來
I appreciate you taking the time to see a poor old civil servant.
我很感激你願意見我這老公僕
- Why don't you have a seat?  - Thank you sir.
- 不如坐下吧?  - 謝謝您
I come here personally to smooth over...
我是來親自化解...
any fracas about a certain matter.
一些小誤會的
Maybe you didn't know it...
你可能不知道...
but Don Ward is a very well-liked man in this town.
但道恩·華德在鎮上挺受歡迎的
He's got lots of friends. His family and their money go back many years.
他有許多朋友 他們家族及產業也很久了
Now, friends vote. Family and money votes.
朋友是選民 家人與金錢都能助選
That's important to me and you.
這對你我都很重要
If you'll think about our little problem along them lines...
若你從這個角度來看我們這個小問題的話...
and you'll forgive me for saying it...
很抱歉我得這麼說...
maybe he did not deserve to be fired.
但他可能不該被開除
He knew about our getting hit...
他非常清楚我們...
on three big machines in a row and he did nothing about it.
在一瞬間被贏了三個大獎 但他卻袖手旁觀
Either he was in on it or he was too dumb to see what was going on.
他要不是跟他們一夥 那很抱歉 他就是蠢到看不見
Either way, I cannot have a man like that working here.
不論如何 我都無法讓一個這樣的人在這兒工作
Before we point the dirty end of the stick at old Don...
在將過錯都推給道恩前...
we better be sure we can prove them charges.
我們得先確定有證據這樣指控他
Believe me, if I could prove it, he would be under arrest.
相信我 要是有證據 他早就被逮捕了
Are we certain that you want the Gaming Control Board...
你確定要讓賭博遊樂委員會...
eyeballing your record and your gangster pals like Nicky?
過目你與你的幫派朋友 尼奇的記錄嗎?
I think you're way out of line talking to me like that.
我覺得你這樣跟我說 有點太過份了
What you're saying is libelous. You're in no position to challenge my expertise.
你所說的幾乎是譭謗 你無權懷疑我的專業
I went way out of my way to be helpful and courteous to that kid.
我已盡我所能去 幫助並善待那孩子
He's weak. He's incompetent. He jeopardizes the whole place.
他太弱了也很無能 他使這地方瀕於險境
There's not much more I can do for him.
我對他真的無能為力
You have got me there.
這倒是真的
Old Don is as useless as tits on a boar.
道恩就像公豬身上的奶頭一樣無用
But he is my brother-in-law...
但他還是我的小舅子...
and I would look on it as a personal favor...
我會當是我欠你的一個人情
if you'd think some more on hiring him back.
若你願意考慮重新聘用他
I can't do that.
我不能
I appreciate the fact that he's your brother-in-law.
我知道他是你的小舅子
I do want to help you and I like to do favors.
我也想幫你更喜歡賣人情
And I know who you are. But I cannot do that.
我也知道你的地位 但我真的不能這麼做
Could there be any position...
日後是否會有其它較適合的...
farther down the trough?
職位呢?
I'm sorry. I can't do anything.
抱歉 並沒有
He's too incompetent. The bottom line is he cannot be trusted.
他太無能了 最終還是他不能被信任
Okay thanks a lot.
好吧 謝謝
That's it. I'm sorry.
抱歉
Mr. Rothstein your people never will understand...
羅斯坦先生 你們這幫人永遠都不會懂...
the way it works out here.
這裏的世界如何運作
You're all just our guests.
你們只不過來此地做客
But you act like you're at home.
但卻喧寶奪主
Let me tell you something partner. You ain't home.
讓我告訴你 老兄 這並不是你家
But that's where we'll send you if it harelips the Governor.
家是我們州長生氣時 送你們回的地方
- Thank you for your time.  - No problem.
- 多謝你空出時間見我  - 沒問題
- Sorry.  - You bet.
- 對不起  - 當然
What happened to my pills?
我的藥呢?
Isn't it bad enough you drink too much? You're taking my pills too?
你喝那麼多酒還不夠嗎? 你還要吃我的藥?
I didn't take your pills.
我沒吃你的藥
For my ulcer I take a half of one of these.
我因為胃潰瘍 才吃半顆
That's when I have extreme pain.
而且是痛到無法忍時才吃
I had a three-month supply. What did you do with them?
我本來有三個月份的 你弄到哪裏去了?
You didn't have to beat him up.
你用不著打他的
What?
什麼?
I was just trying to help him.
我只是想幫他
Like I'm sleeping with the guy.
好像我跟他上床似的
Yeah how do I know?
是嗎 我哪知道?
You can't make me stop caring about people.
你不能讓我完全不關心別人
- What?  - I said...
- 什麼?  - 我說...
you can't make me stop caring about people.
你不能讓我完全不關心別人
Listen...
聽著...
I'm trying to make the best of everything here.
我只想讓一切比較好
I mean you're my wife for Christ's sakes.
老天啊 你是我老婆
People look up to you in this town.
鎮上的人都很看重你
You know what Ace? I don't give a shit.
你知道嗎 艾斯? 那關我屁事
I'm getting out of here.
我要離開
You gotta get a hold of yourself.
你冷靜一點
- Okay.  - If not for me at least for Amy.
- 好  - 不為我 也為艾美
Understand? Your drinking's getting way out of hand.
懂嗎 你酒喝得太過份了
I'm gonna get you into a program. They got plenty of good ones.
我幫你安排去做治療 這兒有很多好療養所
- I don't need one.  - Yes you do. It's very discreet.
- 我不需要  - 你需要 那很隱密的
There's no names in the papers.
姓名也不會被公佈
That's all you care about.
你只在乎名譽
You don't care about me.
你不在乎我
- Yes I do.  - No you don't.
- 我在乎  - 不 你不在乎
How could you say that?
你怎能這樣說?
You're a beautiful woman. You're destroying yourself.
你是個美麗的女人 你在摧殘自己
You don't need that stuff that fucking leech living off you.
你不需要那些 你現在芒刺在背
I know you better than you know yourself.
我比你還要瞭解你
You're a tiger. You're stronger than I am.
你像隻老虎 你比我還堅強
When you set your mind on doing something you do it better than anybody.
只要你下定決心的事 你就做得比任何人都要好
You're gonna do it.
你一定得去
Oh God.
天啊
I'll try.
我試
I will.
我會的
Don't be mad at me okay?
別生我氣 好嗎?
No matter what the problems were outside the count room...
不管在計算室外有多少問題...
it was all worth it.
都是值得的
The cash kept rolling in...
現金滾滾而來...
and the suitcases kept coming and going.
皮箱也不停的進出
And let me tell you the fucking bottom line here is cash.
讓我告訴你 除了錢還是錢
The only problem was that after a while...
唯一的問題是過了一陣子後...
the bosses noticed that the suitcases were getting a little light.
老大們發覺皮箱越來越輕
Wait a minute. You mean to tell me...
等一下 你是說...
that the money we're robbing is being robbed?
我們搶的錢被人搶?
Somebody's robbing from us?
有人搶我們?
We go through all this fucking trouble and somebody's robbing us?
我們這麼大費周章 竟有人在搶我們?
Like I said it's part of the business. It's considered leakage.
如我所說 這就是這行的一部分 就當做是遺漏的
Leakage my balls. I want the guy who's robbing us.
遺漏 狗屁 我要找到搶我們的人
Even John Nance that's the guy who ran the scam...
就連約翰·南斯 主導這騙局的人...
he knew there wasn't much he could do about it.
都知道自己無能為力去阻止
You gotta know that a guy who helps you steal...
你得知道一個肯幫你偷錢的人...
even if you take care of him real well...
就算你把他照顧得好好的...
he's gonna steal a little extra for himself.
他還是為自己多偷一點
Makes sense don't it? Right?
很合理不是嗎?
You go try and make these hard-headed old greaseballs understand that.
試著讓這些固執的老頭們瞭解吧
What's the point of skimming if we're being skimmed?
如果自己抽完還要被別人抽 還有什麼意義?
It defeats the whole purpose of what we're doing.
這樣我們根本就在做白工嘛
They take this money because they're my guys so give them some leeway.
他們是我的手下才幫我們拿錢 就睜隻眼閉隻眼吧
But the bosses never believed in leeway...
但老大們從來就不相信這理論...
so listen to what they do.
聽聽他們做了什麼
They put Artie Piscano the underboss of K. C...
他們將艾題·派斯康 堪薩斯市的二佬...
in charge of making sure nobody skimmed the skim.
調來管理 確定沒有人抽頭
- What were you doing?  - I was with my goomah.
- 你那時在幹嘛?  - 我與我馬子一起
- What are you doing with your goomah?  - I gave her a schiaffo.
- 你跟你馬子那時在幹嘛?  - 我打她一巴掌
The only trouble was Piscano was a disaster.
問題是 派斯康是個麻煩
This guy could fuck up a cup of coffee.
這傢夥連泡咖啡都可搞砸
- What you been doing?  - I'm out there more than I'm here.
- 你都在幹嘛?  - 我在那兒的時間比在這兒多
Little did anybody know where this would lead.
當時沒人想到 後來會演變為何
If they did they would've been better off making fucking novenas.
若有人早知道 去做念珠可能都還好些
You gotta go back there and talk to that guy.
你得回去跟那傢夥講
- My expenses weren't paid for the last trip.  - What expenses?
- 我上次的花費都還沒補給我  - 什麼花費?
I'm laying money out of my own pocket and I never get anything back.
我一直自掏腰包 卻什麼都拿不回來
You gotta go back out there.
你得再回去
From now on I'm gonna start keeping records.
從今開始 我得開始做記錄了
What are you gonna do with records, pay taxes?
你要記錄幹嘛 繳稅嗎?
I can't keep laying out my own fucking dough for these trips.
我不能一直這樣自己出錢 跑來跑去
What the hell are we doing over here?
我們他媽的到底在那兒幹嘛?
You're going to Las Vegas and having a good time at my expense.
我花錢讓你去賭城玩
What the fuck? I mean after all....
我靠 我是說...
No matter how many novenas you could make...
不論你做了幾符念珠...
nothing was gonna stop what came up next at the casino.
都無法阻止接下來 在賭場發生的事
- I can't believe you're doing this.  - We made a deal.
- 我不相信你會這樣做  - 我們有協議
It turned out Phil Green "Mr. Integrity"...
結果菲立浦·葛林 "老實先生"...
had a partner nobody knew about...
有個沒人知道的搭擋...
and when she showed up and demanded money from Tangiers...
當她出現並向坦吉樂要錢時...
- Why are you doing this to me?  - Because you're wrong.
- 你為什麼這樣對我?  - 因為你錯了
- I'm not.  - You are.
- 我沒錯  - 你有
No I am not wrong.
不 我沒錯
Green tried to stonewall her.
葛林試著搪塞她
I will see that you don't get away with this.
我不會這麼輕易的放過你的
So she sued him in court.
所以她一狀告到法庭去
The court will now hear the matter of Anna Scott...
本庭現在將開始審理 安娜·史考特...
against Tangiers Corporation and its President Philip Green.
對坦吉樂集團與其總裁 菲立浦·葛林
Oberon on behalf of Mr. Green.
葛林先生將由歐伯倫辯護
Logan on behalf of Anna Scott.
安娜·史考特的律師則是羅根
Mr. Oberon, proceed.
歐伯倫先生 可以開始了
Thank you, Judge.
謝謝 大人
I believe he was fair, and I'm delighted with the decision.
我覺得判決很公正 而我也對判決非常滿意
We got a problem.
有麻煩了
It didn't go too well. Green has to open up the books...
官司結果不理想 葛林得呈交帳簿...
has to show how he got the financing.
他得解釋錢是怎麼來的
That's not good.
這可不好
She was doing pretty good with her lawsuit.
她官司還打得不錯
But before she could start counting her money...
但在鈔票還未落入她口袋之前...
the boys back home decided to settle the case out of court.
老家的老頭子們就已決定庭外和解
So they sent me.
因此他們派我
Can you comment on Anna Scott's murder?
你對安娜·史考特的謀殺有什麼想法嗎?
- What are you talking about?  - She was found last night shot in the head.
- 你在說什麼?  - 她昨晚被人發現中彈身亡
Was this just a real estate partnership?
只是有關房地產合夥問題嗎?
Her lawyer said you were partners.
她的律師說你們是搭擋
We were involved in minor real estate deals many years ago.
我們是在多年前 在一些小房地產交易上合作過
It was never a partnership.
稱不上是搭擋
Did you ever hear of the.22 caliber killer?
你聽過.22口徑殺手嗎?
Now Instead of the cops only looking at Nicky...
現在條子不只是盯尼奇...
they started looking at Green too.
他們也開始盯葛林
And he was supposed to be our squeaky-clean front man.
他本是我們的正派門面
I had to start giving interviews to make sure everybody knew...
我得接受訪問 讓大家都知道...
the casino was on the up-and-up.
賭場沒有牽涉到案子
So how often do you really fill in for him?
你多常幫他代班?
Green's here about two or three times a month...
葛林一個月大約來個兩三次...
and he's busy with other real estate deals and things.
他還有其他房地產交易和別的事要忙
So in Green's absence then you're the boss?
所以葛林不在時 你就是老大囉?
I serve at the pleasure of the Chairman of the Board.
我很榮幸能為董事會的主席服務
My responsibilities are to run the day-to-day operations.
我的責任是管理賭場的日常運作
So day-to-day then you're the boss?
所以平常日子你就是老大?
Well in a sense you could say that I am the boss...
可以這麼說吧...
when Mr. Green is away.
當葛林先生不在時
You could say that.
可以這麼說
山姆·羅斯坦 "我是老大"
Have you read this?
你看了沒?
About Mr. Rothstein.
關於羅斯坦先生
It says, "The Midwest bookmaker with mob ties...
上面說 "與黑道有關連的中西部下注者...
"says that he is the real boss of the $100 million Tangiers casino empire."
說他才是價值一億的坦吉樂賭場真正的老闆"
- Do you believe that?  - Did he really say that?
- 你相信嗎?  - 他真的這麼說?
Why of course he really said that. It's right here.
他當然是這麼說的 這兒不都寫了嗎
Has that man even filed for his license yet?
這傢夥申請執照了沒?
I don't know. We have to check the files.
我不知道 得查查
Without getting your shorts in a knot would you do that?
去查查看吧 用不著太激動
And check closely 'cause we may have to kick a kike's ass out of town.
查仔細點 我們也許能將這死猶太人踢出城了
Thank you.
謝謝
A Gaming Control Board investigation of Tangiers executive...
賭博遊樂委員會開始調查坦吉樂的高層主管...
Sam Rothstein's application for a gaming license is underway.
山姆·羅斯坦的賭博遊樂執照還沒核發下來...
Rothstein who heads the Tangiers casino operation and is a boyhood friend...
羅斯坦負責管理坦吉樂賭場的運作 並也是賭城黑手黨老大...
of Las Vegas mob boss Nicky Santoro...
尼奇·山多羅的兒時好友...
could lose his ability to work in the casino....
他有可能會失去在賭場工作的權力...
Hello?
喂?
I gotta meet Clean Face. What about the Chez Paris?
我得見見清潔工 在小巴黎如何?
我要去你家見見銀行經理 好嗎?
You can't. You gotta make a reservation. It's all booked up.
你得要訂位 一定客滿了
No, no. It's okay. It's impossible.
不用 沒關係 不可能啦
我不要在家見客
You gotta make a reservation. It's difficult to get in.
絕對客滿 而且很難進去
我會從高爾夫球場過來 六點見
It's okay I'll use the service entrance. I'll see you at nine.
沒關係 我走後門 九點見
All right.
好
The battle between state gaming officials and Tangiers casino boss...
州政府賭博遊樂處官員 與坦吉樂高層...
Sam "Ace" Rothstein is heating up.
山姆"艾斯"羅斯坦之戰正如火如荼
Tonight a look at Ace Rothstein's attempt to get state licensing...
今晚 看看艾斯·羅斯坦如何嘗試取得州立執照...
despite law-enforcement allegations of Rothstein's organized crime connections.
雖然面對警方的指控 懷疑羅斯坦與犯罪集團有勾結
Will Sam Rothstein's friendship with organized crime figure Nicky Santoro...
山姆·羅斯坦與黑道人物尼奇·山多羅之間的友誼...
keep Rothstein from running the Tangiers casino?
是否會阻礙羅斯坦管理坦吉樂賭場呢?
And can the integrity of state gaming laws be jeopardized by a boyhood friendship?
而州政府的賭博遊樂法規 是否會因兒時友誼而受到威脅呢?
Why don't you take it easy on that stuff?
你少喝點吧?
Come on. Let me help you down.
來 我扶你下樓
We're talking about some stuff.
我們在談話
At 6:00 will a boyhood friendship...
今晚六點 兒時的友誼是否...
unseat Rothstein as the Tangiers casino boss?
會讓羅斯坦失去坦吉樂老大的位子?
Exclusive on the KBBO special news report.
KBBO獨家專題報導
Go down. Just go downstairs.
下樓去 到樓下去
You can't let this concern you Ace. Don't worry about that stuff.
你不能讓這影響你 艾斯 別管這些了
It's just a political witch hunt.
只是政治圈找替死鬼遊戲
Do you want something to drink?
你要喝什麼嗎?
- Charlie you want a refill?  - Yeah that would be great.
- 查理 你還要嗎?  - 好啊
I don't want nothing. Hi Mr. Clark. I've been trying to reach you.
我什麼都不要 嗨 克拉克先生 我一直在找你
- You're tougher to get than the President.  - I've been busy.
- 你比總統還難找  - 最近比較忙
Yeah? At least you could return my phone calls though.
是嗎? 但你至少也該回我個電話吧
Listen Nicky we talked about this.
聽著 尼奇 我們談過這個
And I explained to you that you might have to take some kind of loss.
我也跟你解釋過 你可能會有虧損
I think I want my money back.
我想把錢拿回來
What are you gonna do strong-arm me?
你是要威脅我嗎?
I think you've gotten the wrong impression about me.
我想你可能誤解我了
I think in all fairness...
我覺得為公平起見...
I should explain to you exactly what it is that I do.
我應該告訴你我打算怎麼做
Tomorrow morning I'll get up nice and early take a walk to the bank...
明天一大早我就會散步去銀行...
and walk in and see and if you don't have my money for me...
走進去看看 若還沒把我的錢準備好的話...
I'll crack your fucking head wide open in front of everybody.
我就會在眾人面前爆開你的頭
And just about the time that I'm coming out of jail...
而當我服完刑出獄時...
hopefully you'll be coming out of your coma.
希望你也能從昏迷中甦醒
And guess what? I'll split your fucking head open again.
知道嗎? 我會再爆開你的頭
'Cause I'm fucking stupid. I don't give a fuck about jail.
因為我是個傻子 我完全不在乎坐牢
That's my business. That's what I do.
這就是我的職業 我會做的事
We know what you do.
我們知道你的職業
You fuck people out of money and get away with it.
你把人的錢騙走 然後大搖大擺的走開
- You can't talk to me like that.  - You fat Irish prick!
- 你不能這樣對我說話  - 你這只愛爾蘭肥豬
You put my money to sleep. Get my money or I'll put your brain to sleep.
你害我領不到我的錢 你最好把它弄出來 不然我要你好看
Never mind Sam. This is personal.
山姆別看 這是我們的事
I'll be there in the morning. You can try me, fatso. You fucking try me.
我明天早上一定到 你試試看啊 肥豬
- You think he got the point?  - What are you doing?
- 你覺得他懂了嗎?  - 你在幹嘛?
He's a square guy for Christ's sakes. He's gonna run to the FBI.
他是個老實的生意人 他會去找聯盟調查局的
That prick's been dodging me for three weeks.
這渾蛋躲了我三個禮拜了
- You're trying to tell me what to do?  - I'm not trying to tell you what to do.
- 你在告訴我該怎麼做嗎?  - 我沒有要告訴你該怎麼做
You're way out of line. Where's your head?
你太過份了 你的腦哪裏去了?
Where's my head? Where's your fucking balls?
我的腦? 你的種又去了哪兒?
I'm trying to put something big together. You know what I'm talking about.
我有更大的計劃 你知道我在說什麼
If you're acting like this now how can I depend on you?
如果你現在就這個樣 我還怎麼指望你啊?
A lot of things gonna change. If you wanna be there with me...
很多事都要改變了 你若要跟我一起...
you're gonna have to go my way.
你就得聽我的
You got to understand my situation. I'm responsible for thousands of people.
你得體諒我的處境 我得對上千名員工負責
I got $100 million a year going through the place.
我每年都得經手一億元
It's all over if I don't get that license.
我若拿不到執照就玩完了
Believe me if it goes bad for me it's gonna go bad for a lot of people.
相信我 我若玩完了 很多人就會跟著完蛋
Forget about your fucking license.
去他媽的什麼爛執照
I plant my own flag out here you ain't gonna need a license.
到時候我說的就是法律 你根本不需要什麼執照
I don't know what it is but the more I talk to you...
我不知道為什麼 但越和你說話...
the more I feel like you just don't want to go along with me.
我越覺得你不會挺我
- No I don't want to come along with you.  - All right.
- 不 我不打算和你一起  - 好
I don't want to be involved in anything you're talking about okay?
我不想涉入你所說的任何事 好嗎?
I want to run a square joint. I just want my license.
我只想好好經營賭場 我只要我的執照
I want everything quiet. That's it!
我只想一切都安靜下來
Quiet like this? "I'm the boss"? That's quiet?
這樣叫安靜? "我是老大" 這樣叫安靜?
It's taken out of context. I had no control.
他們扭曲了意思 我根本控制不了
Ronnie and Billy will tell you exactly what happened.
羅尼與比利可以告訴你整個經過
Back home that looks bad.
這在老家很難看
Looks bad? Every time you're on television I get mentioned. That looks bad.
難看? 每次只要你上電視 就會提到我 這才叫難看
What the fuck happened to you?
你到底怎麼了?
- What happened to you? You lost control?  - I lost control?
- 你怎麼了? 整個失控?  - 我失控?
You're fucking walking around like John Barrymore.
你他媽的像個電影明星似的走來走去
A pink robe and a fucking cigarette holder? I lost control?
穿粉紅色的浴袍還拿煙盒? 是我失控?
I don't wanna bring this up but you treat people with disrespect.
我本來不想提的 但你不尊重人
Even your own wife.
連你老婆都不例外
My wife? What does she have to do with this?
我老婆? 關她什麼事?
She was upset about a lot of things especially that Lester Diamond incident.
她為了許多事不高興 尤其是萊斯特·戴蒙德那檔
You're the shoulder to cry on? Did you tell her about your role in that?
你是她哭訴的對象? 你沒告訴她那事你也有份?
No that's not the fucking point.
沒有 那不是重點
The point is she's upset and you've got a problem.
重點是 她不快樂 你也有問題
I'd appreciate it if you'd stay out of my personal life.
我希望你不要干涉我的私生活
You wouldn't like it if I did it to you.
若我這樣你也會不爽吧
She came to talk to me. Was I supposed to throw her out?
她來找我說話的 我該趕她出去嗎?
Stay away from her. It's none of your business.
離她遠一點 不關你的事
A week ago it was. Now it's not. When you need me you need me.
一周前就是我的事 現在就不是 你需要我時 我就得到
Right the way you need me to vouch for you as a citizen.
是啊 就像你需要我幫你做擔保一樣
I'm gonna have to straighten out what you did with this guy.
我得去解決你剛剛對那人所做的事情
This guy's gonna run to the FBl.
他會去找聯邦調查局的
Your head's bigger than your casino. That's your problem.
你的自尊比你的賭場還大 這就是你的問題
I knew what he wanted and I didn't want any part of it. He wanted to take over.
我知道他想做什麼 但我不想參與 尼奇想自個兒當老大
He wanted to go after Gaggi the skim everything and everybody.
他想幹掉蓋吉 抽頭 還有一切
He also stopped asking permission from back home for every little thing.
他不再每件小事都要老家批准
A casino boss and his wife were killed. The bulls questioned Nicky.
一位賭場大亨與他老婆被殺了 調查員偵問了尼奇
A dealer from the Scirocco. They questioned Nicky.
一位西洛可的莊家 他們也詢問尼奇
Stool pigeons wound up in the trunks of their cars. They questioned Nicky.
幾個線民死在自己的後車箱裏 他們也追問尼奇
A lawyer.
一個律師
They questioned Nicky.
他們問尼奇
When some guys who didn't pay their shylocks began disappearing...
當一些拖欠高利貸的人 莫名的開始消失...
Nicky's name was in every newspaper.
尼奇的名字佈滿每家報紙
Nicky was questioned in two dozen murders but they always had to let him go.
尼奇因為一堆謀殺案調查被偵訊 但他們每次都放他走
There were never any witnesses.
從來沒有目擊者
The coppers blamed me for everything that went wrong.
條子把所有的不順 都歸昝於我
Watch yourself. You're gonna get runned over.
小心點 你會好看的
If a guy tripped over a banana peel they'd bring me in for it.
若有個傢夥踩到香蕉皮跌倒 可能都要帶我回局裏
Be nice.
客氣點
The bosses were no better. They complained because things don't run smooth.
老大們也沒好到哪兒去 他們抱怨事情運作不順
In my line of work things don't run so smooth. I'm sorry.
不過在我這行 真抱歉 事情本來就不會順
I'm dealing with degenerate animals out here.
我每天對付的可是些三教九流之徒
The bosses what do they give a fuck?
老大們在乎個屁啊?
They're sitting on their asses drinking anisette.
他們只會坐著喝酒
Meanwhile I'm the guy in the trenches.
而這期間我得做牛做馬
Fucking bosses think it's a fucking free lunch out here.
那些王八老大們 真以為天下的午餐都是免費的
Frankie, they found a guy's head in the desert.
法蘭克 他們在沙漠裏找到一個傢夥的頭
You know about that?
你知道嗎?
I heard.
聽說了
Everybody's talking about it and making a big deal out of it. It's in all the papers.
大家都在講 報紙裏也有登
What are you gonna do?
你要怎麼辦?
That's no good.
這可不好
Tell him to take care of things a little better.
叫他做事要小心點
I'll tell him Remo.
我會的 利蒙
Fucking bosses smoking their Di Nobilis...
王八老大們抽著雪茄
and eating trip' and fucking soffrit' fried pigs' guts...
吃著他們的美食...
while if I wanna talk private I gotta go to a fucking bus stop.
而我若想私下找人談話 我還得坐在公車站
- What do they care? Long as I send money.  - They're complaining.
- 他們在乎個屁? 只要我拿錢回去  - 他們在抱怨了
Let them complain. I'm the one who's here. I do all the work.
讓他們抱怨 是我在這兒 活都是我在做
- Somebody don't like it fuck them.  - It's up to you.
- 有人不喜歡 就去他的  - 你決定咯
They want a fucking war? I'm ready.
他們他媽的想打仗? 我準備好了
If I take care of five of those guys the rest will fall into place.
我只要幹掉那五個 其他的自然會水到渠成
Peek-a-boo you fucks you.
被我抓到了吧 這群王八羔子
I see you you motherfuckers.
我看到你們了 渾蛋
Nicky was not only bringing heat on himself but on me too.
問題是 尼奇不只是讓自己更受注目 還連累到我
The FBI watched every move he made but he just didn't care.
聯邦調查局盯著他的每一步 但他不在乎
If they're gonna watch me I'm gonna watch them back.
想要盯我 我就盯回去
I spent a few bucks. Top dollar. Who gives a shit?
或許花了很多錢 但誰在乎?
I got the latest anti-bugging equipment from the same places that sell to the CIA.
我買了最先進的反竊聽裝置 向賣給中央調查局的那家買的
I had all the special police frequency radios
我有所有的員警特殊頻道對講機
FBI de-scramblers night-vision cameras...
FBI的解幹擾器 夜光照相機...
So the miserable sons of bitches never caught me doing anything I couldn't handle.
這些衰角從未抓到我任何把柄
I got my job on the line he's having the time of his life.
我工作都快丟了 但他卻玩得不亦樂乎
He has every cop in the state watching him and he's out playing golf.
全州的員警都在盯他 他卻在打高爾夫球
And at the worst possible time for me.
對我來說時期最壞不過
I had my license hearing coming up and I didn't want to leave anything to chance.
我的執照聽證會要到了 我不想有一點點失敗的機率
If I can't work in Vegas where am I gonna go?
若不能在賭城工作 那我要去哪兒?
You've been very open with us with the books and papers.
你一直都很合作 從檔到帳簿
That'll mean a lot when you go before the commission.
這對委員會是很重要的
- All I ask is a fair hearing.  - This honesty will guarantee it.
- 我只希望能有個公正的聽證會  - 你的誠實會為你贏的
We'll move on to....
接下來...
I want to hear about Kansas City.
我想聽聽關於堪薩斯市
What the fuck is this?
這他媽的是什麼?
Where's this fucking guy gonna land in the fairway?
這傢夥要停在哪裏 球場上嗎?
They're fucking agents Frankie. Look at this.
他們是探員 法蘭克 來看看
The Feds were watching Nicky play golf for so long...
他們盯尼奇打高爾夫盯到...
they ran out of gas.
飛機沒油
Just what I needed right in front of the control board.
還真是我需要的 就在委員會面前
$100 whoever hits the plane.
賭一百看誰先打到飛機
If things weren't bad enough... in comes Piscano the Kansas City underboss.
禍不單行 隨後就看到派斯康 堪薩斯市的老二
He ran the grocery store in Kansas City where they brought the suitcases.
在堪薩斯市收皮箱的那家超市 就是他開的
Fighting over those suitcases again. You know what that means?
又在為皮箱的事吵了 你知道這代表什麼嗎?
I gotta take another trip to Vegas. It's gonna cost me another couple grand.
我又得去拉斯維加斯了 又要花我好幾千
He ran it with his brother-in-law...
他和他姐夫一起開店...
but he mostly complained about his trips to Vegas to his brother-in-law and mother.
但他大多都在跟他姐夫與岳母 抱怨他去賭城的事
You gotta lay down the law or they'll make a fool out of you.
你得表明態度 要不然他們當你是病貓
I write it all down. Every fucking nickel goes down.
我全記下來了 他媽的每一分一毛
- What's the matter with you?  - Everything's here.
- 你是怎麼了?  - 全都在這兒
- Since when do you talk like that?  - I'm sorry.
- 你何時開始這樣講話?  - 抱歉
Nance gives me trouble I'll take the eyes out of his freaking head.
南斯要是找我麻煩 我就將他的眼挖出來
- Again.  - I didn't curse I said "freaking head."
- 又來了  - 我沒罵粗話
- That's enough.  - I'm sorry.
- 夠了  - 抱歉
What happens next you can't believe it.
接下來發生的事 簡直是出乎意料
Who'd believe the FBI had a wire in the place...
誰會想到聯邦調查局會在裏面裝竊聽器...
looking for information about some old homicide...
為了調查很久以前的一樁命案...
about some guy who was whacked out God knows when over God knows what?
為了一個不知在何時 也不知為何事被幹掉的人
What prevents him with the suitcases from taking what he wants?
你怎麼阻止拿皮箱的人 拿走他想要的?
Nance brings back two suitcases from the Tangiers. What about three or four?
南斯從坦吉樂拿了兩口箱子回來 若其實有三箱或四箱呢?
We've got nobody in the room to watch. That's the law.
我們沒有人在計算室裏看著 那是法律
We can't even go into the count room to watch our money.
我們甚至連計算室都進不去
He's got his people in there. They could all be in on it together.
他有他的人在裏面 他們搞不好根本是一夥的
I'll find out. If it's Green himself I'll bury that bastard.
若我知道是葛林幹的 我會埋了那王八蛋
I never trusted him. I got eyes behind my head.
我從就不相信他 我後腦都有眼睛
They trust that scumbag. I don't.
他們信任那渾蛋 我可不
I'll hit the two of them in the head with a shovel.
我該給他們一人一鏟
Take it easy.
冷靜點
Ma I'm sorry. They're beating me left and right.
媽 抱歉 但他們一直跟我玩陰的
- I'm sorry. I'm upset.  - I know but that's enough.
- 抱歉 我很生氣  - 我知道 可是夠了
You know what they're doing to me. I can't take this no more.
你也知道他們在對我做什麼 我受不了了
- Take it easy. You'll get a heart attack.  - I know. I'm too upset.
- 冷靜 別心臟病發  - 我知道 我太氣了
The damn thing is they hear all this stuff...
該死的是 他們聽得一清二楚...
about Las Vegas casinos and suitcases...
關於拉斯維加斯賭場還有皮箱...
and that's it.
玩完了
Everything's coming out of my pocket. I gotta pay.
全都是從我口袋裏掏 我得付錢
Would you believe this could happen?
你相信有這麼巧嗎?
華盛頓
I'm in this to make money not lose it.
我是來賺錢的 不是虧錢
Every FBI man across the country had their ears open now.
全國每個聯邦調查局探員都張大了耳朵
If you want something done right you gotta do it yourself.
要將事情辦好就得靠自己
Piscano this guy basically sunk the whole world.
派司康這傢夥 幾乎搞砸了所有人的生活
There are some that are good and some that are bad.
有些好的就有些壞的
Members of the Commission...
主席先生 委員會的同仁...
Mr. Rothstein is pleased to be here today.
今天羅斯坦先生很榮幸能在這兒
When the day finally came I was ready.
當那天終於來時 我已準備好了
I felt so confident that all I had to do was present my case.
我自信滿滿的認為 我只需要呈上我的案件
We have documents one of which is a report by retired FBl agents...
我們擁有檔 其中一份是由一位退休的聯邦探員寫的...
which completely absolves Mr. Rothstein from any wrongdoing.
上頭清楚的記載羅斯坦先生 並未觸犯任何法律
- Counselor before you continue...  - I want to have this marked....
- 律師 在你繼續前...  - 我要將這呈為...
this Commission acts on a motion denying the Rothstein application.
本委員會針對是否應 駁回羅斯坦的申請書在此動議
- Denying?  - Do I hear a motion seconded?
- 駁回?  - 有人讚成駁回嗎?
Mr. Chairman I second the motion.
主席先生 我贊成
Do I have a vote on the motion?
還有贊同票嗎?
- Aye!  - Aye!
同意
The ayes have it. This hearing is adjourned.
同意票獲勝 聽證會結束
- You have to be kidding.  - Adjourned? What do you mean?
- 開什麼玩笑  - 什麼叫結束?
Senator, you promised me a hearing. You didn't even look at the FBl reports.
議員 你答應我一場聽證會的 你連聯邦調查局的報告都沒看
When you were my guest at the Tangiers Hotel didn't you promise me a fair hearing?
你來坦吉樂作客時 不是答應我會有公平的聽證會?
- I was never your guest.  - Never my guest? I never comped you?
- 我從未是你的客人  - 不是我的客人? 我沒招待過你?
I don't comp you at least three times a month?
難道我一個月沒有最少招待你三次?
I'd like to answer that at this time.
我現在回答這個問題
Mr. Rothstein is being very typical to this point. He's lying.
羅斯坦先生的反應很常見 他在撒謊
The only time I was at the Tangiers was a dinner with Barney Greenstein.
我唯一一次去過坦吉樂就是巴尼·葛林斯坦那次晚宴
- Was I at the dinner?  - You were wandering around.
- 我當時在場嗎?  - 你四處周旋著
- Was I at that dinner?  - You were wandering.
- 我在場嗎?  - 你四處周旋
- You were in the building.  - I was in the building?
- 你在室內  - 我在室內?
You know damn well I was there. You swore I would have a fair hearing.
你很清楚我在那兒 你向我保證會有公正的聽證會
Did you not?
沒有嗎?
Tell me I was at least at the dinner. Allow me that much.
至少承認說我那天在場 這總可以了吧
- Give me that much at least!  - Yes you were.
- 至少也得說我在場吧  - 是 你在
Thanks for not calling me a liar you son of a bitch.
多謝你沒說我是騙子 你這個狗東西
A routine licensing hearing turned into bedlam yesterday...
一場例行的聽證會 在昨晚成了一場鬧劇...
when the flamboyant Tangiers Casino executive Sam "Ace" Rothstein...
當搶眼的坦吉樂高層 山姆"艾斯"羅斯坦...
accused top gaming officials of corruption.
指控賭博遊樂委員會高官貪汙
promised me a fair hearing when you were comped at my hotel?
你在我的旅館接受招待 並答應我會有公平的聽證會
And you asked for copies of your bill to put on your expense account.
你還要求將你的帳單掛公帳
In a wild outburst that followed his gaming license denial...
當賭博遊樂執照被駁回時大吼大叫...
- Bullshit!  - ...Rothstein followed several...
- 狗屁  - 羅斯坦與好幾名...
stunned commissioners into the hallway where he continued his harangue...
錯愕的委員到走道 並持續著他的指控...
until his own lawyers and friends urged him to leave.
直到他的律師與朋友勸他離開
You have a past. I have a past. My past is no worse than yours.
你有過去 我也有過去 我的不見得比你的糟糕
You guys think you have the right to pass judgment!
你們還自以為有權去判決別人
Long suspected of running Tangiers without a license...
被懷疑長期無照管理坦吉樂...
yesterday's hearing was to determine if someone with Rothstein's history...
昨天的聽證會本是要決議 像羅斯坦如此背景的人...
was qualified to officially hold a top gaming post.
是否有資格正式在賭博遊樂界 擔任如此高的職位
Fucking hypocrites!
王八偽君子
羅斯坦玩完了
- What the hell's he gonna do now?  - I don't know.
- 他現在怎麼辦?  - 我不知道
What's he doing?
他在幹嘛?
He knows all those guys he yelled at are friends of ours.
他也知道他大吼大叫的那群人 都是我們的朋友
What's the matter with him making all this mess?
他是怎麼了 搞得一團糟?
Maybe he could run things with another job title.
他或許可以用另一個頭銜管事
Won't be the best but what are we gonna do?
這不是最好的 但我們又能如何呢?
However he runs things it's gotta be quiet. Let him hide upstairs in the office.
他不論管什麼 都得安靜點 讓他躲到樓上辦公室去
Say he's a janitor. I don't give a shit.
說他是工友 我不在乎
But please whatever job he takes make sure it's something quiet.
但拜託 不管他做什麼 都得低調點
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位先生與女士...
the Tangiers Hotel proudly presents the all-new...
坦吉樂大飯店 非常榮幸能為您介紹...
Sam Rothstein show Aces High.
山姆·羅斯坦秀 《艾斯的單人牌》
Tonight, taped live from the all-new sports book,...
今晚 從最新的球賽賭區 現場實況轉播...
we present the premiere showing of Aces High,...
我們為您帶來《艾斯的單人牌》的首次演出...
with the Sasha Semenoff Orchestra...
連同莎夏西門諾夫交響樂團...
and the Sam Rothstein dancers!
與山姆·羅斯坦舞群
Mr. Rothstein is a professional gambler and the best U.S. football handicapper.
羅斯坦先生是位職業賭徒 也是全美最棒的美式足球下注者
A man who will take you inside the real Las Vegas as no one has ever done before.
一位能帶領你進入真正的拉斯維加斯的人
Now, ladies and gentlemen, the new entertainment director of the Tangiers Hotel...
現在讓我們歡迎 坦吉樂賭場新的娛樂董事...
Mr. Sam Rothstein.
山姆·羅斯坦先生
Welcome to the Sam Rothstein show. We're happy to have you here this evening.
歡迎來到山姆·羅斯坦秀 很高興你們能參與
The young lady to my left is Trudy...
我左邊的這位小姐是特茹蒂...
who is a lead new dancer in our fabulous show from Paris.
她是我們巴黎秀新的首席舞者
Our first guest this evening...
我們今晚的第一位來寶...
is Frankie Avalon.
法蘭克·艾華倫
- Keep an eye on him.  - I've got a large family.
- 看好他  - 我有個大家庭
- How many kids do you have?  - I'm very proud to say eight children.
- 你有幾個孩子?  - 我很自豪的說 八個
- That's amazing.  - There's nothing to it. It was my pleasure.
- 太了不起了  - 沒什麼 是我的榮幸
Ace don't do it.
別這樣
Jesus.
天啊
He's juggling!
他在耍雜技
Let's not take County Commissioner Pat Webb too seriously.
我們別對縣輔導派特·委布太認真
I recently challenged him to a debate on this program and he declined.
我最近本想邀他在節目上辯論的 但是他拒絕了
What are you worried about Pat? You don't have to send me any questions.
你在擔心什麼呢 派特? 你不需要事先給我問題
You can ask me anything you want.
你什麼都可以問我
What the hell is he doing on television?
他在電視上幹嘛?
He's on all night screaming about taking his lawsuit to the Supreme Court.
他整晚都在上面 喊著要將他的案子告上最高法院
He really must be crazy. He's gonna go to Washington with this?
他真是瘋了 他想將這帶到華府去?
He's out of his fucking mind.
他簡直是瘋了
It's a pity we have such hypocrisy. Some people do what they want.
世上有這樣的偽君子真是可嘆 他們愛做什麼就做什麼
Other people have to pay through the nose. Such is life.
其他人卻得承擔後果 這就是人生
Andy go see him. Tell him maybe it's time he should quit.
安迪 去找他 告訴他辭職的時候到了
First, what they did was totally unconstitutional.
第一點 他們的所做所為 完全的違反了憲法
We're on the list to be heard before the U.S. Supreme Court.
我們已在高等法院的等候單上了
These guys don't care about the Supreme Court.
這些傢夥才不在乎高等法院
They want things to quiet down. They want you to walk away.
他們要一切平息 要你別再搞了
Walk away? Andy you can't be serious. Don't you see what's at stake?
別搞了? 安迪 你不是說真的 你難道看不到這嚴重性嗎?
The old man said maybe your friend should give in.
老頭說你的朋友或許該罷手了
When the old man says "maybe " that's like a papal bull.
當老頭說"或許"時 就像是教皇發諭令一樣
Not only should you quit you should run.
你不但該罷手 還該跑路
Every time they mention my name in the papers they mention Nicky too.
他們每次在報上提到我的名字 就一定扯到尼奇
How the fuck does that help?
這他媽的有什麼幫助?
The heat he brought down is murder.
他帶來的注目簡直是謀殺
The police department was cooperative.
警察局本來很合作
They're pissed off. Nobody can make a move anymore.
他將他們激怒到 現在大家都動不了
What do you do about that?
你能怎樣呢?
- What are you proposing?  - I don't know. He doesn't listen to me.
- 你想說什麼?  - 我不知道 他根本不聽我的
Maybe he should get lost for a while. Would that be so bad?
或許他才該消失一陣子 這樣會很糟嗎?
- They ain't sending Nicky nowhere.  - If he took a break...
- 他們不會調走尼奇的  - 若他離開一陣...
it would give everybody time to maneuver.
給大家移動佈局的機會
I would forget about the maneuver. I would just get out.
別再搞佈局的事 趕緊離開吧
I can't do that.
我不能
Of course as soon as Andy got home Nicky heard about our talk in the car.
當然 安迪一到家後 尼奇就聽說我們的談話
Next morning bright and early I get the call.
第二天一大早 我就接到電話
I've got to do some shopping. Want to go?
我得去買點東西 你要不要去?
Getting a call from Nicky wasn't easy anymore.
連接尼奇的電話都不是件易事
Even the codes didn't work. So we figured out another act.
暗號都沒有用了 我們得想新方法
If a phone's tapped the Feds can only listen in on the stuff involving crimes.
若是電話被竊聽 他們只能聽關於犯罪的談話
On routine calls they have to click off after a few minutes.
例行通話時 他們必須在幾分鐘後掛斷
I got a sprained fucking elbow.
我手肘好像扭到了
Meet me at 3:00.
三點見
- At Caesar's?  - 100 yards further down the road.
- 在凱撒宮嗎?  - 這條路下去再一百碼處
- Why?  - Don't ask questions. Just be there.
- 為什麼?  - 別問了 到那兒就是了
Suzy Cream Cheese has the same outfit.
蘇西克理姆有件一模一樣的衣服
I saw something.
我看到個東西
Something very cute.
這東西好可愛
Okay he's out. It's the ant. Brown unit.
他出門了 棕組
He's with the bogey. I think it's Frankie.
他帶著個替身 應該是法蘭克
Nicky started out before me...
尼奇比我早出門...
because it wasn't that easy for him to get around anymore.
因為他要出門越來越難了
Nicky couldn't even go for a ride without changing cars...
尼奇到那兒都最起碼得...
at least six times before he could shake all his tails.
換六次車才甩得掉跟蹤他的人
Because of the planes he had to use underground garages.
因為有飛機 所以他得用地下停車場
Meeting in the desert always made me nervous.
在沙漠中央會面總讓我緊張
It's a scary place.
那是個可怕的地方
I knew about the holes in the desert of course.
我當然也知道沙漠裏的洞
And everywhere I looked there could have been a hole.
我張望的每一處都可能是個洞
Normally my prospects of coming back alive...
通常我與尼奇會面 能活著回來...
from a meeting with Nicky were 99 out of 100.
機率是百分之九十九
But this time when I heard him say a couple of hundred yards down the road...
但這次 當我聽他說 離道路幾百碼外...
I gave myself 50-50.
我想應該還有一半的機率吧
Where the fuck you get off talking to people behind my back?
你他媽的跟別人 在背後捅我是什麼意思?
- What people?  - Did you think I wouldn't find out?
- 跟什麼人?  - 你以為我不會發現嗎?
I don't even know what you're talking about.
我根本不知道你在說什麼
You said I'm bringing heat on you? I gotta listen to people because of you?
你說我害你被盯? 我得因為你被人家念?
You're ordering me out? You better get your own fucking army!
你想搞走我? 你最好準備好自己的軍隊?
I didn't order you or anybody.
我沒有要搞走任何人
I told Andy Stone that you had heat and that was a problem.
我跟安迪說你被盯上了 這是個問題
You want me to get out of my own fucking town?
你想要我離開我自己的地盤?
Yeah let the bullshit blow over so I can run the casino.
是啊 我說等風頭過了 我才能好好經營賭場
Anything goes wrong with the casino it's my ass not yours.
賭場出了什麼事我得負責 不是你
You know that you only have your fucking casino because I made that possible!
你知道你之所以能管那狗屁賭場 都是因為我
I'm what counts out here.
在這兒我才算數
Not your fucking country clubs or your fucking TV shows.
不是你他媽的什麼俱樂部 也不是你那狗屁電視秀
And what the fuck are you doing on TV anyhow?
你他媽的在電視上幹嘛?
I get calls from back home every day. They think you went batshit!
我每天都得接老家的電話 他們都覺得你瘋了
I'm only on TV because I gotta be able to hang around the casino.
我上電視是因為 我必須待在賭場
You don't understand that....
你不懂的
You could've had the food-and-beverage job without going on TV!
你不上電視也可以拿那餐飲的頭銜
- You wanted to go on TV.  - Yeah I wanted to go on TV.
- 是你想上電視吧  - 對 我想上電視
That way I have a forum. I can fight back. I'm known. People see me
這樣我才有擂臺 我才可以反擊 我要有知名度
They know they can't fuck around with me, like they could if I was an unknown.
若我有知名度他們就不能隨隨便便打發我
You're making a spectacle of yourself.
你將自己變成個笑話
I wouldn't even be in this situation if it wasn't for you.
要不是你 我也不會落到這步田地
You brought down so much heat on me.
你讓我被盯上
Every time I meet somebody they ask me if I know you.
我每次遇見個人 他們都只想知道我認不認識你
Sure now you wanna blame your fucking license on me.
所以你現在要將你執照的那件事怪到我的頭上
When you asked me if you could come out here...
當你請示我你可不可以來這兒時...
what did I tell you? I knew you'd come out no matter what I said. Do you remember?
我是怎麼說的? 我就知道 不管我說什麼你都會來 記得嗎?
Back up a fucking minute here. One minute.
等一下 倒退一下
I asked you? When the fuck did I ever ask you if I could come out here?
我請示你? 我他媽的什麼時候請示過你我可不可以來這兒?
Get this through your head you Jew motherfucker!
搞清楚點 死猶太人
You only exist out here because of me! That's the only reason!
你是因我才在這兒 只因為這樣
Without me you personally....
要沒有我 你自己...
Every fucking wise guy still around will take a piece of your fucking Jew ass!
在這兒隨便哪個還在混的 都可能宰了你
Then where you gonna go? You're fucking warned.
到時你怎麼辦? 我警告你了
Don't go over my fucking head again you motherfucker you!
別想再踩在我頭上 你這個王八蛋
Well we got company.
有客人
Did you see that?
看到了嗎?
Dumb Jew motherfucker. Grew up together and he acts like he doesn't know me.
蠢猶太人 我們一起長大的 他竟裝作不認識我
I know we're supposed to avoid each other but there's ways to do things.
我知道我們應該避免碰面 不過應該有其他辦法吧
Fuck him.
去他的
To Abraham Lincoln.
敬林肯總統
Forget about it. Don't let it bother you.
算了 別讓這煩你
Does it look like it's bothering me? Why do I give a fuck?
我看來很煩躁嗎? 我為什麼要在乎?
Oscar too. All the money I gave him that prick.
奧斯卡也是的 我給了他那麼多錢 渾蛋
He didn't even look over. What's his fucking problem?
他連看都不看這邊 他到底是什麼毛病?
- Fucking Jews stick together don't they?  - They're having a good time.
- 死猶太人都是一夥的 不是嗎?  - 他們好像玩得很快樂
So are we.
我們也是啊
Yeah?
喂?
- Sam we got a problem.  - What is it?
- 山姆 有麻煩  - 怎麼了?
The little guy. Nobody told him he was eighty-sixed from the joint.
那矮子 沒人跟他說 他被禁止進入賭場
We turned our heads and made out like we didn't know who he was.
我們只要都假裝不認識他
He's over at the 21 table with his nose wide open.
他現在在21點桌大剌剌的豪賭
He took money out of his own kick. His nose is open for about $10,000.
他從他那份抽頭裏拿錢 已經輸了一萬了
Now he's really pissed.
現在他很生氣
- He wants a $50,000 marker.  - Just give him $10,000.
- 他要五萬的籌碼  - 給他一萬就好了
That's it. I'll be right down.
就這樣 我馬上來
He's gonna come up with $10,000 just the way you want.
就如你所要求 他會去拿一萬
No I said fucking $50,000!
不 我他媽的說五萬
Go get it. I don't give a fuck where you get it.
給我去拿 我不在乎你用什麼方法
Fuckers. They take it but don't wanna give it back.
王八蛋 只會拿錢卻不還來
How the fuck can you grin?
你還笑得出來?
You know how much I'm stuck? Do you give a fuck?
你知道我輸多少了嗎? 你在乎嗎?
Give yourself a hand right across your fucking mouth.
給自己點掌聲吧 順便加一巴掌
Look at this beaut they put in now.
看看現在上來的這個怪胎
Sherbert send you in here to rob me now?
雪伯提派你來搶我的嗎?
Been fucking knocking everybody's dick in all night? Been beating the customers?
你今晚屌了很久了吧? 贏很多喔?
Jag-off. Hit me.
再來一張
Take this stiff and pound it up your fucking ass.
將這張牌從你後面塞進去
Hit me again.
再來一張
Take this one and stick it up your sister's ass. Hit me again.
這張捅你姐姐後面去 再來一張
Keep looking at him. If you had any heart at all you'd be stealing for a living.
一直看他幹嘛 你要還有良心 你就寧可去當小偷
Hit me again! What the fuck you keep looking at him for?
再給我一張 你他媽的一直看他幹嘛?
You fucking.... Look at this 20 points in a row. Hit me again.
你這 你看看 連二十張公 再來一張
You should pay as fast as you collect you know.
你給錢應該跟拿錢一樣快吧
- You gotta get out of here.  - Tell this motherfucker to pay that marker.
- 你得走了  - 叫那王八蛋付籌碼
You're not listening. I'm here to help you. You're gonna bury us both.
你沒在聽 我是來幫你的 你會將我們倆都毀了
- Just give me the money.  - I'm gonna okay you $10,000 that's it.
- 把錢給我  - 我只批准一萬 就這樣
Then you gotta get out before the cops are all over you.
然後你得在條子找到你之前給我走
$10,000 and that's it.
就一萬
What are you staring at you bald-headed Jew prick?
你在看什麼? 你這禿頭的死猶太人
- Come on. Let's get out of here.  - Sue me you Jew fuck!
- 快 我們快走  - 告我啊 死猶太人
Get out of here? I got a marker coming. Deal.
走? 我有籌碼要來耶 發牌
I know but everything's changed now. You're talking about a divorce.
我知道 但現在情況不同了 你要求的是離婚
You're asking for alimony payments and child support and now custody.
你要求你與孩子的贍養費 現在又要孩子的監護權
I just want what any divorced woman would get.
我只要任何一個離婚女人想要的
She's only sober about two hours a day.
她一天不過清醒兩個小時
It's usually from 11:00 a.m. to 1:00 p.m.
通常是早上十一點到下午一點
If I gave her her money and her jewels she's gonna piss it all away in a year.
我要是給她錢與珠寶 她一年內就會浪費光了
Where would you be then? Coming right back to me...
到時你怎麼辦? 還不是又回來找我...
or finding some other excuse to come....
或找什麼其他的理由回來...
We had a deal. Remember that?
我們有協議 記得嗎?
He said if it didn't work out between us I could get my things and leave.
他說過若我們之間走不下去 我可以拿我的東西走
Look in my eyes.
看著我
You know me.
你知道我
Do you see anything that makes you think I would ever let...
你看到任何跡象 讓你覺得...
someone in your condition take my child away from me?
以你現在的狀況 我會將我的孩子交給你?
Do you?
有嗎?
You know that won't happen.
你知道這不可能
And after all this time...
過了這麼久...
and as hard as I tried as much as I wanted...
不管我多麼努力 多麼想...
I could never reach her.
我始終觸碰不到她
I could never make her love me.
我無法讓她愛我
I always felt she should have gone for all that money...
我總覺得她會愛我 那麼多的錢...
being somebody, for the first time in her life, a home, a kid.
第一次在生命中成為一個重要的人 一個家 孩子
That's not what happened. It didn't work out that way.
但事實並非如此 那樣做卻行不通
- Everything all right?  - What could we do?
- 都好嗎?  - 我們能怎麼辦?
After a while we'd just take breathers from each other. Little separations.
過一陣子後 我們開始放對方的假 短期的不見面
At that time, I remember Ginger took Amy and went to Beverly Hills.
那時 我記得金吉兒帶著艾美去比佛利山莊
She was gonna spend a week shopping.
她要去逛一個禮拜的街
- Yes Mr. Rothstein.  - The Beverly Hotel in Beverly Hills.
- 是的 羅斯坦先生  - 比佛利大飯店
- Hello Beverly Hotel.  - Mrs. Rothstein, please.
- 你好 比佛利大飯店  - 請找山姆·羅斯坦夫人
Sorry, Mr. and Mrs. Rothstein have checked out already.
很抱歉 羅斯坦先生與夫人已經退房了
Mr. and Mrs. Rothstein?
羅斯坦先生與夫人?
- Yes they both checked out.  - Thank you.
- 是的 他們倆都退房了  - 謝謝
Hello.
喂
My wife is with an old friend of hers in L.A.
我老婆跟她一個老朋友在洛杉磯
Some lowlife named Lester Diamond.
一個叫萊斯特·戴蒙德的敗類
My daughter's with them. They're gonna try and kidnap her.
我女兒跟他們在一起 他們會試著綁架她
- Is there anybody you can send?  - We'll take care of it.
- 你那邊有人嗎?  - 我們會幫你搞定
We got a number and an address.
查到電話號碼與住址了
Hello. Is this Lester?
喂 是萊斯特嗎?
Who's calling?
哪位?
This is Sam Rothstein. I want to talk to Ginger.
我是山姆·羅斯坦 我要跟金吉兒講話
She's not here Sam.
她不在這兒 山姆
Listen to me very carefully. I want to talk to Ginger.
你給我聽好 我要跟金吉兒說話
I want my kid back. I want her put on a plane immediately.
我要我的孩子 我要她馬上搭下班飛機回來
- I know she's there. Don't fuck around.  - I wouldn't.
- 我知道她在 別玩把戲  - 山姆 我沒有
You shouldn't do this.
你不應這麼做
You understand? Put her on the fucking phone.
你懂不懂? 叫她聽電話
Sam I don't know where she is.
山姆 我不知道她在哪兒
So listen can I call you back in a few minutes?
聽著 我可以待會兒打給你嗎?
702-472-1862
- I'll call back.  - Right away.
- 我馬上回你  - 馬上
- Right back.  - You got it.
- 馬上  - 好的
Schmuck. All right, I just bought us a few minutes.
白癡 好了 我多拖了一些時間
You want to get back at this prick?
你想報復嗎?
You got what $2 million in that box?
那保險箱裏有兩百萬對吧?
You got a minute? He's got $2 million in the box right?
喂 耽誤你一下? 他保險箱裏有兩百萬對吧?
You let him keep your jewels. We take the cash...
珠寶就留給他 我們拿走現金...
and the only other thing he cares about. Her majesty.
與他唯一在乎的另一件東西 他的小公主
We go to Europe. You dye your hair.
我們去歐洲 你把頭髮染了
I don't want to go to Europe. I want to go to see The Elephant Man.
我不要去歐洲 我要去看《像人》
1980年 約翰·赫特主演的電影
We're going to Europe. Let the adults talk. You dye your hair.
我們要去歐洲 讓大人講話 你去染頭髮
You get plastic surgery like we talked about.
像我們所說的去整容
How much you think he'll pay to get this kid back?
你覺得他會願意付多少贖金?
- I don't want to go to Europe.  - Shut your mouth.
- 我不要去歐洲  - 你給我閉嘴
- You shut up.  - Want me to come over?
- 你才閉嘴  - 你要我過來?
I'll smack your face. Don't give me your shit!
我一巴掌打死你 別找我麻煩
This has always been a dream but now we're going.
這本來是個夢 但現在要實現了
- Lester he called you here.  - Right. Ace was on the phone.
- 萊斯特 他打到這兒來  - 他剛在電話上
- I just talked to him.  - So he knows where you are.
- 我剛跟他講完  - 所以他知道你在哪兒
That means he's sending some guys over here now.
這表示他現在就派人過來了
It means he's sitting by the phone like a dumbbell....
這表示他在電話旁像個蠢蛋...
Yeah he's sitting by the phone waiting for you to call him back!
對 他就像是蠢蛋坐在電話旁等你打給他
What are we gonna do? He's probably got guys outside the fucking house!
我們該怎麼辦? 他可能已經派人在門外守著了
- It's this fucking bullshit of yours!  - Get your bag! Let's go!
- 又是你在那兒鬼扯  - 快拿行李 快走
- What bullshit? You want to talk it over?  - Are you done yakking?
- 什麼鬼扯? 你想現在討論這嗎?  - 你嘮叨完了沒?
Go! Get in the car!
快 快上車
Just relax. Nobody's killing anybody.
冷靜點 沒人要被殺
- I think he's gonna kill me.  - Relax.
- 他一定會殺了我  - 冷靜點
Call me back here in exactly an hour on this phone. I'll see what I can do.
一個小時後打這支電話給我 我想想辦法
I'll call you back in an hour at this number...
我一個小時後打給你...
- and you'll be there right?  - I'll be here.
- 你會接對不對?  - 我會在
Listen don't do anything else crazy. You all right?
聽著 別再做什麼蠢事了 你還好嗎?
Okay bye.
好 再見
- Knock it off.  - She started it.
- 停止  - 是她開始的
She started the whole thing.
都是她開始的
- Don't even think you're gonna drive.  - I'm gonna drive.
- 你別想開車  - 我來開
- I'm not gonna drive with a crazy woman.  - You're driving me nuts!
- 我可不想坐瘋婆子開的車  - 你快把我搞瘋了
Get on the passenger side! I'm sending this kid to Bolivia in a box!
滾到旁邊去 我要將這小鬼裝箱寄到玻利維亞去
Can we....
我們能不能...
Ginger called me.
金吉兒打給我
- I just told you she called me.  - What'd she want?
- 我說她打給我  - 她想怎樣?
She was afraid to call you.
她不敢打給你
She's with that cocksucker again. They got Amy.
她又跟那敗類在一起了 艾美在他們手上
She wants to come back but she's afraid you're gonna whack her out.
她想回來 可是她害怕你會殺了她
They're gonna kidnap my kid. What do you want?
他們想綁架我的孩子 你覺得我會怎樣?
I know. Why didn't you come to me? This is family. It ain't business.
我知道 你怎麼不來找我? 這是家務事 不是公事
You make calls back home. It makes us look bad out here. You know what I mean?
你卻打電話回老家 這樣讓我們很難看
Back and forth this one and that one.
這樣來來回回
In the meantime, she's gone anyway. Am I right?
在這期間她也一樣會跑了 不是嗎?
What am I going to do with this woman?
我該拿這女人怎麼辦?
- Driving me fucking crazy.  - I think if you...
- 快把我搞瘋了  - 我覺得你...
assure her that she's gonna be all right she'll come back.
應該保證不會動她 她才會回來
Driving me fucking crazy.
簡直被她搞瘋了
Once you get her here, you think about it.
她回來後你再從長計議
Wait till you get the kid back. She wants to come back.
最起碼先把孩子弄回來 她也想回來
That's the main thing here.
這才是重點
You want your kid don't you?
你要孩子不是嗎?
Hello.
喂
Hi it's me. Just who you wanted to talk to right?
是我 你迫不及待想跟我講話吧?
Listen I'm not gonna ask you where you are.
聽著 我不會問你人在哪兒
Just please put Amy on a plane to get her here right away.
只是請你將艾美馬上 送上飛機回來
- That's all I'm asking.  - Do you....
- 我別無所求  - 你...
I mean, I don't think she should go by herself.
我是說 我不覺得她應該一個人回去
What do you mean?
你這是什麼意思?
What I mean is
我是說...
Do you think if I came back....
如果我回去...
Do you think you could forgive me?
你可以原諒我嗎?
I don't know. I gotta tell you, I don't know.
老實說 我不知道
I understand that.
我瞭解
I know I fucked up.
我知道我搞砸了
- What about the money? Where's the box?  - I gotta tell you...
- 那錢呢? 盒子呢?  - 老實說...
I made some mistakes and I spent some money.
我做錯事了 我花了一些錢
- What's it under?  - Pretty serious.
- 少很多嗎?  - 蠻多的
- How serious?  - It's under $25,000.
- 多少  - 兩萬五以下
- It's under $25,000?  - Yeah.
- 兩萬五以下?  - 對
- The $2 million is still there?  - Yeah I got the rest.
- 剩下的兩百萬還在嗎?  - 在 其他的都還在
Okay no big deal. That's okay.
好吧 沒關係
He got his $25,000.
他拿了兩萬五
That I'll live with. Any more I couldn't.
我可以接受 再多就不行了
Okay.
好
All right all right. Where are you? I'll send a plane for you right away.
好啦 你在哪裏? 我馬上派飛機去接你
Hi Sam.
嗨 山姆
So what'd you do with it?
你拿去幹嘛了?
With what?
什麼?
With the money.
錢啊
He needed some clothes.
他需要些衣服
$25,000 for clothes?
兩萬五買衣服?
He wanted a watch too.
他還要了只表
$25,000 for clothes and a watch?
兩萬五買衣服和表?
Good evening signora. This way.
晚安夫人 這邊請
The good part was I had Amy back.
好事是艾美回來了
So we went home, had the housekeeper stay over, put the kid to bed.
我們回家 請管家來過夜 然後送孩子上床
I calmed myself down and we went to dinner.
我逼自己冷靜 然後我們出門吃飯
I tried to keep things nice and civil...
我試著讓一切緩和...
but $25,000 for three suits?
但是兩萬五買三套西裝?
That doesn't make much sense.
這不太合理
First of all he's not gonna wear $1,000 suits.
第一點 他不可能穿一千元一套的西裝
Let's say he did which he won't.
就算假設他穿 雖然他不會
How you gonna get fitted for 25 suits in three days?
三天內怎麼可能量身訂做25套西裝?
I mean how could you get fitted that fast?
怎麼可能量得那麼快?
I can't get fitted that fast and I pay twice as much.
我付兩倍的錢都不可能那麼快
I bought him a watch too.
我還幫他買了只表
But even if you bought him a really nice watch one that he thought was nice...
就算是買了只好表 一隻他認為是好的表...
he doesn't know what the fuck a good watch is.
他根本不知道好表長什麼樣子
Say you go $5,000 to $12,000 at the most which is impossible for him.
假設表價在五千 最多一萬二 對他來說也不可能
Plus at the most three suits $1,000 apiece. That still leaves what?
加上三套一千一套的西裝 還剩多少?
- Around $10,000?  - Would you knock it off Sam?
- 差不多一萬左右  - 山姆 可以停止嗎?
- I'm just trying to figure it out.  - There's nothing to figure out.
- 我只是想算清楚  - 沒什麼好算的
I'm home. We're working it out.
我回家了 我們在協調
But I've been told before "We're working it out."
可是我以前也聽過 "我們在協調"
You think that you're home...
你以為你回家...
after what you just put me through with Amy is a favor to me?
在你對我與艾美所做的一切後 算是給我面子嗎?
Counting the watch let's say another $4,000 for expenses this weekend...
加上表 假設你們這個週末 花費了四千好了...
of which you must have had a good time.
我相信你們一定過得很愉快
I know he did. That's for sure.
至少我很確定他很愉快
I know that fucking piece of shit had a good fucking time.
我知道那狗雜種一定很快樂
On my money.
花我的錢
You might as well have fucked him which you probably did anyway.
你乾脆就跟他上床算了 你八成也這樣做了
You're looking at me a certain way.
你看我的表情很奇怪
You're teary-eyed.
你熱淚盈眶
You're upset. You're a good actress you know that?
你很難過 你真是個好演員
Good fucking actress.
真他媽的演得好
You can fucking get pity out of people.
你可讓任何人可憐你
I'm not a john. You understand?
但我不是嫖客 好嗎?
You always thought I was but I'm not. And I'm not a sucker.
你一直以為我是 但我不是 我也不是冤大頭
That fucking pimp cocksucker.
那可惡的拉皮條狗雜碎
He's lucky I didn't kill him last time.
上次沒殺了他是他命好
Lucky he's fucking living. If you would have stayed with Amy...
他活著是命好 若你們帶著艾美...
and you had run away he would have been dead.
然後走人的話 他就死定了
Both of you. Dead. Dead.
你們倆都死定了
No it isn't fair.
不 不公平
He doesn't come home at night. What is the big fucking deal?
他晚上根本不回家 有什麼了不起?
I go.... Listen I just can't fucking take it.
我走 聽著 我真的受不了
Why should I fucking take it? That wasn't the deal.
我為什麼要忍受? 這不是我們的協議
He acts like I'm the only one around here with a fucking past.
他一副好像就只有我有過去的樣子
He'll never let me live it down.
他永遠都不讓我忘記
Well yes I have tried. Of course I've tried.
是 我試過 我當然試過
What the fuck do you think I came back here for?
你以為我為什麼回來?
No, I'm not. I want to have him killed.
不 我不 我想殺了他
Yes, I want him killed. I've fucking had it.
對 我要殺了他 我受夠了
So are you with me on this?
你要幫我嗎?
You want to get rid of me? Here I am.
你想幹掉我? 我就在這兒
Go ahead. Get rid of me.
來啊 幹掉我啊
- Hello.  - Yes I do!
- 喂  - 是的
I fucking hate you! I can't take it anymore!
我恨死你了 我受不了了
Yes I want to kill you! I hate your fucking guts!
是 我要殺了你 我恨死你了
You hate my guts? I want you to come with me now! Come with me now.
你恨死我了? 我要你現在就給我過來 給我過來
I want you out of here!
我要你滾
Take your fucking bag and get out of here!
拿好行李給我滾
I'll go but I want my money right now!
我會走 但我現在就要我的錢
- You'll get your money! Don't worry.  - The arrangement is over.
- 你會拿到錢的 別擔心  - 協議結束了
- No kidding!  - And I still get my money.
- 廢話  - 我還是拿得到錢
I need some cash now! You can't just put me in the street!
我現在就要一些現金 你不能就這樣把我趕出街
You've never been straight with me ever since I met you!
你從一認識我就沒誠實過
You never even loved me in the first place!
你從一開始就沒愛過我
I need eyes in the back of my head with you you bitch!
跟你這婊子一起 我連腦後都得長眼睛
How could I love you? You treat me like I'm your fucking dog!
我怎麼愛你? 你對我像對條狗一樣
- You're lower than a dog!  - Fuck you!
- 你連狗都不如  - 去你的
Here! Is this enough money?
拿去 夠了沒?
Will it last you two fucking days? Take it!
可以活兩天嗎? 拿去
- Greedy bitch. Take the fucking money.  - I'm going to the bank...
- 貪得無厭的婊子 錢拿去  - 我要去銀行...
- and I'm getting my jewelry too!  - It opens at 9:00 a.m. Be there.
- 我還要去拿我的珠寶  - 早上9點開 去拿啊
Don't send your guys down there to stop me! I mean it!
別叫你的人去阻止我 我說真的
I guarantee you I will not stop you.
我向你保證我絕對不會阻止你
You're not getting rid of me with one fucking suitcase!
你別想以一口箱子就打發我
Come back tomorrow and get the rest. Just get out of here.
剩下的明天再回來拿吧 給我滾
- I'm taking Amy.  - You're not.
- 我要帶艾美走  - 不行
I am. I'm waking her up right now.
我要 我現在去叫她
You're stoned. You're a junkie. Get out of here.
你嗑藥了 你這個毒蟲 給我滾
I am not! She's my daughter too!
我不是 她也是我女兒
Send my lawyers a letter god-fucking-damn you!
寫信給我的律師吧 去你的
You're not getting away with this! You're not gonna cut me out of my end!
你跑不掉的 你別想不遵守你的諾言
Fucker!
王八蛋
The funny thing was, after all that, I didn't want her to go.
好笑的是 經過這麼多事 我還是不想讓她走
She was the mother of my kid. I loved her.
她是我孩子的媽 我愛她
And later, I realized I didn't want to give her the money, because if I did...
後來 我發現我並不想將錢給她 因為我若給了...
I knew I'd never see her again.
我知道將再也見不到她
Have a good day at school okay?
在學校要開開心心的喔
Okay angel.
好的 天使
From now on, I have to know where you and Amy are at all times.
從現在起 我隨時都得知道你與艾美在哪兒
Here's a beeper.
這是呼叫器
I want you to keep it on you.
我要你拿著
It's very light.
很輕
So I can call you whenever I have to.
讓我可以隨時打給你
Okay?
好嗎?
What are you supposed to do? What do you wanna do?
你能怎麼做? 你想怎麼做呢?
You want to stay the way you are? You can't do that.
你想就像現在這樣嗎? 你也不能啊
Two people don't get along at some point you gotta call it....
兩個人若合不來 總要有人出來說...
It's not my business but I think that's what you gotta do.
這不關我的事 但我覺得你應該這樣做
You're right. I know.
你說得對 我知道
- I was just  - What?
- 我只是...  - 什麼?
- Nothing.  - What were you gonna say?
- 沒什麼  - 你想說什麼?
- I don't  - Tell me what you were gonna say.
- 我不...  - 告訴我你本來想說什麼
Yeah?
真的?
I was thinking maybe you know somebody at the bank...
我在想說你有沒有認識銀行的人...
who could help me get my jewelry out?
可以幫我把珠寶拿出來?
There's a lot of money in there.
有很多錢在那兒
I'd be willing to take care of anybody who helped me out.
我願意重賞任何可以幫助我的人
Let me think about that.
我想想辦法
Let me see who I got. Gotta get somebody I can trust.
我看看能找誰 一定得是可以信得過的人
You know he's never gonna give me my jewelry.
你也知道他是不會把珠寶給我的
He holds that key so tight he's probably got it stuck up his ass.
他把那把鑰匙抓得很緊 我看就差沒藏到屁眼裏去了
You're right. That's Sammy.
說得好 真像是山姆
And he's probably got it there too.
搞不好真的就在那兒
He's so fucking lucky. I could have buried him.
他真是命大 我本可以埋了他
I could have gone to Europe and taken the baby.
我本可以去歐洲並把孩子帶走
Then he'd have tracked me down and he'd have killed me.
那他可能就會找到我 並把我殺了
No he wouldn't. I would have.
不 他不會 但我會
- He'd have been right too. Seriously.  - Come on.
- 不過他是沒錯  - 別鬧了
You don't take a guy's kid and then take off.
你不能就這樣把他的孩子帶走
I didn't. I did but then I did exactly what you told me to do and I came back.
我沒有 我本來有 但後來我照你所說的回家了
You did. You're right. I like that.
你是 你照做了 很好
- That's what I like you did the right thing.  - I did what you told me to.
- 我喜歡這樣 你做對了  - 我聽了你的話
- Yes you did.  - You always tell me the right thing to do.
- 是的  - 你總會告訴我正確的做法
He really fucked himself up out here didn't he?
他真的在這兒把自己搞砸了 不是嗎?
- He sure did.  - Everything went to his head.
- 是啊  - 這一切改變了他的想法
Changed.
改變了
- He did. He ain't the same person.  - No he's not.
- 他變了 他已不是同一個人了  - 不 他不是
- He really thinks who the fuck he is.  - Exactly.
- 他真的覺得自己多了不起  - 的確
He hates me.
他恨我
He hates my fucking guts.
他好恨我
Come on you're a toughie. You can take this.
別這樣 你最堅強了 這不算什麼
- Don't cry.  - I'm not as tough as you think I am.
- 別哭  - 我沒你想像的堅強
Yes you are.
你有
I'm not and he scares the shit out of me.
我沒有 我好怕他
- I never know what he's gonna do.  - Come on.
- 我永遠都不知道他下步要幹嘛  - 別這樣
- Don't be scared.  - I need some help.
- 別怕  - 我需要幫助
I need some help.
我需要幫助
You gotta help me.
你得幫我
I need a new sponsor Nicky.
我需要個新靠山
I do. I need a new sponsor.
真的 我需要個新的靠山
- Is that what you want?  - Yeah.
- 這是你想要的?  - 是啊
- A sponsor?  - Yeah.
- 靠山?  - 是的
Okay. Don't worry about it. Nobody will fuck with you anymore.
好 別擔心 沒人敢動你的
I'll take care of you.
我會照顧你的
- Thank you.  - It's what you want isn't it?
- 謝謝你  - 這是你想要的 不是嗎?
That's Ace's wife.
艾斯的老婆
This is great for the boss.
這給老闆看太好了
- Hi.  - Hi.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- You didn't answer your beeper.  - I threw it away.
- 你沒回呼叫器  - 我丟了
You threw it away?
你丟了
I tried to do it. I know that you want me to but....
我試著帶著 我知道你希望我帶著...
I'm driving down the freeway and the fucking thing beeps.
可是我開在高速公路上時 它也在響
I'm in a restaurant it's embarrassing.
在餐館也是 很丟臉
I don't want to do it anymore. Where's Amy?
我不要再帶了 艾美呢?
- I put her to bed.  - I got your cigarettes.
- 她睡了  - 我買了你要的煙
Oscar wants you to call him.
奧斯卡要你跟他連絡
- So who'd you go to lunch with?  - Jennifer.
- 你跟誰吃的午餐?  - 珍妮佛
- Where'd you go?  - To the Riviera.
- 去哪兒吃?  - 歐華賭場
What'd you have?
吃什麼?
- I had a salad.  - What did Jennifer have?
- 我叫沙拉  - 珍妮佛呢?
She had the same.
她也一樣
Okay.
好
I want you to call Jennifer...
我要你打給珍妮佛...
and I want you to tell her to tell you what you had for lunch.
我要你叫她告訴你 你午餐吃了什麼
I'm gonna listen in on the other line.
我從另一線聽
- Why do you want to do that?  - You know why I want to do it.
- 你幹嘛這樣?  - 你知道為什麼
- Just do it.  - Fine.
- 照做就是了  - 好啦
I just need to get the bowl for my thing.
我只是需要拿個碗裝這個
The line's busy.
忙線中
There's nobody there.
沒人在
- Hello?  - Hello Jennifer. It's Sam.
- 喂  - 喂 珍妮佛 是山姆
All right. I didn't have lunch with Jennifer.
好啦 我沒跟珍妮佛吃飯
Who were you with?
那你跟誰?
I was with somebody.
一個人
I know you were with somebody. Who was it?
我知道你有伴 是誰?
I just hope it's not someone who I think it might be.
我只希望不是我想的那個人
I just hope it's not that.
我只希望不是他
I knew she fucked around.
我知道她在外面亂來
Yeah she did what she did and I did what I had to do but...
她做她做的 我也做我要做的...
Jesus Nicky was the worst thing she could have done.
可是 天啊 尼奇是她所能做出最糟糕的事
What if he won't stop?
若他不願停呢?
It could get us both killed.
我們兩個可能都會沒命
I can back him off.
我可以讓他停
She was very convincing when she wanted to be.
她在必要時可以很有說服力
And this is how she backed him off.
她是這樣讓他停的
Hey Ginger.
嗨 金吉兒
Don't forget if you're challenged...
別忘了 要是他追問你
if he asks anything deny everything.
不管他問你什麼 你都不要承認
You understand? I don't want him bringing beefs back home.
懂不懂? 我不想他跟老家那頭抱怨
That could really cause a serious problem.
這樣麻煩就大了
Got to be careful. He's not dumb you know?
得小心點 他也不是蠢蛋 懂嗎?
You hear what I'm saying right?
你懂我的意思吧?
I know. You don't have to tell me that.
我知道 你不用告訴我
Do you think I'm stupid?
你當我白癡嗎?
Do I think you're stupid? No.
我當你白癡? 不
I think you're beautiful. But I gotta go.
我當你是美女 但我得走了
By this time Nicky had things so fucked up on the streets...
這時候 尼奇在外的事已經亂到...
that every time Marino went back home the packages got smaller and smaller.
每次瑪雷諾回老家時 皮箱都越來越小
It got to the point when he walked into the place...
後來甚至嚴重到 他每走入一個地方...
he didn't know whether he was going to be kissed or killed.
他都不確定會被親還是被殺
Frankie I want to ask you something.
法蘭克 我有事問你
It's private.
私人的事
But I want you to tell me the truth.
我要你說實話
Of course, Remo.
當然 利蒙
I want you to tell me the truth mind you.
我要你說真話
I always tell you the truth, Remo.
我對你一直都很誠實 利蒙
Frankie, the little guy,
法蘭克 小矮個...
he wouldn't be fucking the Jew's wife, would he?
他不是在搞猶太人的老婆吧?
Because if he is, it's a problem.
因為若他有 就是個問題
What could I say?
我能說什麼?
I knew if I gave the wrong answer...
我知道若我答錯了...
Nicky, Ginger, Ace, all of them could have wound up getting killed.
尼奇 金吉兒與艾斯全部都可能被幹掉
Because there's one thing about these old-timers.
因為這些老傢夥們有個禁忌
They don't like any fucking around with the other guys' wives.
就是他們不能忍受搞別人老婆
It's bad for business.
那很難看
So I lied, even though I knew that by lying to Gaggi...
所以我撒謊 雖然我知道對蓋吉撒謊...
I could wind up getting killed too.
可能會害我也被幹掉
- No I ain't seen anything like that.  - Are you sure?
- 不 我沒見到這種事  - 你確定?
I'm positive.
我很確定
Remo, things are very fucked up down there.
利蒙 那邊現在可是一團糟
I know. That's why I'm asking.
我知道 所以我才問你
You see my main concern is Nicky.
我最擔心的是尼奇
I want to know if he's doing all right if he's okay.
我想知道他最近如何 過得好不好
- He's good he's fine.  - I'm asking you to keep an eye on Nicky.
- 他很好  - 我要你看好尼奇
- Do it for me.  - No problem.
- 為了我  - 沒問題
You see I wouldn't want to be jeopardizing anything for our friends.
你知道 我不想得罪我們的朋友
You understand?
你懂嗎?
- I understand.  - Okay.
- 我懂了  - 好
Frankie, you're a good boy.
法蘭克 你是個好孩子
Thanks, Remo.
謝了 利蒙
By now, Nicky and his crew had already hit rock bottom.
這時 尼奇與他那幫人已經跌到穀底了
Vegas really got to him.
賭城真的改變了他
The booze, the coke, the broads.
酒精 可卡因 女人
I mean, he got sloppy.
我是說 他開始大意
He just wasn't the same Nicky anymore.
他再也不是以前那個尼奇了
- You must've drank too much.  - Fuck yourself.
- 你喝太多了  - 去你的
One night he had to belt a guy three times...
有晚他對個傢夥開了三槍...
before the guy finally went down.
才將他打死
In the old days Nicky would've decked him with one shot.
要是以前 尼奇只要一槍就夠了
You add this into the mix....
加上這些成份...
Maybe Vegas got to all of us.
可能賭城改變了我們全部
His crew followed him right over the edge.
他那幫人隨著他一起墮落
They were all tuned up half the time on coke.
他們每天一半的時間 都在吸毒中渡過
They started doing stupid things. The worst was Blue.
他們開始做些蠢事 尤其是布魯
- What do you guys want?  - Police! Stay in the car!
- 你們要幹嘛?  - 員警 別下車
He never knew when to keep his mouth shut.
他從不知道何時該閉嘴
- Drop the gun!  - Fuck you!
- 放下槍  - 去你的
The cops shot Blue...
條子朝布魯開槍...
because they thought his hero sandwich was a gun.
因為他們以為 他手上拿的潛艇堡是手槍
They could have been right but who knows?
他們也許是對的 但誰知道?
Jesus Christ! What gun? He's got a fucking hero sandwich here.
天啊 什麼槍? 他手上拿的是潛艇堡
- What do you want?  - It's pitch black.
- 不然能怎樣?  - 這兒這麼黑
- It's tinfoil. It looked like a gun!  - You moron!
- 是錫箔紙 看來像槍  - 你這智障
- I'll be doing paperwork for two months!  - What'll we do?
- 我得辦兩個月的公文  - 該怎麼辦?
- Sorry!  - You jerk-off!
- 抱歉  - 白癡
To make matters worse... to get even Nicky's crew got stoned one night...
更糟的是 為了報仇 尼奇那幫人有天晚上...
and started shooting up the cops' houses.
吸毒後跑去掃射員警的家
It got to the point where they couldn't talk in the Gold Rush anymore...
後來嚴重到連在掏金熱潮裏 都不方便講話...
because the Feds put a wire in the wall.
因為聯邦調查局在竊聽
Even when they talked outside they had to cover their mouths...
他們連在外面講話時都得摀住嘴
because the Feds brought in lip readers.
因為聯邦調查局請來了讀唇語的專家
Nicky found out about it from a teller who owed him money.
尼奇是從一個欠他錢的銀行職員那聽說的
He asked me again about you and the Jew's wife.
他又問我你跟猶太人老婆的事
Walk walk walk. What'd you say?
走 走 走 你說什麼?
He asked me again about you and the Jew's wife.
他又問我你跟猶太人老婆的事
What'd you tell him?
你怎麼說?
I told him I didn't know nothing.
我說我不知道
Jiggs and Tony Gorilla said if you did anything you're fucked up.
傑葛與東尼·國理拉說 你要是有做什麼就完了
You think he's going home making a beef behind my back?
你想他是不是背著我回老家 跟他們抱怨?
No you would have heard something.
不 若有的話 你應該早聽到風聲
- What's to stop him?  - I know.
- 有什麼阻止他這麼做?  - 是啊
I don't trust him anymore but they'd never okay anything.
我不相信他了 但老大們不會答應我幹掉他的
But they keep asking about it.
但他們一直在問
Sure they're asking. They earn with the prick.
當然會問 他們靠他賺錢
I got a funny feeling he's gonna start a war or something.
我有種感覺 他好像想引發戰爭
I'm not sure yet. But you know what I want you to do?
我還不確定 但你知道我要你幹嘛嗎?
Who's this guy?
這是誰?
That ain't nobody.
誰都不是
You know what I want you to do?
你知道我要你幹嘛嗎?
Get some guys to dig a hole in the desert and show you where it's at.
找個人在沙漠挖個洞 要他告訴你在哪兒
- Angelo and Buster.  - I'm not sure yet.
- 安基羅與本斯特  - 我還不確定
- They'll do it.  - When I'm ready I'll say the words:
- 他們肯幹的  - 我準備好時會跟你說...
"Go see the Jew." And you make it disappear. Know what I mean?
"去找猶太人" 然後你就讓他消失 懂不懂?
Let me know. But you gotta be ready.
讓我知道 但你得準備好
You know what I'm talking about?
你懂我的意思嗎?
Did I say to do anything yet?
我有叫你行動嗎?
I said I'm not sure. I'll let you know. I want to think about it.
我說了我不確定 我會讓你知道 我得再想想
Where are these pricks at? They're in the motel?
那些渾蛋呢? 在旅館裏嗎?
There or in the fucking bank. I don't know. All over the joint.
那裏或是銀行 我也不知道 到處都是
I'll be right back.
我馬上回來
Any calls for me give them to Mr. Sherbert.
有我的電話就轉給雪伯提先生
- Sure Mr. Rothstein.  - I'm going home for a few seconds.
- 好的 羅斯坦先生  - 我回家一會兒
He's on his way home.
他要回家了
Okay.
好的
Hello? Ginger?
喂? 金吉兒?
- Help Daddy!  - Amy!
- 爸爸 救命  - 艾美
- Amy open the door!  - I can't! I'm tied!
- 艾美 開門  - 我不能 我被綁起來了
- Dad!  - What happened?
- 爸爸  - 發生什麼事
- Who did this to you?  - Mommy.
- 是誰?  - 是媽媽
I'm gonna get a knife and cut you loose.
我去拿刀把繩子切斷
- No please!  - Okay I'm gonna be right back.
- 不要走  - 沒關係 我馬上回來
- When did this happen honey?  - I don't know.
- 什麼時候的事 甜心?  - 我不知道
What time did your mother do this? When did she leave?
你媽什麼時候做的? 她什麼時候走的?
I don't know.
我不知道
- Hello?  - Sammy.
- 喂?  - 山姆
- Yeah. Who's this?  - Me.
- 你是誰?  - 是我
- You okay?  - No I'm not okay.
- 你還好嗎?  - 我不好
- How'd you know I was here?  - I just wanted to talk to you.
- 你怎麼知道我在?  - 我只想跟你談談
Ginger's missing. She tied Amy up and locked her in her room.
金吉兒不見了 她將艾美綁在房間並上鎖
I don't know where she is.
我不知道她在哪兒
Well listen Ginger's here at the Leaning Tower with me.
聽著 金吉兒在比薩斜塔 跟我一起
She's there with you?
她在你那兒?
- Yeah she's here.  - I'll be right over.
- 是 在這兒  - 我馬上來
All right.
好的
- Coming over.  - Great.
- 過來了  - 非常好
Don't make a scene all right?
別鬧事 好嗎?
I want to talk to that Irish bitch.
我要跟那愛爾蘭婊子說話
She's trying to save your marriage.
她想要挽救你們的婚姻
Nicky I want to talk to that fucking bitch.
尼奇 我要見那婊子
Be fucking nice. Calm.
客氣點 冷靜
Be nice. Don't fuck up in here.
客氣點 別搞砸了
- Hi.  - Are you out of your mind?
- 嗨 山姆  - 你瘋了嗎?
You tie up our kid and lock the door? Are you out of your mind?
你把我們的孩子綁起來還鎖門? 你瘋了嗎?
That's our child. Are you out of your mind?
那是我們的孩子 你他媽的瘋了嗎?
It was just for a little while. The baby-sitter wasn't there.
只是一下下而已 保姆剛好不在
I ought to have you committed. You do that again and I'll
我真該送你去瘋人院 你下次再試試看...
I was just gonna be out for a little while.
我只是出去一會兒
- She was asleep. I was gonna be back...  - Listen.
- 她睡了 我一會就要回去的...  - 聽著
- ...before she even woke up.  - Listen you fucking cunt...
- 在她醒來前  - 聽著 你這賤貨...
let me tell you something.
讓我告訴你
Listen to me. Listen carefully.
聽我說 聽清楚
You ever touch her again or do anything like that again...
你別想再動她一根汗毛...
I'll fucking kill you pure and simple.
我會殺了你 就這麼簡單
You hear me? Pure and simple.
你聽到沒? 就這麼簡單
- Why don't you let me go?  - I'll kill you.
- 你為何不讓我走?  - 我會殺了你
- You fucking whore.  - I'll sign anything you want me to sign.
- 你這個婊子  - 你要我簽什麼都行
I just want the key to my jewelry and you to let me go.
我只要珠寶的鑰匙 還有讓我走
- Want your jewelry?  - Let me go.
- 你想要珠寶?  - 放我走
And let you disgrace me, you fucking pig?
然後讓你丟我的臉 你這隻豬?
Get up and be a mother.
你給我起來當個母親
Get in the car and go home right now.
立刻上車回家
Get up and get in the...
起來...
Get up. Get up!
起來
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
我要是你就不會這樣
Get up. Get up.
起來
Get going. Get up! Get the...
Are you threatening me?
你在威脅我嗎?
I'll fucking kill you in this place.
我現在就可宰了你
Get up and go home.
起來回家
I'm going! You...
我要走了
You need approval from him to go home?
你現在要他批准才能回家?
So what?
那又怎樣?
Who fucking blew you in the parking lot before you came in?
你從停車場進來前 又是誰在幫你吹喇叭?
You make me sick, you fucking...
你讓我作嘔
Once a hooker, always a hooker.
一日為娼 終生為娼
Oh, fuck you!
去你的
Fuck you, Sam Rothstein! Fuck you!
去你的 山姆·羅斯坦
# I can't get me no #
# Satisfaction #
# I can't get no #
Yeah, Billy Sherbert, please. Put him on.
找比利·雪伯提
Who's this?
誰啊?
Billy, I'll explain later.
聽好 我待會再解釋
You got a gun at home?
你家裏有槍嗎?
Bring it over right away.
馬上帶過來
- Take it easy. I'll do it.  - Okay.
- 冷靜點 我帶  - 好
Leave it where it is!
就留著吧
Where is he? I want that Jew bastard killed!
他在哪兒? 我要殺了那猶太王八蛋
Hide her car in the back.
把她的車藏到後面去
There's no reason to hide my car! He already knows!
不需要藏我的車 他早就知道了
Supposing he goes back home and makes a fucking beef?
他要是回去告狀怎麼辦?
- I gotta know exactly what you said. Tell me.  - Me? Nothing. I said....
- 我得知道你到底跟他說了什麼  - 我? 我說...
I said no. Everything he said I just kept saying no.
我說沒有 不管他說什麼 我都說沒有
I told you this was fucking dangerous.
我早跟你說這很危險
I said, "Ginger, this is a dangerous situation. Be very careful."
我說 "金吉兒 狀況很危險 你一定要小心"
If it's so dangerous, why don't you kill him?
若真這麼危險 你為何不殺了他?
I'm not gonna kill him. Shut the fuck up.
我不會殺他 閉上你的嘴
Have him killed, and get it over with!
殺了他 做個了斷
Don't be such a smart ass!
別自做聰明
I know the guy 35 years, I'm gonna fucking whack him for you?
我跟他35年的交情 我會為了你幹他?
Motherfucker.
王八蛋
I knew this. I knew it.
我就知道
What about my money?
那我的錢呢?
How the fuck am I gonna get your money now?
我現在怎麼幫你拿錢?
You think he's gonna give you fucking money? Are you out of your mind?
你還以為他會給你錢嗎? 你瘋了嗎?
- Look what you did to this guy.  - What?
- 看看你怎麼對他的  - 什麼?
If you would have just kept your fucking mouth shut.
你只要閉上你的嘴
What the fuck is the use!
現在有個屁用
I should've never got involved. Hey.
我真不該淌混水的...
You motherfucker, you!
喂 你這渾蛋
You fuck! You fucker!
你渾蛋
Get the fuck out of here.
給我滾
Get out! Get the fuck out!
給我滾出去
Oh, calm down. Take it easy!
下去 冷靜點
Get up! I should never have gotten involved!
我根本不該管這瘋子的
You'll fucking kill her. Take it easy.
你會殺了她 冷靜點
Get her out of here.
把她弄出去
Let's go. That's right.
走吧
Get the fuck out of here.
給我滾
I don't need you!
我不需要你
I'll get my own fucking money!
我自己會拿到我的錢
All right, all right.
好好好
I'm going to the FBI!
我要去找聯邦調查局
I'm not scared anymore!
我不怕你了
Be careful.
自己小心
You've fucked with me for the last time!
這是你最後一次玩我
Okay, yeah.
好 好
Be careful. Okay. Come on. Get inside.
小心啊 走吧 進去
Can you believe that?
你瞧瞧
Look at this motherfucker.
他媽的
I fucked up, Frankie.
我錯了 法蘭克
I fucked up good this time.
我這次真的搞砸了
I should never have started with this fucking broad.
我真不該跟那蕩婦搞的
Take it easy. What could you do?
冷靜點 你能怎樣呢?
I mean, she threw herself at you, right?
是她自己送上門的 不是嗎?
I'm in a bad fucking spot here.
我現在身處困境了
You know that? Huh?
你知道嗎?
Bad fucking spot.
裏外不是人
I'd left the kid with neighbors
我將孩子給鄰居託管
and I had $1 million in cash and jewels
將近一百萬的現金與珠寶...
that I gave to Sherbert to lock up.
我交給雪伯提鎖在賭場
Put it in the hotel safe, then I want you to come right back.
把這放進旅館的保險櫃 然後馬上回來
She's alone.
她一個人...
Take the gun and go into Amy's.
拿著槍到艾美房間去
Wait there for me.
在那兒等我
Get down here and talk to me, God damn it!
下樓見我
Don't fucking ignore me, you motherfucker!
你不能不理我 渾蛋
I mean it!
我說真的
You come down here right now!
馬上給我下來
Get down here and talk to me, God damn it!
下來見我 媽的
Fuck you! God damn you, come out here!
去你的 你給我下來
I'm gonna drive your fucking car through the living room!
我要將車開進客廳
You fucking coward!
你這個懦夫
You motherfucker, you!
渾蛋
Come out here and talk to me, you fucker!
出來見我
Will you stop it?
你夠了沒?
You're drunk. You're on drugs.
你喝醉又嗑藥
I am not!
我沒有
- You're gonna be sorry if you don't stop it.  - Don't you threaten me!
- 你再不停就要後悔了  - 別威脅我
You are not threatening me anymore!
你無法再威脅我了
You fuck! You fuck! I'm sick of you!
王八蛋 我受夠你了
I am fucking Nicky Santoro! I am!
我與尼克·山多羅上床
He's my new sponsor!
他是我的新靠山
How about that, you fuckhead!
怎麼樣 王八蛋
What are you looking at? Fuck off!
你在看什麼? 滾開
Go inside!
快進去
This is none of your business!
關你們屁事
I don't have to take your shit anymore!
我再也不要每天看你臉色了
I'll go to the FBI! I will go to the police!
我要去找聯邦調查局 我要去找員警
I am not protecting you anymore!
我不會再保護你了
Mrs. Rothstein. Okay.
羅斯坦夫人...
He won't let me inside!
他不讓我進去
Mr. Rothstein, I'm sorry.
羅斯坦先生
We've been getting some complaints about the noise.
我們接到很多關於噪音的抱怨
I'm trying to get in my house.
我試著回我家
He won't let me in.
但他不讓我進門
I'm sorry, Randy, I'm not gonna let her in.
我不讓她進去 抱歉 藍帝
- I'm not gonna let her in the way she's behaving.  - Won't let me in?
- 她那樣子 我不能讓她進門  - 不讓我?
Who knows what you'll do in there.
誰知道你進去會幹嘛
I've been in the same clothes for two days!
我已經兩天沒換衣服了
- I want to get my things! Big deal!  - Okay.
- 我要收拾東西 什麼大不了的  - 好
Let her in to get a few things. That way she'll leave.
讓她進去拿點東西 她就會走了
- This is half her house.  - I'm afraid.
- 這房子一半是她的  - 我不敢
- You aren't afraid!  - She'll destroy stuff.
- 你才不怕  - 她會亂砸東西
- Let me in the house!  - Hey!
- 讓我進去  - 喂
- Fucker!  - Hold on! Please!
- 渾蛋  - 請等一下
You should be afraid the way you treat me!
你這樣對我 你是該害怕
It'll make it easier on everybody.
讓大家都好過點
Let her get her things, we'll be out of your hair.
若讓她進去拿東西 我們大家就不打擾你了
If she calms down, I will let her in.
她要冷靜下來 我就讓她進來
I am calm!
我很冷靜
If she calms down,
若她冷靜下來...
I will let her in for five minutes
我讓她進來五分鐘...
if you gentlemen will escort her out
如果你們願意在她不願走時
if she happens to not want to leave.
護送她出去
- Can I go in?  - That's not a problem.
- 可以進去了嗎?  - 這不是問題
Jeff, would you go in with her?
傑夫 你跟她去?
Yes. Fine! Fuck you!
好 好 去你的
You won't believe how mean he is.
你無法相信他多壞
He's locked up my important stuff.
他把我的證件都鎖起來
All my papers. I have to get them.
我要拿它們
Don't let him come up.
別讓他上來這兒...
I know they're in the desk. Fuck.
因為它們在這書桌裏
Just pay attention.
注意點
He could come up here at any time.
他隨時都會上樓
Are you watching for him?
你有看著他嗎?
Got them.
找到了
I don't want her in there more than a few more minutes.
我不要她在裏頭超過五分鐘
It'll just be a couple minutes. We got other things to do too.
很快就好了 我們也有別的事要做
I'll hurry her up.
我們會叫她快點的
How's everything else besides this?
其他都還好吧?
Fine.
很好
How's your family?
你那邊呢?
Not bad. In fact, my wife's pregnant again.
不錯啊 我老婆又懷孕了
Oh, good. Congratulations.
恭喜你
Thanks. Yeah.
謝了
We're kind of happy about that.
我們很開心
I just have to get this one more thing and then we can go.
我得再拿一樣東西 然後我們就可以走了
Shit! Fuck!
媽的
Shit! God!
Oh, that pisses me off! Don't worry about it.
氣死我了 別管它
It would be great if you guys follow me out of here,
若能... 跟我一起出去最好...
because he's been threatening me.
因為他在威脅我
Take care. Thank you.
保重 謝謝
I just need to pick up a little cash.
我只是需要領一些現金
Could you come with me?
你可以陪我來嗎?
You've got to stop her.
你得阻止她
I'm sorry, Sam. What can I do?
抱歉 山姆 我無能為力
She's a fucking junkie.
她是個毒蟲
She's out of her fucking mind!
根本就瘋了
She has the keys.
她有鑰匙
It's still in both your names.
而且你們兩人名字都在戶頭上
I'm sorry, there's nothing I can do. I'd like to help.
我無能為力 我想要幫忙...
- but I can't.  - LegaHy, she can't take that stuff.
- 但我不能  - 嚴格說 她不能拿
- She can't. Half of it is mine.  - Listen to me.
- 她不能 一半是我的  - 聽我說
There's nothing I can do.
我愛莫能助
I'm coming down.
我馬上到
Shit. God damn it.
媽的 靠
I'm gonna need a bag.
我需要個袋子
If you could just ask the guy for the big bag.
你可以幫我要個袋子嗎?
Go get a bag, man.
拿個袋吧
Here, here.
拿去
Lady, I can't take it.
小姐 我不能拿
No, you can. You've been so nice to me.
你可以 你對我好好
Just hold the top open, all right?
好 幫我打開 好嗎?
And I can...
這樣我就可以...
Oh, God, it's him. You have to stop him.
天啊 是他 你們得阻止他
He said he was gonna kill me.
因為他說他會殺了我
You should just stop him.
你們得阻止他
Mr. Rothstein, wait a minute.
羅斯坦先生 等一下
Hold on a second. Hold on a second.
請等一下
She's driving away.
她開走了
There's nothing we can do.
我們不能做什麼
Look, look.
你瞧瞧
You can't stop her for speeding?
你們不能抓她超速嗎?
Look what she's doing.
看看她開多快
Nothing we can do. She had the key.
我們不能做什麼 她有鑰匙
She's on the account.
她的名字在戶頭上
Let's pull her over at that Citgo station.
我們在加油站攔她
Okay. Let's do it.
好的 就這麼辦
We're placing you under arrest for...
我們必須逮捕你
For what?
為了什麼?
- For aiding and abetting  - For what?
- 為了協助犯罪...  - 為了什麼?
- For aiding and abetting  - I'm just trying to leave.
- 為了協助犯罪...  - 我只是要離開
After all the threats and the bullshit,
在這麼多威脅之後...
Ginger didn't tell them anything.
金吉兒什麼都沒告訴他們
By then the Feds didn't need her anyway.
但那時 他們也不需要她了
They had all they needed.
他們已有足夠的證據
I didn't do anything.
但我什麼都沒做
Everybody began to tumble...
大家就像牌九一樣跟著倒
FBI! We have a warrant!
聯邦調查局 我們有拘捕令
...one after the other, like dominoes.
一單接著一單 像多米諾骨牌一樣
Between Piscano complaining on the wire,
不管是竊聽器上派斯康的抱怨...
Nicky, Ginger, me and my license,
還是尼奇 我與我的執照...
paradise, we managed to really fuck it all up.
天堂就這樣被我們搞砸了
Mom.
媽
Yeah, someone's at the fucking door.
門口他媽的有人
FBI. We have a search warrant.
聯邦調查局 我們有搜查令
I got wind of the pinches coming down, so I took off.
我馬上知道苗頭不對 所以我跑路了
Who needs to hang around for that bullshit?
誰要待在那兒找麻煩啊?
- I'm Mark Casper FBI.  - Yeah?
- 我是馬克·凱斯伯 FBI  - 是嗎?
Can I make a fucking phone call?
我可以打個電話嗎?
Hold on. Make a phone call but don't talk to us like that.
可以 但你不用這樣對我們講話
Everybody, out of the room.
大家都出去
Over to the alarm.
往警鈴的方向走
But they got almost everybody else.
其他人似乎都被抓了
This area is seized!
這地方被查封了
Get the master account list.
去拿總戶頭單
I want all papers seized, regardless of what they are.
我要查封所有的檔
Put every box on the table.
將每個箱子都放到桌上
Oh, yes. Here we are. Little craps figures.
好 在這兒 所有的數字
Green? Don't even ask.
葛林? 別提了
...$30,000 of yours.
你的三萬元
No. That's why it wasn't valid.
不 所以不成立
I was being extorted.
我是被敲詐的
I'll tell you what you want to know.
你們想知道什麼就問我
I've got nothing to hide.
我不需要隱藏
Now for the best. I couldn't believe this shit...
最經典的是 我不敢相信...
Piscano's expense reports took the cake.
派斯康的花費記錄 竟然成了關鍵
This is good. Bingo.
這太好了
He might as well have given them a blueprint.
他乾脆就把藍圖給他們算了
Names, addresses, dates, everything.
所有人的名字 地址 日期 一切都在上面
Look at this.
看看這
Thank you so much, Mr. Piscano.
真是多謝你了 派斯康先生
How considerate of you.
你真是體帖
Those are my mother's books.
那是我媽的賬目
You're under arrest.
你被逮捕了
Fucking balloon-head.
真是個蠢才
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛?
Wait! Wait a minute! He's sick!
等一下 等一下 他有病
Move back.
走開
- God! It's his heart! Is he breathing?  - CPR now!
- 是心臟 還呼吸嗎?  - 快人工呼吸
Artie got so upset, he had a heart attack
艾提被搞到心臟病發...
and dropped dead in front of his wife.
當他老婆的面就掛了
- Calm down!  - Artie! No, I won't calm down!
- 冷靜點  - 我無法冷靜
- He's my husband!  - We can't help...
- 他是我丈夫 艾提  - 我們也不能...
And at the end of the day, they came to see me with the pictures.
最後... 他們終於拿照片來給我看
Why protect a friend who betrayed you?
為什麼要保護一個背叛你的朋友?
But I didn't want to look at them.
但我並不想看它們...
I didn't want to look at the guys who brought them either.
或是拿照片來的人
Your honor, as you can see, my clients are elderly and infirm.
大人 你可看見 我的客戶們都年事已大並生病
Any incarceration could pose a serious health risk.
任何的刑責都將會嚴重威脅到他們的健康
Some of the bosses were so old,
當老大們被逮時 有些簡直老到...
they needed doctors at their arraignment.
罪狀認否程式時都需要醫師
Pre-trial services recommends bail as set.
預審時建議將保釋金額 維持現額
We're going to take a recess.
現在休庭
When it looked like they could get 25 years to life for skimming a casino,
當情況看來他們似乎... 得為了抽頭而關上25年時...
sick or no fucking sick, people were going to get clipped.
不管有病沒病 總有人要倒楣
The day of the arraignment, they had this meeting in the back of the courthouse.
所以在罪狀認否程式那天 他們在法庭後頭開會
See, when something like this happens,
當類似的事發生時
you know how things are gonna work out.
你已知道事情會怎樣
It's always better with no witnesses.
最好是不要有目擊者
So what about Andy?
那安迪呢?
He won't talk. Stone is a good kid.
他不會說的 史東是好傢夥
Stand-up guy just like his old man.
跟他老爸一樣帶種
That's the way I see it.
我是這麼想的
I agree. He's solid. He's a fucking Marine.
我同意 他很強悍
He's okay. He always was.
他沒問題 一直都是
Remo, what do you think?
你說呢?
Look, why take a chance?
為什麼要冒險呢?
At least, that's the way I feel about it.
我是這麼想的啦
Call Artie. Tell him, I don't care what.
打給艾提 告訴他不管怎樣...
He's got to be in my office Thursday morning before 11:00.
他星期四都得來我辦公室
It's important.
非常重要
I gotta have a conversation with that guy...
我一定得跟他談談
As much as they liked him, he wasn't one of us.
不管他們多喜歡他 他還不是家族一員
He wasn't Italian.
他不是義大利人
As far as they knew, he could have talked.
對他們來說 他隨時可能供出來
Otherwise, Stoney might still be alive.
要不然他可能還活著
哥斯達黎加
The first one to skip was John Nance.
第一個翹頭的就是約翰·南斯
He found a nice, warm, secluded place in Costa Rica.
他在哥斯達黎加 找了個又好又隱密的地方
He thought nobody would find him there.
他以為沒人找得到他
But then his kid got nabbed by the Feds for drugs.
但他孩子隨後因犯毒 被聯邦調查局逮了
Naturally, the bosses were afraid he'd come out of hiding
老大們當然怕他會出現...
just to save his kid and give them all up.
為了救孩子而把大家供出來
So...
所以...
Where you going, jag-off?
你想去哪裏?
But, anyway, they all had to follow.
但大家都得跟著
Everybody went down.
大家都完了
Fuck you.
去你的
Before you knew it, anybody who knew anything
不知不覺... 任何知道一點小事的人
wound up getting whacked.
都被幹掉了
Oh, no! No. No.
不 不
After Ginger took off, she wasn't much help to anybody.
金吉兒走後 她對任何人都沒什麼用
She found some pimps, lowlifes, druggies and bikers in L.A.
她在洛杉磯結識了一些 皮條客 敗類 毒蟲與飛車黨
In a few months, they went through all the money and all the jewels.
幾個月內 他們就把所有的錢跟珠寶花光了
# To wear that ball and chain #
# Well, there is a house in New Orleans #
After they found her body, I had a private doctor do another autopsy.
當他們找到遺體時... 我私下請了個醫生驗屍
He said they gave her a hot dose.
他說他們給她打了過量的毒品
In the end, all she had left was $3,600 in mint condition coins.
最終 她身上只剩下價值三千六百元的全新硬幣
No matter what the Feds or the papers
不管條子與文件
might have said about my car bombing,
對我的汽車炸彈有什麼評論...
it was amateur night, you could tell.
一看就知道是新手幹的
Whoever it was, they put the dynamite under the passenger side.
不管是誰 他們將炸彈裝在副駕駛座下麵
But what they didn't know, what nobody outside the factory knew,
他們不知道的是 除了車廠外沒人知道的是...
was that that model car was made
那台車的駕駛座下
with a metal plate under the driver's seat.
多加了一塊鐵板
It's the only thing that saved my life.
全靠了它救我一命
The bombing was never authorized
那炸彈從沒被批准
but I suspect I know who lit the fuse.
但我想我知道是誰幹的
Hey, Nicky.
嗨 尼奇
And so did the powers that be.
老大們也知道吧
- Hi.  - How you doing?
- 你好嗎?  - 你好嗎?
It took months for everything to calm down.
好幾個月後一切才平息
But, finally, my guys got out on bail,
但我的人終於保釋出來了
and the bosses wanted me to send
老大們要我將我小弟
my brother Dominick out to Vegas.
多明尼送回賭城
Always the dollars.
永遠都是為了錢
Always the fucking dollars.
I mean, it was still way too hot for me to even go near Vegas.
我是說 我連賭城都不能踏入
So I set up a meeting with the guys way out in the sticks.
所以我在個鳥不生蛋的地方 安排大家碰面
I didn't want my brother fucked around.
我不想害我小弟
What's right is right.
對的就是對的
They don't give a fuck about...
他們才不在乎...
Holy fucking...
去你媽的...
What the fuck...
搞什麼...
Come on, motherfucker!
來啊 王八蛋
Tough guy! You and your fucking brother!
不是很猛嗎? 你跟你哥
You fucking scumbag! No more!
你們兩個渾蛋 夠了
Frankie!
法蘭克
No more! You see? Watch!
夠了 你看著
Frankie! You piece of shit!
法蘭克 你這王八蛋
Fuck you, you motherfucker!
去你的
Fucking punk, motherfucker!
王八羔子
Piece of shit!
狗雜種
No!No!No!No!
不
Take this motherfucker out!
把這渾蛋拖走
Oh, Dominick.
多明尼
Frankie, leave the kid alone.
別搞他了 他還活著
He's still breathing. Leave him alone.
他還在呼吸 別搞他了
Frankie.
法蘭克
All right. Strip him.
好了 脫他衣服
No balls. You got no fucking balls.
沒種 你真他媽的沒種
Oh, Dominick.
多明尼
Dominick.
Come on, come on.
來吧
Bury them?
埋了他們?
Bury them.
埋
The word was out.
話放出去了
The bosses had enough of Nicky.
老大們受夠了尼奇
They had enough.
受夠了
How much were they gonna take?
他們還能忍受多久呢?
So they made an example of him and his brother.
所以拿他們兄弟倆殺雞儆猴
They buried them while they were still breathing.
他們倆被活埋
Mister, you all right? Watch out!
你還好嗎? 小心
Mister, you all right?
先生 你沒事吧?
Yeah.
沒事
They had other ideas for me.
他們有別的事給我做
We need some help over here!
我們這兒需要幫忙
You sure are lucky, mister.
你真是幸運
The town will never be the same.
這城市再也不一樣了
After the Tangiers, the big corporations took it all over.
在坦吉樂之後 大集團全權掌管
Today it looks like Disneyland.
今日的賭城像是迪士尼樂園
While the kids play cardboard pirates,
孩子們玩著海盜遊戲時...
Mommy and Daddy drop house payments and junior's college money
爸爸與媽媽將房貸與大學學費...
on the poker slots.
浪費在吃角子老虎機
In the old days, dealers knew your name,
想當年 莊家知道你的名字
what you drank, what you played.
喝什麼酒 玩什麼牌
Today, it's like checking into an airport.
今天就像是在機場登記一般
If you order room service, you're lucky if you get it by Thursday.
你要是叫客房送餐 星期四給你送到就了不起了
Today it's all gone. A whale shows up with $4 million in a suitcase
都沒了 一個人拎著 裝著四百萬的皮箱...
and some 25-year-old hotel school kid
就有個25歲的旅遊系大學畢業生
is gonna want his Social Security number.
想要他的身份字號
After the Teamsters got knocked out of the box,
全美卡車司機工會離開後...
the corporations tore down practically all the old casinos.
大集團幾乎將所有的舊賭場都拆了
And where did the money come from to rebuild the pyramids?
而蓋新金字塔的錢是從哪來的呢?
Junk bonds.
垃圾債券
聖地亞哥
Still not sure?
還不確定?
Probable. Maybe questionable.
有可能 有些質疑
All right, Let me know as soon as you can find out.
好吧 知道後立即通知我
But in the end, I wound up right back where I started.
最後 我又回到了起點
I could still pick winners
我還是會選贏家...
and I could still make money for all kinds of people back home.
也還是可以為老家各式各樣的人賺錢
And why mess up a good thing?
何必搞砸好事呢?
And that's that.
就是這樣
# Sometimes I wonder why I spend the lonely nights #
# Dreaming of a song #
# The melody haunts my reverie #
# And I am once again with you #
# When our love was new #
# And each kiss an inspiration #
# Ah, but that was long ago #
# And now my consolation #
# ls in the stardust of a song #
# Beside a garden wall #
# When stars were bright #
# And you were in my arms #
# The nightingale told his fairy tale #
# Of paradise where roses grew #
# Though I dream in vain #
# In my heart it will remain #
# My stardust melody #
# The memory of love's refrain #